<document name='fairytales-corpus-data/OrangeFairyBook.txt'>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='0'></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='1'>The Orange <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='orange;book' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='6.85666666667' arousal='4.07' dominance='6.12333333333'>Fairy</entity> Book</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='2'>Edited by <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='' verbs='edit' valence='4.95' arousal='4.1' dominance='6.64'>Andrew Lang</entity></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='3'>Preface</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='4'></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='5'>The children who read fairy books, or have fairy books read to them, do not read prefaces, and the parents, aunts, uncles, and cousins, who give fairy books to their daughters, nieces, and cousines, leave prefaces unread.  For whom, then, are prefaces written?  When an author publishes a book "out of his own head," he writes the preface for his own pleasure.  After reading over his book in print--to make sure that all the "u"s" are not printed as "n"s," and all the "n"s" as "u"s" in the proper names--then the author says, mildly, in his preface, what he thinks about his own book, and what he means it to prove--if he means it to prove anything--and why it is not a better book than it is.  But, perhaps, nobody reads prefaces except other authors; and critics, who hope that they will find enough in the preface to enable them to do without reading any of the book.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='6'>This appears to be the philosophy of prefaces in general, and perhaps authors might be more daring and candid than they are with advantage, and write regular criticisms of their own books in their prefaces, for nobody can be so good a critic of himself as the author--if he has a sense of humour.  If he has not, the less he says in his preface the better.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='7'>These Fairy Books, however, are not written by the Editor, as he has often explained, "out of his own head."  The stories are taken from those told by grannies to grandchildren in many countries and in many languages-- French, Italian, Spanish, Catalan, Gaelic, Icelandic, Cherokee, African, Indian, Australian, Slavonic, Eskimo, and what not. The stories are not literal, or word by word translations, but have been altered in many ways to make them suitable for children.  Much has been left out in places, and the narrative has been broken up into conversations, the characters telling each other how matters stand, and speaking for themselves, as children, and some older people, prefer them to do.  In many tales, fairly cruel and savage deeds are done, and these have been softened down as much as possible; though it is impossible, even if it were desirable, to conceal the circumstance that popular stories were never intended to be tracts and nothing else. Though they usually take the side of courage and kindness, and the virtues in general, the old story-tellers admire successful cunning as much as Homer does in the Odyssey.  At least, if the cunning hero, human or animal, is the weaker, like Odysseus, Brer Rabbit, and many others, the story-teller sees little in intellect but superior cunning, by which tiny Jack gets the better of the giants.  In the fairy tales of no country are "improper" incidents common, which is to the credit of human nature, as they were obviously composed mainly for children. It is not difficult to get rid of this element when it does occur in popular tales.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='8'>The old puzzle remains a puzzle--why do the stories of the remotest people so closely resemble each other?  Of course, in the immeasurable past, they have been carried about by conquering races, and learned by conquering races from vanquished peoples.  Slaves carried far from home brought their stories with them into captivity.  Wanderers, travellers, shipwrecked men, merchants, and wives stolen from alien tribes have diffused the stories; gipsies and Jews have passed them about; Roman soldiers of many different races, moved here and there about the Empire, have trafficked in them.  From the remotest days men have been wanderers, and wherever they went their stories accompanied them.  The slave trade might take a Greek to Persia, a Persian to Greece; an Egyptian woman to Phoenicia; a Babylonian to Egypt; a Scandinavian child might be carried with the amber from the Baltic to the Adriatic; or a Sidonian to Ophir, wherever Ophir may have been; while the Portuguese may have borne their tales to South Africa, or to Asia, and thence brought back other tales to Egypt.  The stories wandered wherever the Buddhist missionaries went, and the earliest French voyageurs told them to the Red Indians.  These facts help to account for the sameness of the stories everywhere;  and the uniformity of human fancy in early societies must be the cause of many other resemblances.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='4' num='9'>In this volume there are stories from the natives of Rhodesia, collected by Mr. Fairbridge, who speaks the native language, and one is brought by Mr. Cripps from another part of Africa, Uganda.  Three tales from the Punjaub were collected and translated by Major Campbell. Various savage tales, which needed a good deal of editing, are derived from the learned pages of the "Journal of the Anthropological Institute."  With these exceptions, and "The Magic Book," translated by Mrs. <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='exception;eventyr;fra;mrs.;tale;source;mr.;stories;jylland;narrative' adjectives='desirable;various' verbs='be;do;modify;have;seem;translate' valence='5.865' arousal='3.89875' dominance='5.61875'>Pedersen</entity>, from "Eventyr fra Jylland," by Mr. <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='exception;eventyr;fra;mrs.;tale;source;mr.;stories;jylland;narrative' adjectives='desirable;various' verbs='be;do;modify;have;seem;translate' valence='5.865' arousal='3.89875' dominance='5.61875'>Ewald Tang Kristensen</entity> (Stories from <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='exception;eventyr;fra;mrs.;tale;source;mr.;stories;jylland;narrative' adjectives='desirable;various' verbs='be;do;modify;have;seem;translate' valence='5.865' arousal='3.89875' dominance='5.61875'>Jutland</entity>), all the tales have been done, from various sources, by <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='exception;eventyr;fra;mrs.;tale;source;mr.;stories;jylland;narrative' adjectives='desirable;various' verbs='be;do;modify;have;seem;translate' valence='5.865' arousal='3.89875' dominance='5.61875'>Mrs. Lang</entity>, who has modified, where it seemed desirable, all the narratives.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='10'></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='11'></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='12'>CONTENTS</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='13'></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='7' num='14'>The Story of the Hero Makoma The Magic Mirror Story of <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='magic;mink;owl;fish;wreath;thief;son;slipper;enchanted;lion;doe;mirror;girl;jachal;jackal;blue;rover;story;casket;makoma;soldier;treasure;fox;frog;book;goldsmith;bird;eagle;clever;hero;truth;covan;eldest;white;adventure;rabbit;falcon;weaver;younger;fortune;plain;stalos;duckling;adventures;cat;ugly;s;wolf;bella-flor;the;foolish' adjectives='jackal' verbs='trick;be;see;get' valence='6.13954545455' arousal='4.61590909091' dominance='5.43621212121'>the King</entity> who would see Paradise How Isuro the Rabbit tricked <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='magic;mink;owl;fish;wreath;thief;son;slipper;enchanted;lion;doe;mirror;girl;jachal;jackal;blue;rover;story;casket;makoma;soldier;treasure;fox;frog;book;goldsmith;bird;eagle;clever;hero;truth;covan;eldest;white;adventure;rabbit;falcon;weaver;younger;fortune;plain;stalos;duckling;adventures;cat;ugly;s;wolf;bella-flor;the;foolish' adjectives='jackal' verbs='trick;be;see;get' valence='6.13954545455' arousal='4.61590909091' dominance='5.43621212121'>Gudu Ian</entity>, the Soldier"s Son The Fox and the Wolf How <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='magic;mink;owl;fish;wreath;thief;son;slipper;enchanted;lion;doe;mirror;girl;jachal;jackal;blue;rover;story;casket;makoma;soldier;treasure;fox;frog;book;goldsmith;bird;eagle;clever;hero;truth;covan;eldest;white;adventure;rabbit;falcon;weaver;younger;fortune;plain;stalos;duckling;adventures;cat;ugly;s;wolf;bella-flor;the;foolish' adjectives='jackal' verbs='trick;be;see;get' valence='6.13954545455' arousal='4.61590909091' dominance='5.43621212121'>Ian Direach</entity> got the Blue Falcon The Ugly Duckling The Two Caskets The Goldsmith"s Fortune The Enchanted Wreath The Foolish Weaver The Clever Cat The Story of <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='magic;mink;owl;fish;wreath;thief;son;slipper;enchanted;lion;doe;mirror;girl;jachal;jackal;blue;rover;story;casket;makoma;soldier;treasure;fox;frog;book;goldsmith;bird;eagle;clever;hero;truth;covan;eldest;white;adventure;rabbit;falcon;weaver;younger;fortune;plain;stalos;duckling;adventures;cat;ugly;s;wolf;bella-flor;the;foolish' adjectives='jackal' verbs='trick;be;see;get' valence='6.13954545455' arousal='4.61590909091' dominance='5.43621212121'>Manus Pinkel</entity> the Thief The Adventures of a Jackal The Adventures of the Jachal"s Eldest Son The Adventures of the Younger Son of the Jackal The Three Treasures of the Giants The Rover of the Plain The White Doe The Girl Fish The Owl and the Eagle The Frog and the Lion <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='magic;mink;owl;fish;wreath;thief;son;slipper;enchanted;lion;doe;mirror;girl;jachal;jackal;blue;rover;story;casket;makoma;soldier;treasure;fox;frog;book;goldsmith;bird;eagle;clever;hero;truth;covan;eldest;white;adventure;rabbit;falcon;weaver;younger;fortune;plain;stalos;duckling;adventures;cat;ugly;s;wolf;bella-flor;the;foolish' adjectives='jackal' verbs='trick;be;see;get' valence='6.13954545455' arousal='4.61590909091' dominance='5.43621212121'>Fairy</entity> The Adventures of Covan the Brown-haired The <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='magic;mink;owl;fish;wreath;thief;son;slipper;enchanted;lion;doe;mirror;girl;jachal;jackal;blue;rover;story;casket;makoma;soldier;treasure;fox;frog;book;goldsmith;bird;eagle;clever;hero;truth;covan;eldest;white;adventure;rabbit;falcon;weaver;younger;fortune;plain;stalos;duckling;adventures;cat;ugly;s;wolf;bella-flor;the;foolish' adjectives='jackal' verbs='trick;be;see;get' valence='6.13954545455' arousal='4.61590909091' dominance='5.43621212121'>Princess</entity> Bella-Flor The Bird of Truth The Mink and the Wolf Adventures of an Indian Brave How the Stalos were Tricked <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='magic;mink;owl;fish;wreath;thief;son;slipper;enchanted;lion;doe;mirror;girl;jachal;jackal;blue;rover;story;casket;makoma;soldier;treasure;fox;frog;book;goldsmith;bird;eagle;clever;hero;truth;covan;eldest;white;adventure;rabbit;falcon;weaver;younger;fortune;plain;stalos;duckling;adventures;cat;ugly;s;wolf;bella-flor;the;foolish' adjectives='jackal' verbs='trick;be;see;get' valence='6.13954545455' arousal='4.61590909091' dominance='5.43621212121'>Andras Baive</entity> The White Slipper The Magic Book</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='15'></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='16'></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='17'>The Orange <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='orange;book' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='6.85666666667' arousal='4.07' dominance='6.12333333333'>Fairy</entity> Book</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='18'></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='19'></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='20'>The Story of the Hero <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='story;hero' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='7.355' arousal='4.935' dominance='5.555'>Makoma</entity></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='21'>From the Senna (Oral Tradition)</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='22'></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='23'>Once upon a time, at the town of Senna on the banks of the Zambesi, was born a child.  He was not like other children, for he was very tall and strong; over his shoulder he carried a big sack, and in his hand an iron hammer.  He could also speak like a grown man, but usually he was very silent.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='24'>One day his mother said to him: "My child, by what name shall we know you?"</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='25'>And he answered: "Call all the head men of Senna here to the river"s bank." And his mother called the head men of <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='crocodile;head;man;pool;mother' adjectives='fierce;black;deep' verbs='come;live;call;lead;have' valence='5.755' arousal='4.3075' dominance='5.465'>the town</entity>, and when they had come he led them down to a deep black pool in <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='crocodile;head;man;pool;mother' adjectives='fierce;black;deep' verbs='come;live;call;lead;have' valence='5.755' arousal='4.3075' dominance='5.465'>the river</entity> where all the fierce crocodiles lived.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='26'>"O great men!" he said, while they all listened, "which of you will leap into the pool and overcome the crocodiles?" But no one would come forward.  So he turned and sprang into the water and disappeared.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='27'>The people held their breath, for they thought: "Surely the boy is bewitched and throws away his life, for the crocodiles will eat him!" Then suddenly the ground trembled, and <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='shore;blood;surface;ground' adjectives='red' verbs='swim;tremble;rise;swirl;become;heave' valence='5.43' arousal='4.38416666667' dominance='5.43'>the pool</entity>, heaving and swirling, became red with blood, and presently <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='shore;blood;surface;ground' adjectives='red' verbs='swim;tremble;rise;swirl;become;heave' valence='5.43' arousal='4.38416666667' dominance='5.43'>the boy</entity> rising to the surface swam on shore.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='28'>But he was no longer just a boy!  He was stronger than any man and very tall and handsome, so that the people shouted with gladness when they saw him.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='29'>"Now, O my people!" he cried, waving his hand, "you know my name--I am <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='crocodile;none;name;greater;hand' adjectives='' verbs='be;venture;slay;cry;wave;know;have' valence='5.26571428571' arousal='4.37428571429' dominance='5.23785714286'>Makoma</entity>, "the Greater"; for have I not slain the crocodiles into <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='crocodile;none;name;greater;hand' adjectives='' verbs='be;venture;slay;cry;wave;know;have' valence='5.26571428571' arousal='4.37428571429' dominance='5.23785714286'>the pool</entity> where none would venture?"</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='30'>Then he said to his mother: "Rest gently, my mother, for I go to make a home for myself and become a hero."  Then, entering his hut he took Nu-endo, his iron hammer, and throwing the sack over his shoulder, he went away.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='31'><entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='mountain;giant;north;west;moon;country' adjectives='many;huge;hilly' verbs='meet;make;come;cross;wander' valence='5.87647058824' arousal='3.70176470588' dominance='5.48294117647'>Makoma</entity> crossed the <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='mountain;giant;north;west;moon;country' adjectives='many;huge;hilly' verbs='meet;make;come;cross;wander' valence='5.87647058824' arousal='3.70176470588' dominance='5.48294117647'>Zambesi</entity>, and for many moons he wandered towards the north and west until he came to a very hilly country where, one day, he met a huge giant making mountains.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='32'>"Greeting," shouted <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='greeting' adjectives='' verbs='be;shout' valence='5.69' arousal='4.88666666667' dominance='5.88'>Makoma</entity>, "you are you?"</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='33'>"I am Chi-eswa-mapiri, who makes the mountains," answered <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='mountain' adjectives='chi-eswa-mapiri' verbs='answer;be;make' valence='5.94428571429' arousal='4.10714285714' dominance='5.86142857143'>the giant</entity>; "and who are you?"</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='34'>"I am <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='greater' verbs='answer;be;signify' valence='5.61' arousal='4.3075' dominance='5.5075'>Makoma</entity>, which signifies "greater,"" answered he.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='35'>"Greater than who?" asked <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='' verbs='ask' valence='5.68' arousal='4.29' dominance='6.485'>the giant</entity>.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='36'>"Greater than you!" answered <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='' verbs='answer' valence='6.1' arousal='4.0' dominance='5.95'>Makoma</entity>.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='37'>The giant gave a roar and rushed upon him.  <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='nothing;head;hammer;nu-endo' adjectives='great' verbs='strike;say;swing' valence='5.69428571429' arousal='4.61428571429' dominance='5.82857142857'>Makoma</entity> said nothing, but swinging his great hammer, Nu-endo, he struck <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='nothing;head;hammer;nu-endo' adjectives='great' verbs='strike;say;swing' valence='5.69428571429' arousal='4.61428571429' dominance='5.82857142857'>the giant</entity> upon the head.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='38'>He struck him so hard a blow that the giant shrank into quite a little man, who fell upon his knees saying: "You are indeed greater than I, O Makoma; take me with you to be your slave!"  So <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='back;sack' adjectives='' verbs='carry;drop;pick' valence='5.136' arousal='3.718' dominance='5.184'>Makoma</entity> picked him up and dropped him into the sack that he carried upon his back.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='39'>He was greater than ever now, for all <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='eagle;strength;hare;difficulty;s;journey;burden' adjectives='little;greater' verbs='go;be;carry;have;resume' valence='5.47' arousal='4.25823529412' dominance='5.31941176471'>the giant</entity>"s strength had gone into him; and he resumed his journey, carrying his burden with as little difficulty as an eagle might carry a hare.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='40'>Before long he came to a country broken up with huge stones and immense clods of earth.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='41'>Looking over one of the heaps he saw a giant wrapped in dust dragging out the very earth and hurling it in handfuls on either side of him.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='42'>"Who are you," cried <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='way' adjectives='' verbs='be;cry;pull' valence='5.546' arousal='4.184' dominance='4.916'>Makoma</entity>, "that pulls up <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='way' adjectives='' verbs='be;cry;pull' valence='5.546' arousal='4.184' dominance='4.916'>the earth</entity> in this way?"</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='43'>"I am Chi-dubula-taka," said he, "and I am making the river-beds."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='44'>"Do you know who I am?" said Makoma.  "I am he that is called "greater"!"</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='45'>"Greater than who?" thundered <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='' verbs='thunder' valence='5.575' arousal='5.425' dominance='5.29'>the giant</entity>.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='46'>"Greater than you!" answered <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='' verbs='answer' valence='6.1' arousal='4.0' dominance='5.95'>Makoma</entity>.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='47'>With a shout, Chi-dubula-taka seized a great clod of earth and launched it at Makoma.  But the hero had his sack held over his left arm and the stones and earth fell harmlessly upon it, and, tightly gripping his iron hammer, he rushed in and struck the giant to the ground. Chi-dubula-taka grovelled before him, all the while growing smaller and smaller; and when he had become a convenient size <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='eswa-mapirus;while;sack;size' adjectives='convenient;chi-dubula-taka;smaller' verbs='grovel;have;pick;put;become;grow' valence='5.563' arousal='3.654' dominance='5.303'>Makoma</entity> picked him up and put him into the sack beside <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='eswa-mapirus;while;sack;size' adjectives='convenient;chi-dubula-taka;smaller' verbs='grovel;have;pick;put;become;grow' valence='5.563' arousal='3.654' dominance='5.303'>Chi</entity>- eswa-mapiri.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='48'>He went on his way even greater than before, as all the river-maker"s power had become his; and at last he came to a forest of bao- babs and thorn trees.  He was astonished at their size, for every one was full grown and larger than any trees he had ever seen, and close by he saw Chi-gwisa-miti, <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='chi-gwisa-mitus;tree;size' adjectives='full;larger' verbs='be;plant;see;astonish;have;grow' valence='6.074375' arousal='3.716875' dominance='5.65625'>the giant</entity> who was planting <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='chi-gwisa-mitus;tree;size' adjectives='full;larger' verbs='be;plant;see;astonish;have;grow' valence='6.074375' arousal='3.716875' dominance='5.65625'>the forest</entity>.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='49'>Chi-gwisa-miti was taller than either of his brothers, but <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='chi-gwisa-mitus;big;brother;o' adjectives='taller;afraid' verbs='be;call' valence='5.54222222222' arousal='3.90888888889' dominance='5.16111111111'>Makoma</entity> was not afraid, and called out to him: "Who are you, O Big One?"</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='50'>"I," said <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='chi-gwisa-mitus;bao-bab;food;thorn;child;elephant' adjectives='' verbs='be;say;plant' valence='5.85454545455' arousal='4.41272727273' dominance='5.57909090909'>the giant</entity>, "am Chi-gwisa-miti, and I am planting these bao-babs and thorns as food for my children the elephants."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='51'>"Leave off!" shouted the hero, "for I am <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='blow;hero' adjectives='' verbs='be;shout;like;exchange' valence='5.99666666667' arousal='4.83555555556' dominance='5.58111111111'>Makoma</entity>, and would like to exchange a blow with thee!"</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='3' num='52'><entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='blow;head;hero;monster;hammer;weapon;earth;root;round;bao-bab' adjectives='soft' verbs='whirl;spring;pluck;fell;sink;strike' valence='5.4135' arousal='4.554' dominance='5.362'>The giant</entity>, plucking up a monster bao-bab by the roots, struck heavily at <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='blow;head;hero;monster;hammer;weapon;earth;root;round;bao-bab' adjectives='soft' verbs='whirl;spring;pluck;fell;sink;strike' valence='5.4135' arousal='4.554' dominance='5.362'>Makoma</entity>; but the hero sprang aside, and as the weapon sank deep into the soft earth, whirled Nu-endo the hammer round his head and felled <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='blow;head;hero;monster;hammer;weapon;earth;root;round;bao-bab' adjectives='soft' verbs='whirl;spring;pluck;fell;sink;strike' valence='5.4135' arousal='4.554' dominance='5.362'>the giant</entity> with one blow.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='53'>So terrible was the stroke that Chi-gwisa- miti shrivelled up as the other giants had done; and when he had got back his breath he begged Makoma to take him as his servant.  "For," said he, "it is honourable to serve a man so great as thou."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='54'>Makoma, after placing him in his sack, proceeded upon his journey, and travelling for many days he at last reached a country so barren and rocky that not a single living thing grew upon it--everywhere reigned grim desolation.  And in the midst of this dead region he found a man eating fire.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='55'>"What are you doing?" demanded <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='' verbs='demand' valence='4.1' arousal='5.85' dominance='5.14'>Makoma</entity>.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='56'>"I am eating fire," answered <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='fire;name;flame-spirit' adjectives='chi-idea-moto' verbs='be;like;laugh;answer;destroy;waste;eat' valence='5.549375' arousal='4.405' dominance='5.553125'>the man</entity>, laughing; "and my name is Chi-idea-moto, for I am the flame-spirit, and can waste and destroy what I like."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='57'>"You are wrong," said <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='wrong;greater' verbs='be;say;destroy' valence='5.19666666667' arousal='4.25666666667' dominance='5.27888888889'>Makoma</entity>; "for I am <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='wrong;greater' verbs='be;say;destroy' valence='5.19666666667' arousal='4.25666666667' dominance='5.27888888889'>Makoma</entity>, who is "greater" than you--and you cannot destroy me!"</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='58'>The fire-eater laughed again, and blew a flame at Makoma.  But the hero sprang behind a rock--just in time, for the ground upon which he had been standing was turned to molten glass, like an overbaked pot, by the heat of the flame-spirit"s breath.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='59'>Then the hero flung his iron hammer at Chi- idea-moto, and, striking him, it knocked him helpless; so <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='woro-nowu;hero;chi;sack;idea-moto;iron;hammer;man' adjectives='helpless;other;great;striking' verbs='knock;place;overcome;have;fling' valence='5.61307692308' arousal='4.38230769231' dominance='5.59615384615'>Makoma</entity> placed him in the sack, Woro-nowu, with the other great men that he had overcome.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='60'>And now, truly, <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='waste;hero;power;fire;industry;tree;wisdom;foresight;strength;hill;river' adjectives='dry;great' verbs='be;plant;lead;wish;make;produce;have' valence='6.06666666667' arousal='4.1319047619' dominance='5.9019047619'>Makoma</entity> was a very great hero; for he had the strength to make hills, the industry to lead rivers over dry wastes, foresight and wisdom in planting trees, and the power of producing fire when he wished.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='61'>Wandering on he arrived one day at a great plain, well watered and full of game; and in the very middle of it, close to a large river, was a grassy spot, very pleasant to make a home upon.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='62'>Makoma was so delighted with the little meadow that he sat down under a large tree and removing the sack from his shoulder, took out all the giants and set them before him.  "My friends," said he, "I have travelled far and am weary.  Is not this such a place as would suit a hero for his home?  Let us then go, to-morrow, to bring in timber to make a kraal."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='63'>So the next day Makoma and the giants set out to get poles to build the kraal, leaving only Chi-eswa-mapiri to look after the place and cook some venison which they had killed.  In the evening, when they returned, they found <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='hair;tree' adjectives='helpless;enormous' verbs='tie;return;find' valence='5.72818181818' arousal='3.82909090909' dominance='5.53545454545'>the giant</entity> helpless and tied to a tree by one enormous hair!</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='64'>"How is it," said <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='astonished;helpless' verbs='be;say;find;bind' valence='5.20833333333' arousal='4.595' dominance='5.22333333333'>Makoma</entity>, astonished, "that we find you thus bound and helpless?"</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='65'>"O Chief," answered Chi-eswa-mapiri, "at mid- day a man came out of the river; he was of immense statue, and his grey moustaches were of such length that I could not see where they ended!  He demanded of me "Who is thy master?" And I answered: "Makoma, the greatest of heroes." Then <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='hair;tree;moustache' adjectives='' verbs='tie;pull;see;seize' valence='5.46' arousal='4.09416666667' dominance='5.45166666667'>the man</entity> seized me, and pulling a hair from his moustache, tied me to this tree--even as you see me."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='66'><entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='rope;finger-nail;mountain-maker;hair;palm;nothing' adjectives='thick;wroth;free;strong' verbs='be;say;cut;set;draw' valence='5.87916666667' arousal='3.9725' dominance='5.95916666667'>Makoma</entity> was very wroth, but he said nothing, and drawing his finger-nail across the hair (which was as thick and strong as palm rope) cut it, and set free the mountain-maker.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='67'>The three following days exactly the same thing happened, only each time with a different one of the party; and on the fourth day <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='sort;camp;s;thing;pole;other;sight;time;party;moustache;man' adjectives='different;same' verbs='be;cut;extend;live;see;stay;say;go;happen' valence='5.915' arousal='3.92633333333' dominance='5.537'>Makoma</entity> stayed in camp when the others went to cut poles, saying that he would see for himself what sort of man this was that lived in <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='sort;camp;s;thing;pole;other;sight;time;party;moustache;man' adjectives='different;same' verbs='be;cut;extend;live;see;stay;say;go;happen' valence='5.915' arousal='3.92633333333' dominance='5.537'>the river</entity> and whose moustaches were so long that they extended beyond men"s sight.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='68'>So when the giants had gone he swept and tidied the camp and put some venison on the fire to roast.  At midday, when the sun was right overhead, he heard a rumbling noise from the river, and looking up he saw the head and shoulders of an enormous man emerging from it.  And behold! right down the river-bed and up the river-bed, till they faded into the blue distance, stretched <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='distance;s;moustache' adjectives='blue;river-bed;grey' verbs='stretch;fade' valence='5.39375' arousal='4.22' dominance='5.6325'>the giant</entity>"s grey moustaches!</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='69'>"Who are you?" bellowed <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='water' adjectives='' verbs='be;bellow' valence='5.805' arousal='4.2475' dominance='6.14'>the giant</entity>, as soon as he was out of the water.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='70'>"I am he that is called <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='hero;name' adjectives='' verbs='be;slay;doest;answer;call;tell' valence='5.65384615385' arousal='4.22692307692' dominance='5.32307692308'>Makoma</entity>," answered the hero; "and, before I slay thee, tell me also what is thy name and what thou doest in <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='hero;name' adjectives='' verbs='be;slay;doest;answer;call;tell' valence='5.65384615385' arousal='4.22692307692' dominance='5.32307692308'>the river</entity>?"</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='71'>"My name is Chin-debou Mau-giri," said the giant.  "My home is in <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='water;home;moustache;fever-mist' adjectives='grey;unto' verbs='come;be;hang;die;bind' valence='5.345' arousal='4.305' dominance='5.18083333333'>the river</entity>, for my moustache is the grey fever-mist that hangs above the water, and with which I bind all those that come unto me so that they die."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='3' num='72'>"You cannot bind me!" shouted Makoma, rushing upon him and striking with his hammer.  But <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='blow;hair;giant;balance;chest' adjectives='slimy;green;long' verbs='regain;be;trip;try;slide;swing;stumble' valence='5.81882352941' arousal='4.20588235294' dominance='5.74588235294'>the river</entity> giant was so slimy that the blow slid harmlessly off his green chest, and as <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='blow;hair;giant;balance;chest' adjectives='slimy;green;long' verbs='regain;be;trip;try;slide;swing;stumble' valence='5.81882352941' arousal='4.20588235294' dominance='5.74588235294'>Makoma</entity> stumbled and tried to regain his balance, <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='blow;hair;giant;balance;chest' adjectives='slimy;green;long' verbs='regain;be;trip;try;slide;swing;stumble' valence='5.81882352941' arousal='4.20588235294' dominance='5.74588235294'>the giant</entity> swung one of his long hairs around him and tripped him up.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='73'>For a moment <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='hair;power;moment;breath;s;flame-spirit' adjectives='helpless;free;fiery' verbs='breathe;be;cut;remember;have;enter' valence='5.71529411765' arousal='4.33' dominance='5.69411764706'>Makoma</entity> was helpless, but remembering the power of the flame-spirit which had entered into him, he breathed a fiery breath upon <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='hair;power;moment;breath;s;flame-spirit' adjectives='helpless;free;fiery' verbs='breathe;be;cut;remember;have;enter' valence='5.71529411765' arousal='4.33' dominance='5.69411764706'>the giant</entity>"s hair and cut himself free.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='74'>As Chin-debou Mau-giri leaned forward to seize him the hero flung his sack <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='blow;head;hero;debou;sack;s;chin;iron;time;hammer' adjectives='dry;slippery;dead' verbs='grip;fling;alight;seize;lean;fall;strike' valence='5.03523809524' arousal='4.36' dominance='5.12047619048'>Woronowu</entity> over <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='blow;head;hero;debou;sack;s;chin;iron;time;hammer' adjectives='dry;slippery;dead' verbs='grip;fling;alight;seize;lean;fall;strike' valence='5.03523809524' arousal='4.36' dominance='5.12047619048'>the giant</entity>"s slippery head, and gripping his iron hammer, struck him again; this time the blow alighted upon the dry sack and Chin- debou Mau-giri fell dead.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='3' num='75'>When the four giants returned at sunset with the poles, they rejoiced to find that <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='giant;fever-spirit;hand;pole;venison;sunset;roast;face' adjectives='gloomy' verbs='be;rejoice;feast;warm;awake;have;return;find;overcome' valence='6.07454545455' arousal='4.19' dominance='5.72545454545'>Makoma</entity> had overcome the fever-spirit, and they feasted on the roast venison till far into the night; but in the morning, when they awoke, <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='giant;fever-spirit;hand;pole;venison;sunset;roast;face' adjectives='gloomy' verbs='be;rejoice;feast;warm;awake;have;return;find;overcome' valence='6.07454545455' arousal='4.19' dominance='5.72545454545'>Makoma</entity> was already warming his hands to <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='giant;fever-spirit;hand;pole;venison;sunset;roast;face' adjectives='gloomy' verbs='be;rejoice;feast;warm;awake;have;return;find;overcome' valence='6.07454545455' arousal='4.19' dominance='5.72545454545'>the fire</entity>, and his face was gloomy.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='76'>"In the darkness of the night, O my friends," he said presently, "the white spirits of my fathers came upon me and spoke, saying: "Get thee hence, <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='head;darkness;father;rest;leave;o;spirit;friend' adjectives='white;strong;great' verbs='be;get;fight;go;say;take;have;hast;come;find;speak' valence='5.89413793103' arousal='4.15275862069' dominance='5.66931034483'>Makoma</entity>, for thou shalt have no rest until thou hast found and fought with <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='head;darkness;father;rest;leave;o;spirit;friend' adjectives='white;strong;great' verbs='be;get;fight;go;say;take;have;hast;come;find;speak' valence='5.89413793103' arousal='4.15275862069' dominance='5.66931034483'>Sakatirina</entity>, who had five heads, and is very great and strong; so take leave of thy friends, for thou must go alone.""</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='77'>Then the giants were very sad, and bewailed the loss of their hero; but Makoma comforted them, and gave back to each the gifts he had taken from them.  Then bidding them "Farewell," he went on his way.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='78'><entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='standing;mountain;woman;west;hut;length;peak;man;river;desert;morass' adjectives='dry;beautiful;water-logged;deep;large;rough' verbs='be;die;travel;ford;tramp;have;arrive' valence='5.63461538462' arousal='4.16307692308' dominance='5.50923076923'>Makoma</entity> travelled far towards the west; over rough mountains and water-logged morasses, fording deep rivers, and tramping for days across dry deserts where most men would have died, until at length he arrived at a hut standing near some large peaks, and inside <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='standing;mountain;woman;west;hut;length;peak;man;river;desert;morass' adjectives='dry;beautiful;water-logged;deep;large;rough' verbs='be;die;travel;ford;tramp;have;arrive' valence='5.63461538462' arousal='4.16307692308' dominance='5.50923076923'>the hut</entity> were two beautiful women.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='79'>"Greeting!" said the hero.  "Is this <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='head' adjectives='' verbs='be;seek' valence='5.85857142857' arousal='3.92428571429' dominance='5.67428571429'>the country</entity> of <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='head' adjectives='' verbs='be;seek' valence='5.85857142857' arousal='3.92428571429' dominance='5.67428571429'>Sakatirina</entity> of five heads, whom I am seeking?"</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='80'>"We greet you, O Great One!" answered the women.  "We are the wives of Sakatirina; your search is at an end, for there stands he whom you seek!"  And they pointed to what Makoma had thought were two tall mountain peaks.  "Those are his legs," they said; "his body you cannot see, for it is hidden in the clouds."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='81'>Makoma was astonished when he beheld how tall was the giant; but, nothing daunted, he went forward until he reached one of Sakatirina"s legs, which he struck heavily with Nu-endo.  Nothing happened, so he hit again and then again until, presently, he heard a tired, far-away voice saying: "Who is it that scratches my feet?"</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='82'>And Makoma shouted as loud as he could, answering: "It is I, Makoma, who is called "Greater"!" And he listened, but there was no answer.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='83'>Then <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='leg;light;tree;brushwood;s;pile;round' adjectives='enormous;dead' verbs='collect;make;set;find' valence='5.518' arousal='3.89066666667' dominance='5.43'>Makoma</entity> collected all the dead brushwood and trees that he could find, and making an enormous pile round <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='leg;light;tree;brushwood;s;pile;round' adjectives='enormous;dead' verbs='collect;make;set;find' valence='5.518' arousal='3.89066666667' dominance='5.43'>the giant</entity>"s legs, set a light to it.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='84'>This time the giant spoke; his voice was very terrible, for it was the rumble of thunder in the clouds.  "Who is it," he said, "making that fire smoulder around my feet?"</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='85'>"It is I, Makoma!" shouted the hero.  "And I have come from far away to see thee, O <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='father;spirit;o' adjectives='fat;weary' verbs='come;bid;fight;see;have;go;seek;grow' valence='5.324375' arousal='4.26125' dominance='5.32'>Sakatirina</entity>, for the spirits of my fathers bade me go seek and fight with thee, lest I should grow fat, and weary of myself."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='86'>There was silence for a while, and then the giant spoke softly: "It is good, O Makoma!" he said.  "For I too have grown weary.  There is no man so great as I, therefore I am all alone.  Guard thyself!" and bending suddenly he seized the hero in his hands and dashed him upon the ground.  And lo! instead of death, <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='life;death;waist;strength;stature;foot' adjectives='mightier' verbs='grip;rush;wrestle;spring;have;find' valence='5.39076923077' arousal='4.54923076923' dominance='5.95153846154'>Makoma</entity> had found life, for he sprang to his feet mightier in strength and stature than before, and rushing in he gripped <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='life;death;waist;strength;stature;foot' adjectives='mightier' verbs='grip;rush;wrestle;spring;have;find' valence='5.39076923077' arousal='4.54923076923' dominance='5.95153846154'>the giant</entity> by the waist and wrestled with him.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='87'>Hour by hour they fought, and mountains rolled beneath their feet like pebbles in a flood; now Makoma would break away, and summoning up his strength, strike the giant with Nu-endo his iron hammer, and Sakatirina would pluck up the mountains and hurl them upon the hero, but neither one could slay the other.  At last, upon the second day, they grappled so strongly that they could not break away; but their strength was failing, and, just as the sun was sinking, they fell together to the ground, insensible.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='88'>In the morning when they awoke, Mulimo the Great Spirit was standing by them; and he said: "O Makoma and Sakatirina!  Ye are heroes so great that no man may come against you.  Therefore ye will leave the world and take up your home with me in the clouds."  And as he spake the heroes became invisible to the people of the <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='hero;people' adjectives='invisible' verbs='become;be;see;speak' valence='6.20625' arousal='4.2575' dominance='5.58875'>Earth</entity>, and were no more seen among them.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='89'>[Native Rhodesian Tale.]</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='90'></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='91'></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='92'>The Magic Mirror</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='93'>From the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='5.0' arousal='5.0' dominance='5.0'>Senna</entity></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='94'></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='95'>A long, long while ago, before ever the White Men were seen in <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='gopani-kufa;man' adjectives='' verbs='be;see;call;live' valence='6.0225' arousal='4.13' dominance='5.595'>Senna</entity>, there lived a man called Gopani-Kufa.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='96'>One day, as he was out hunting, he came upon a strange sight.  An enormous python had caught an antelope and coiled itself around it; the antelope, striking out in despair with its horns, had pinned the python"s neck to a tree, and so deeply had its horns sunk in the soft wood that neither creature could get away.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='97'>"Help!" cried the antelope, "for I was doing no harm, yet I have been caught, and would have been eaten, had I not defended myself."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='98'>"Help me," said the python, "for I am Insato, <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='python;insato' adjectives='' verbs='be;say;reward;help' valence='5.71555555556' arousal='4.55444444444' dominance='5.7'>King</entity> of all the Reptiles, and will reward you well!"</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='99'><entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='python;moment;antelope;assegai' adjectives='free' verbs='set;stab;consider' valence='5.435' arousal='4.4725' dominance='5.3275'>Gopani-Kufa</entity> considered for a moment, then stabbing the antelope with his assegai, he set the python free.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='100'>"I thank you," said the python; "come back here with the new moon, when I shall have eaten the antelope, and I will reward you as I promised."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='101'>"Yes," said the dying antelope, "he will reward you, and lo! your reward shall be your own undoing!"</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='102'><entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='python;kraal;spot;moon' adjectives='new' verbs='go;save;return;have' valence='5.95111111111' arousal='4.03444444444' dominance='5.33777777778'>Gopani-Kufa</entity> went back to his kraal, and with the new moon he returned again to the spot where he had saved the python.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='103'><entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='possession;country;effect;pita;meal;ground' adjectives='huge;own;sleepy' verbs='be;thank;lie;give;say;see;come' valence='5.57904761905' arousal='3.91523809524' dominance='5.7280952381'>Insato</entity> was lying upon the ground, still sleepy from the effects of his huge meal, and when he saw <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='possession;country;effect;pita;meal;ground' adjectives='huge;own;sleepy' verbs='be;thank;lie;give;say;see;come' valence='5.57904761905' arousal='3.91523809524' dominance='5.7280952381'>the man</entity> he thanked him again, and said: "Come with me now to Pita, which is my own country, and I will give you what you will of all my possessions."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='104'><entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='thinking;insato;antelope' adjectives='afraid' verbs='be;say;follow;have;consent' valence='5.68111111111' arousal='4.21555555556' dominance='5.54'>Gopani-Kufa</entity> at first was afraid, thinking of what the antelope had said, but finally he consented and followed Insato into <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='thinking;insato;antelope' adjectives='afraid' verbs='be;say;follow;have;consent' valence='5.68111111111' arousal='4.21555555556' dominance='5.54'>the forest</entity>.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='105'>For several days they travelled, and at last they came to a hole leading deep into the earth.  It was not very wide, but large enough to admit a man.  "Hold on to my tail," said Insato, "and I will go down first, drawing you after me."  <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='' verbs='do;enter' valence='5.64' arousal='4.11' dominance='6.19333333333'>The man</entity> did so, and <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='' verbs='do;enter' valence='5.64' arousal='4.11' dominance='6.19333333333'>Insato</entity> entered.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='106'>Down, down, down they went for days, all the while getting deeper and deeper into the earth, until at last the darkness ended and they dropped into a beautiful country; around them grew short green grass, on which browsed herds of cattle and sheep and goats.  In the distance Gopani-Kufa saw a great collection of houses all square, built of stone and very tall, and their roofs were shining with gold and burnished iron.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='107'><entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='neck;gold;python;s;place;snake;skin;ring;arm;man' adjectives='great;strong;round;pure;handsome' verbs='wrap;turn;cover;find;be' valence='5.87333333333' arousal='4.30619047619' dominance='5.52142857143'>Gopani-Kufa</entity> turned to <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='neck;gold;python;s;place;snake;skin;ring;arm;man' adjectives='great;strong;round;pure;handsome' verbs='wrap;turn;cover;find;be' valence='5.87333333333' arousal='4.30619047619' dominance='5.52142857143'>Insato</entity>, but found, in the place of the python, a man, strong and handsome, with the great snake"s skin wrapped round him for covering; and on his arms and neck were rings of pure gold.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='108'>The man smiled.  "I am Insato," said he, "but in my own country I take man"s shape--even as you see me--for this is Pita, the land over which I am king."  He then took <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='hand' adjectives='' verbs='take;lead' valence='5.4675' arousal='4.065' dominance='5.35'>Gopani-Kufa</entity> by the hand and led him towards <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='hand' adjectives='' verbs='take;lead' valence='5.4675' arousal='4.065' dominance='5.35'>the town</entity>.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='109'>On the way they passed rivers in which men and women were bathing and fishing and boating; and farther on they came to gardens covered with heavy crops of rice and maize, and many other grains which Gopani-Kufa did not even know the name of.  And as they passed, the people who were singing at their work in the fields, abandoned their labours and saluted <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='people;work;cocoanut;delight;field;labour;palm;refreshment;singing;journey;wine' adjectives='green;long' verbs='be;return;bring;pass;abandon;salute' valence='5.88470588235' arousal='4.01294117647' dominance='5.70823529412'>Insato</entity> with delight, bringing also palm wine and green cocoanuts for refreshment, as to one returned from a long journey.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='110'>"These are my children!" said Insato, waving his hand towards the people.  Gopani-Kufa was much astonished at all that he saw, but he said nothing.  Presently they came to the town; everything here, too, was beautiful, and everything that a man might desire he could obtain. Even the grains of dust in the streets were of gold and silver.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='111'>Insato conducted Gopani-Kufa to the palace, and showing him his rooms, and the maidens who would wait upon him, told him that they would have a great feast that night, and on the morrow he might name his choice of the riches of Pita and it should be given him.  Then he was away.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='112'>Now Gopani-Kufa had a wasp called Zengi-mizi.  Zengi-mizi was not an ordinary wasp, for the spirit of the father of Gopani-Kufa had entered it, so that it was exceedingly wise.  In times of doubt Gopani-Kufa always consulted the wasp as to what had better be done, so on this occasion he took it out of the little rush basket in which he carried it, saying: "Zengi-mizi, what gift shall I ask of Insato to-morrow when he would know the reward he shall bestow on me for saving his life?"</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='113'>"Biz-z-z," hummed Zengi-mizi, "ask him for Sipao the Mirror."  And it flew back into its basket.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='114'>Gopani-Kufa was astonished at this answer; but knowing that the words of Zengi-mizi were true words, he determined to make the request.  So that night they feasted, and on the morrow <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='morrow;gopani-kufa' adjectives='' verbs='come;say;feast;greet;give' valence='6.57' arousal='4.39' dominance='6.04333333333'>Insato</entity> came to Gopani-Kufa and, giving him greeting joyfully, he said:</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='115'>"Now, O my friend, name your choice amongst my possessions and you shall have it!"</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='116'>"O king!" answered <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='possession;sipao;mirror' adjectives='' verbs='answer;have' valence='5.55333333333' arousal='4.00166666667' dominance='5.70833333333'>Gopani-Kufa</entity>, "out of all your possessions I will have the Mirror, Sipao."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='117'>The king started.  "O friend, Gopani-Kufa," he said, "ask anything but that!  I did not think that you would request that which is most precious to me."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='118'>"Let me think over it again then, O king," said <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='king;to-morrow;mind;o' adjectives='' verbs='say;let;think;change;know' valence='5.72461538462' arousal='4.09923076923' dominance='5.79384615385'>Gopani-Kufa</entity>, "and to-morrow I will let you know if I change my mind."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='119'>But <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='insato;loss;wish;power;mirror' adjectives='troubled;much;magic' verbs='fulfil;be;own;owe;have;ask;fear;possess' valence='5.330625' arousal='4.34' dominance='5.255'>the king</entity> was still much troubled, fearing the loss of <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='insato;loss;wish;power;mirror' adjectives='troubled;much;magic' verbs='fulfil;be;own;owe;have;ask;fear;possess' valence='5.330625' arousal='4.34' dominance='5.255'>Sipao</entity>, for the mirror had magic powers, so that he who owned it had but to ask and his wish would be fulfilled; to it Insato owed all that he possessed.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='120'>As soon as the king left him, Gopani-Kufa again took Zengi-mizi, out of his basket.  "Zengi-mizi," he said, "<entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='thing;mirror;request;value;zengi-mizus' adjectives='loth;other;equal' verbs='ask;be;say;seem;grant' valence='5.90416666667' arousal='4.10416666667' dominance='5.76583333333'>the king</entity> seems loth to grant my request for the Mirror--is there not some other thing of equal value for which I might ask?"</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='121'>And the wasp answered: "There is nothing in the world, O Gopani-Kufa, which is of such value as this Mirror, for it is a Wishing Mirror, and accomplishes the desires of him who owns it.  If <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='life;end;mirror' adjectives='' verbs='go;hesitate;bestow;save' valence='5.94818181818' arousal='4.17454545455' dominance='5.60454545455'>the king</entity> hesitates, go to him the next day, and the day after, and in the end he will bestow the Mirror upon you, for you saved his life."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='122'>And it was even so.  For three days Gopani- Kufa returned the same answer to the king, and, at last, with tears in his eyes, Insato gave him the Mirror, which was of polished iron, saying: "Take Sipao, then, O Gopani- Kufa, and may thy wishes come true.  Go back now to thine own country; <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='country' adjectives='own' verbs='go;show' valence='5.72666666667' arousal='3.51' dominance='5.695'>Sipao</entity> will show you <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='country' adjectives='own' verbs='go;show' valence='5.72666666667' arousal='3.51' dominance='5.695'>the way</entity>."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='123'><entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='farewell;mirror' adjectives='' verbs='be;say;rejoice;take' valence='5.62571428571' arousal='4.44857142857' dominance='5.79857142857'>Gopani-Kufa</entity> was greatly rejoiced, and, taking farewell of <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='farewell;mirror' adjectives='' verbs='be;say;rejoice;take' valence='5.62571428571' arousal='4.44857142857' dominance='5.79857142857'>the king</entity>, said to the Mirror:</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='124'>"Sipao, Sipao, I wish to be back upon the Earth again!"</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='125'>Instantly he found himself standing upon the upper earth; but, not knowing the spot, he said again to the Mirror:</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='126'>"Sipao, Sipao, I want <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='sipao;kraal' adjectives='own' verbs='want' valence='5.57' arousal='4.67666666667' dominance='5.00333333333'>the path</entity> to my own kraal!"</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='127'>And behold! right before him lay <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='' adjectives='' verbs='lay' valence='6.40333333333' arousal='4.14666666667' dominance='6.03333333333'>the path</entity>!</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='128'>When he arrived home he found his wife and daughter mourning for him, for they thought that he had been eaten by lions; but he comforted them, saying that while following a wounded antelope he had missed his way and had wandered for a long time before he had found <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='antelope;daughter;wife;mourning;lion;way;time;home' adjectives='wounded;long' verbs='wander;be;think;comfort;find;say;have;follow;arrive;miss;eat' valence='5.85076923077' arousal='3.96307692308' dominance='5.59076923077'>the path</entity> again.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='129'>That night he asked Zengi-mizi, in whom sat the spirit of his father, what he had better ask <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='father;spirit' adjectives='next' verbs='ask;have;sit' valence='6.30571428571' arousal='3.70714285714' dominance='5.87857142857'>Sipao</entity> for next?</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='130'>"Biz-z-z," said the wasp, "would you not like to be as great a chief as Insato?"</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='131'>And <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='mirror' adjectives='' verbs='smile;say;take' valence='6.13' arousal='4.53' dominance='6.2325'>Gopani-Kufa</entity> smiled, and took the Mirror and said to it:</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='132'>"Sipao, <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='town;sipao;insato;pita' adjectives='great;chief' verbs='wish;want;be' valence='5.92636363636' arousal='4.25' dominance='5.54363636364'>Sipao</entity>, I want a town as great as that of Insato, <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='town;sipao;insato;pita' adjectives='great;chief' verbs='wish;want;be' valence='5.92636363636' arousal='4.25' dominance='5.54363636364'>the King</entity> of Pita; and I wish to be chief over it!"</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='133'>Then all along the banks of the Zambesi river, which flowed near by, sprang up streets of stone buildings, and their roofs shone with gold and burnished iron like those in Pita; and in the streets men and women were walking, and young boys were driving out the sheep and cattle to pasture; and from the river came shouts and laughter from the young men and maidens who had launched their canoes and were fishing.  And when the people of the new town beheld Gopani-Kufa they rejoiced greatly and hailed him as chief.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='134'>Gopani-Kufa was now as powerful as Insato the King of the Reptiles had been, and he and his family moved into the palace that stood high above the other buildings right in the middle of the town.  His wife was too astonished at all these wonders to ask any questions, but his daughter <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='daughter;wife;question;secret;mirror;care;wonder' adjectives='astonished;whole;great;last' verbs='be;reveal;beg;keep;say;have;ask;become;entrust;tell' valence='6.1415' arousal='3.977' dominance='5.79'>Shasasa</entity> kept begging him to tell her how he had suddenly become so great; so at last he revealed the whole secret, and even entrusted <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='daughter;wife;question;secret;mirror;care;wonder' adjectives='astonished;whole;great;last' verbs='be;reveal;beg;keep;say;have;ask;become;entrust;tell' valence='6.1415' arousal='3.977' dominance='5.79'>Sipao</entity> the Mirror to her care, saying:</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='135'>"It will be safer with you, my daughter, for you dwell apart; whereas men come to consult me on affairs of state, and the Mirror might be stolen."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='136'>Then <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='wish;gopani-kufa;man;pillow;people' adjectives='many' verbs='do;love;grant;rule;ask;take;need;hide' valence='5.85066666667' arousal='4.09733333333' dominance='5.53266666667'>Shasasa</entity> took the Magic Mirror and hid it beneath her pillow, and after that for many years Gopani-Kufa ruled his people both well and wisely, so that all men loved him, and never once did he need to ask <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='wish;gopani-kufa;man;pillow;people' adjectives='many' verbs='do;love;grant;rule;ask;take;need;hide' valence='5.85066666667' arousal='4.09733333333' dominance='5.53266666667'>Sipao</entity> to grant him a wish.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='137'>Now it happened that, after many years, when the hair of Gopani-Kufa was turning grey with age, there came white men to that country.  Up the Zambesi they came, and they fought long and fiercely with Gopani-Kufa; but, because of the power of the Magic Mirror, he beat them, and they fled to the sea-coast.  Chief among them was one Rei, a man of much cunning, who sought to discover whence sprang Gopani-Kufa"s power.  So one day he called to him a trusty servant named <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='servant;secret;greatness' adjectives='trusty' verbs='be;name;say;call;go;find' valence='5.86533333333' arousal='3.94533333333' dominance='5.62266666667'>Butou</entity>, and said: "Go you to <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='servant;secret;greatness' adjectives='trusty' verbs='be;name;say;call;go;find' valence='5.86533333333' arousal='3.94533333333' dominance='5.62266666667'>the town</entity> and find out for me what is the secret of its greatness."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='3' num='138'>And Butou, dressing himself in rags, set out, and when he came to Gopani-Kufa"s town he asked for the chief; and the people took him into the presence of Gopani-Kufa.  When the white man saw him he humbled himself, and said: "O Chief! take pity on me, for I have no home!  When <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='strength;hand' adjectives='' verbs='starve;march;know;fight;turn;lay;stand' valence='5.25733333333' arousal='4.35866666667' dominance='5.408'>Rei</entity> marched against you I alone stood apart, for I knew that all the strength of the <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='strength;hand' adjectives='' verbs='starve;march;know;fight;turn;lay;stand' valence='5.25733333333' arousal='4.35866666667' dominance='5.408'>Zambesi</entity> lay in your hands, and because I would not fight against you he turned me forth into <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='strength;hand' adjectives='' verbs='starve;march;know;fight;turn;lay;stand' valence='5.25733333333' arousal='4.35866666667' dominance='5.408'>the forest</entity> to starve!"</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='139'>And <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='house;s;story;man' adjectives='white' verbs='believe;feast;take;give' valence='6.323' arousal='4.286' dominance='5.621'>Gopani-Kufa</entity> believed the white man"s story, and he took him in and feasted him, and gave him a house.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='140'>In this way the end came.  For the heart of Shasasa, the daughter of Gopani-Kufa, went forth to Butou the traitor, and from her he learnt the secret of the Magic Mirror.  One night, when all <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='chief;man;pillow;mirror' adjectives='white' verbs='feel;steal;sleep;find;flee' valence='5.67142857143' arousal='3.74785714286' dominance='5.31357142857'>the town</entity> slept, he felt beneath her pillow and, finding the Mirror, he stole it and fled back with it to <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='chief;man;pillow;mirror' adjectives='white' verbs='feel;steal;sleep;find;flee' valence='5.67142857143' arousal='3.74785714286' dominance='5.31357142857'>Rei</entity>, the chief of the white men.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='141'>So it befell that, one day, as Gopani-Kufa was gazing up at <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='misgave;war-canoe;window;sight;gopani-kufa;spirit;man' adjectives='white' verbs='be;befall;gaze;see' valence='5.91785714286' arousal='3.95642857143' dominance='5.435'>the river</entity> from a window of <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='misgave;war-canoe;window;sight;gopani-kufa;spirit;man' adjectives='white' verbs='be;befall;gaze;see' valence='5.91785714286' arousal='3.95642857143' dominance='5.435'>the palace</entity> he again saw the war-canoes of the white men; and at the sight his spirit misgave him.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='142'>"Shasasa! my daughter!" he cried wildly, "go fetch me the mirror, for the white men are at hand."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='143'>"Woe is me, my father!" she sobbed.  "The Mirror is gone!  For I loved Butou the traitor, and he has stolen Sipao from me!"</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='144'>Then <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='basket;rush' adjectives='' verbs='draw;calm' valence='5.695' arousal='3.575' dominance='6.475'>Gopani-Kufa</entity> calmed himself, and drew out Zengi-mizi from its rush basket.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='145'>"O spirit of my father!" he said, "what now shall I do?"</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='146'>"O Gopani-Kufa!" hummed the wasp, "there is nothing now that can be done, for the words of the antelope which you slew are being fulfilled."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='147'>"Alas!  I am an old man--I had forgotten!" cried the chief.  "The words of the antelope were true words--my reward shall be my undoing--they are being fulfilled!"</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='3' num='148'>Then the white men fell upon the people of Gopani-Kufa and slew them together with the chief and his daughter <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='possession;magic;daughter;power;people;hand;chief;mirror;gopani-kufa;slew;man' adjectives='white' verbs='rest;have;fall' valence='5.99058823529' arousal='4.12235294118' dominance='5.45529411765'>Shasasa</entity>; and since then all the power of the <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='possession;magic;daughter;power;people;hand;chief;mirror;gopani-kufa;slew;man' adjectives='white' verbs='rest;have;fall' valence='5.99058823529' arousal='4.12235294118' dominance='5.45529411765'>Earth</entity> has rested in the hands of the white men, for they have in their possession <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='possession;magic;daughter;power;people;hand;chief;mirror;gopani-kufa;slew;man' adjectives='white' verbs='rest;have;fall' valence='5.99058823529' arousal='4.12235294118' dominance='5.45529411765'>Sipao</entity>, the Magic Mirror.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='149'></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='150'></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='151'>Story of <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='story' adjectives='' verbs='see' valence='6.3625' arousal='3.92' dominance='5.7'>the King</entity> Who Would See</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='152'>Paradise</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='153'></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='154'>Once upon a time there was king who, one day out hunting, came upon a fakeer in a lonely place in the mountains.  The fakeer was seated on a little old bedstead reading the Koran, with his patched cloak thrown over his shoulders.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='155'>The king asked him what he was reading; and he said he was reading about Paradise, and praying that he might be worthy to enter there. Then they began to talk, and, by-and- bye, the king asked the fakeer if he could show him a glimpse of Paradise, for he found it very difficult to believe in what he could not see.  The fakeer replied that he was asking a very difficult, and perhaps a very dangerous, thing; but that he would pray for him, and perhaps he might be able to do it; only he warned the king both against the dangers of his unbelief, and against the curiosity which prompted him to ask this thing.  However, the king was not to be turned from his purpose, and he promised the fakeer always to provided him with food, if he, in return, would pray for him.  To this the fakeer agreed, and so they parted.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='156'>Time went on, and <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='fakeer;food;paradise;promise;time' adjectives='old' verbs='be;accord;show;send;ask;go;reply' valence='6.10133333333' arousal='3.97533333333' dominance='5.81'>the king</entity> always sent the old fakeer his food according to his promise; but, whenever he sent to ask him when he was going to show him Paradise, the fakeer always replied: "Not yet, not yet!"</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='157'>After a year or two had passed by, the king heard one day that the fakeer was very ill-- indeed, he was believed to be dying.  Instantly he hurried off himself, and found that it was really true, and that the fakeer was even then breathing his last.  There and then the king besought him to remember his promise, and to show him a glimpse of Paradise.  The dying fakeer replied that if the king would come to his funeral, and, when the grave was filled in, and everyone else was gone away, he would come and lay his hand upon the grave, he would keep his word, and show him a glimpse of Paradise.  At the same time he implored the king not to do this thing, but to be content to see Paradise when God called him there.  Still <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='s;way;curiosity' adjectives='' verbs='be;arouse;give' valence='6.13125' arousal='4.67' dominance='5.53875'>the king</entity>"s curiosity was so aroused that he would not give way.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='158'>Accordingly, after the fakeer was dead, and had been buried, he stayed behind when all the rest went away; and then, when he was quite alone, he stepped forward, and laid his hand upon the grave!  Instantly the ground opened, and the astonished king, peeping in, saw a flight of rough steps, and, at the bottom of them, the fakeer sitting, just as he used to sit, on his rickety bedstead, reading the Koran!</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='159'>At first <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='fakeer;courage' adjectives='frightened;surprised' verbs='stare;be;muster;step;beckon;come' valence='5.36727272727' arousal='4.47818181818' dominance='5.44636363636'>the king</entity> was so surprised and frightened that he could only stare; but the fakeer beckoned to him to come down, so, mustering up his courage, he boldly stepped down into <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='fakeer;courage' adjectives='frightened;surprised' verbs='stare;be;muster;step;beckon;come' valence='5.36727272727' arousal='4.47818181818' dominance='5.44636363636'>the grave</entity>.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='3' num='160'>The fakeer rose, and, making a sign to the king to follow, walked a few paces along a dark passage.  Then he stopped, turned solemnly to his companion, and, with a movement of his hand, drew aside as it were a heavy curtain, and revealed--what?  No one knows what was there shown to the king, nor did he ever tell anyone; but, when the fakeer at length dropped the curtain, and the king turned to leave the place, he had had his glimpse of Paradise!  Trembling in every limb, he staggered back along <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='limb;air' adjectives='fresh' verbs='stagger;tremble;stumble' valence='4.733' arousal='3.576' dominance='5.088'>the passage</entity>, and stumbled up <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='limb;air' adjectives='fresh' verbs='stagger;tremble;stumble' valence='4.733' arousal='3.576' dominance='5.088'>the steps</entity> out of <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='limb;air' adjectives='fresh' verbs='stagger;tremble;stumble' valence='4.733' arousal='3.576' dominance='5.088'>the tomb</entity> into the fresh air again.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='161'>The dawn was breaking.  It seemed odd to the king that he had been so long in the grave.  It appeared but a few minutes ago that he had descended, passed along a few steps to the place where he had peeped beyond the veil, and returned again after perhaps five minutes of that wonderful view!  And what WAS it he had seen?  He racked his brains to remember, but he could not call to mind a single thing!  How curious everything looked too!  Why, his own city, which by now he was entering, seemed changed and strange to him!  The sun was already up when he turned into the palace gate and entered the public durbar hall.  It was full; and there upon the throne sat another king!  The poor king, all bewildered, sat down and stared about him.  Presently a chamberlain came across and asked him why he sat unbidden in the king"s presence.  "But I am the king!" he cried.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='162'>"What king?" said the chamberlain.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='163'>"The true king of this country," said he indignantly.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='164'>Then the chamberlain went away, and spoke to the king who sat on the throne, and the old king heard words like "mad," "age," "compassion." Then the king on the throne called him to come forward, and, as he went, he caught sight of himself reflected in the polished steel shield of the bodyguard, and started back in horror!  He was old, decrepit, dirty, and ragged!  His long white beard and locks were unkempt, and straggled all over his chest and shoulders.  Only one sign of royalty remained to him, and that was the signet ring upon his right hand.  He dragged it off with shaking fingers and held it up to <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='finger' adjectives='' verbs='drag;hold;shake' valence='5.224' arousal='4.694' dominance='5.682'>the king</entity>.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='165'>"Tell me who I am," he cried; "there is my signet, who once sat where you sit--even yesterday!"</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='166'>The king looked at him compassionately, and examined the signet with curiosity.  Then he commanded, and they brought out dusty records and archives of the kingdom, and old coins of previous reigns, and compared them faithfully.  At last <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='king;none;whither;ring;signet;man' adjectives='old;last' verbs='be;get;reign;turn;say;know;have;hast;disappear' valence='5.509' arousal='4.078' dominance='5.562'>the king</entity> turned to the old man, and said: "Old man, such a king as this whose signet thou hast, reigned seven hundred years ago; but he is said to have disappeared, none know whither; where got you the ring?"</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='167'>Then the old man smote his breast, and cried out with a loud lamentation; for he understood that he, who was not content to wait patiently to see the Paradise of the faithful, had been judged already.  And he turned and left <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='life;word;jungle;prayer;meditation;punishment' adjectives='last' verbs='purge;purify;leave;turn;live;go;release;come' valence='5.6135' arousal='4.3455' dominance='5.5365'>the hall</entity> without a word, and went into the jungle, where he lived for twenty-five years a life of prayer and meditations, until at last the Angel of Death came to him, and mercifully released him, purged and purified through his punishment.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='168'>[A Pathan story told to Major Campbell.]</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='169'></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='170'></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='171'>How Isuro the Rabbit Tricked Gudu</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='172'></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='173'>Far away in a hot country, where the forests are very thick and dark, and the rivers very swift and strong, there once lived a strange pair of friends.  Now one of the friends was a big white rabbit named <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='baboon;rabbit;friend;gudu' adjectives='fond;big;white;other;tall' verbs='be;see;call;name' valence='6.03' arousal='3.77631578947' dominance='5.67052631579'>Isuro</entity>, and the other was a tall baboon called Gudu, and so fond were they of each other that they were seldom seen apart.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='174'>One day, when the sun was hotter even than usual, the rabbit awoke from his midday sleep, and saw Gudu the baboon standing beside him.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='175'>"Get up," said Gudu; "I am going courting, and you must come with me. So put some food in a bag, and sling it round your neck, for we may not be able to find anything to eat for a long while."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='176'>Then the rabbit rubbed his eyes, and gathered a store of fresh green things from under the bushes, and told <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='eye;thing;bush;journey;rabbit;store' adjectives='ready;fresh;green' verbs='rub;be;gather;tell' valence='6.07642857143' arousal='3.73142857143' dominance='5.77642857143'>Gudu</entity> that he was ready for the journey.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='177'>They went on quite happily for some distance, and at last they came to a river with rocks scattered here and there across <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='distance;river;rock' adjectives='last' verbs='go;come;scatter' valence='5.51125' arousal='4.18375' dominance='4.99625'>the stream</entity>.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='178'>"We can never jump those wide spaces if we are burdened with food," said Gudu, "we must throw it into the river, unless we wish to fall in ourselves."  And stooping down, unseen by <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='front;water;stone;splash' adjectives='big;loud;unseen' verbs='stoop;be;throw;pick' valence='5.51545454545' arousal='4.10272727273' dominance='5.59181818182'>Isuro</entity>, who was in front of him, <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='front;water;stone;splash' adjectives='big;loud;unseen' verbs='stoop;be;throw;pick' valence='5.51545454545' arousal='4.10272727273' dominance='5.59181818182'>Gudu</entity> picked up a big stone, and threw it into the water with a loud splash.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='179'>"It is your turn now," he cried to Isuro.  And with a heavy sigh, the rabbit unfastened his bag of food, which fell into <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='food;sigh;rabbit;bag' adjectives='heavy' verbs='unfasten;fall' valence='5.5575' arousal='4.015' dominance='4.9975'>the river</entity>.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='180'><entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='neck;tree;hair;bag;fruit;avenue;side' adjectives='thick;other;delicious-looking' verbs='begin;hide;lead;lay;have;go;open;eat' valence='5.86578947368' arousal='3.71684210526' dominance='5.76473684211'>The road</entity> on the other side led down an avenue of trees, and before they had gone very far <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='neck;tree;hair;bag;fruit;avenue;side' adjectives='thick;other;delicious-looking' verbs='begin;hide;lead;lay;have;go;open;eat' valence='5.86578947368' arousal='3.71684210526' dominance='5.76473684211'>Gudu</entity> opened the bag that lay hidden in the thick hair about his neck, and began to eat some delicious-looking fruit.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='181'>"Where did you get that from?" asked <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='' verbs='ask' valence='5.95' arousal='3.48' dominance='6.29'>Isuro</entity> enviously.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='182'>"Oh, I found after all that I could get across <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='pity;bag' adjectives='' verbs='answer;seem;keep;find;get' valence='5.39636363636' arousal='3.95454545455' dominance='5.31636363636'>the rocks</entity> quite easily, so it seemed a pity not to keep my bag," answered <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='pity;bag' adjectives='' verbs='answer;seem;keep;find;get' valence='5.39636363636' arousal='3.95454545455' dominance='5.31636363636'>Gudu</entity>.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='183'>"Well, as you tricked me into throwing away mine, you ought to let me share with you," said Isuro.  But <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='' verbs='stride;pretend;hear' valence='5.705' arousal='3.94' dominance='5.5025'>Gudu</entity> pretended not to hear him, and strode along <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='' adjectives='' verbs='stride;pretend;hear' valence='5.705' arousal='3.94' dominance='5.5025'>the path</entity>.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='184'>By-and-bye they entered a wood, and right in front of them was a tree so laden with fruit that its branches swept the ground.  And some of the fruit was still green, and some yellow.  The rabbit hopped forward with joy, for he was very hungry; but Gudu said to him: "Pluck the green fruit, you will find it much the best.  I will leave it all for you, as you have had no dinner, and take the yellow for myself."  So the rabbit took one of the green oranges and began to bite it, but its skin was so hard that he could hardly get his teeth through the rind.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='185'>"It does not taste at all nice," he cried, screwing up his face; "I would rather have one of the yellow ones."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='186'>"No! no!  I really could not allow that," answered Gudu.  "They would only make you ill.  Be content with the green fruit."  And as they were all he could get, <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='' verbs='put;be;force;get' valence='5.542' arousal='3.948' dominance='5.362'>Isuro</entity> was forced to put up with them.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='3' num='187'>After this had happened two or three times, Isuro at last had his eyes opened, and made up his mind that, whatever Gudu told him, he would do exactly the opposite.  However, by this time they had reached <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='dwelt;leaf;wife;whenever;bush;food;s;mouth;isuro;time;clump' adjectives='' verbs='be;gather;run;point;heal;burn;reach;say;hear;have;enter;call;eat' valence='5.80633333333' arousal='4.06133333333' dominance='5.607'>the village</entity> where dwelt <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='dwelt;leaf;wife;whenever;bush;food;s;mouth;isuro;time;clump' adjectives='' verbs='be;gather;run;point;heal;burn;reach;say;hear;have;enter;call;eat' valence='5.80633333333' arousal='4.06133333333' dominance='5.607'>Gudu</entity>"s future wife, and as they entered <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='dwelt;leaf;wife;whenever;bush;food;s;mouth;isuro;time;clump' adjectives='' verbs='be;gather;run;point;heal;burn;reach;say;hear;have;enter;call;eat' valence='5.80633333333' arousal='4.06133333333' dominance='5.607'>Gudu</entity> pointed to a clump of bushes, and said to Isuro: "Whenever I am eating, and you hear me call out that my food has burnt me, run as fast as you can and gather some of those leaves that they may heal my mouth."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='188'>The rabbit would have liked to ask him why he ate food that he knew would burn him, only he was afraid, and just nodded in reply; but when they had gone on a little further, he said to <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='food;reply;rabbit' adjectives='further;little;afraid' verbs='be;like;nod;burn;go;say;know;have;ask;eat' valence='5.89894736842' arousal='4.08578947368' dominance='5.70263157895'>Gudu</entity>:</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='189'>"I have dropped my needle; wait here a moment while I go and fetch it."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='190'>"Be quick then," answered Gudu, climbing into a tree.  And the rabbit hastened back to the bushes, and gathered a quantity of the leaves, which he hid among his fur, "For," thought he, "if I get them now I shall save myself the trouble of a walk by-and-by."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='191'>When he had plucked as many as he wanted he returned to <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='' adjectives='many' verbs='go;return;pluck;have;want' valence='5.606' arousal='4.224' dominance='5.576'>Gudu</entity>, and they went on together.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='192'>The sun was almost setting by the time they reached their journey"s end and being very tired they gladly sat down by a well.  Then Gudu"s betrothed, who had been watching for him, brought out a pitcher of water--which she poured over them to wash off the dust of the road--and two portions of food.  But once again the rabbit"s hopes were dashed to the ground, for <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='s;hope;rabbit;ground' adjectives='' verbs='dash;be;say' valence='6.01571428571' arousal='4.11' dominance='5.92428571429'>Gudu</entity> said hastily:</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='193'>"The custom of the village forbids you to eat till I have finished." And Isuro did not know that Gudu was lying, and that he only wanted more food.  So he saw hungrily looking on, waiting till his friend had had enough.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='194'>In a little while Gudu screamed loudly: "I am burnt!  I am burnt!" though he was not burnt at all.  Now, though Isuro had the leaves about him, he did not dare to produce them at the last moment lest the baboon should guess why he had stayed behind.  So he just went round a corner for a short time, and then came hopping back in a great hurry.  But, quick though he was, <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='nothing;water;drop' adjectives='quick;quicker' verbs='be;remain;have' valence='5.88714285714' arousal='3.87428571429' dominance='5.77428571429'>Gudu</entity> had been quicker still, and nothing remained but some drops of water.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='195'>"How unlucky you are," said Gudu, snatching the leaves; "no sooner had you gone than ever so many people arrived, and washed their hands, as you see, and ate your portion."  But, though <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='nothing;life;bed' adjectives='better;hungrier' verbs='be;say;know;have;go;believe' valence='6.4975' arousal='3.925' dominance='6.04875'>Isuro</entity> knew better than to believe him, he said nothing, and went to bed hungrier than he had ever been in his life.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='196'>Early next morning they started for another village, and passed on <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='monkey;nut;people;garden;village' adjectives='large;busy' verbs='start;be;gather;pass' valence='5.90714285714' arousal='4.165' dominance='5.36'>the way</entity> a large garden where people were very busy gathering monkey- nuts.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='197'>"You can have a good breakfast at last," said Gudu, pointing to a heap of empty shells; never doubting but that Isuro would meekly take the portion shown him, and leave the real nuts for himself.  But what was his surprise when <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='surprise' adjectives='' verbs='answer;be' valence='6.57333333333' arousal='4.66666666667' dominance='5.54'>Isuro</entity> answered:</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='198'>"Thank you; I think I should prefer these."  And, turning to the kernels, never stopped as long as there was one left.  And the worst of it was that, with so many people about, <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='nut;people' adjectives='many;worst' verbs='be;take' valence='5.535' arousal='3.99' dominance='5.0725'>Gudu</entity> could not take the nuts from him.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='199'>It was night when they reached <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='porridge;s;meat;mother' adjectives='millet' verbs='be;betroth;reach;lay;dwell' valence='5.967' arousal='3.795' dominance='5.487'>the village</entity> where dwelt the mother of <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='porridge;s;meat;mother' adjectives='millet' verbs='be;betroth;reach;lay;dwell' valence='5.967' arousal='3.795' dominance='5.487'>Gudu</entity>"s betrothed, who laid meat and millet porridge before them.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='200'>"I think you told me you were fond of porridge," said Gudu; but Isuro answered: "You are mistaking me for somebody else, as I always eat meat when I can get it."  And again <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='porridge' adjectives='content' verbs='be;force;hate' valence='5.03166666667' arousal='4.16166666667' dominance='5.02166666667'>Gudu</entity> was forced to be content with the porridge, which he hated.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='201'>While he was eating it, however a sudden thought darted into his mind, and he managed to knock over a great pot of water which was hanging in front of <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='thought;water;pot;mind;front' adjectives='great;sudden' verbs='be;knock;manage;hang;dart;put;eat' valence='5.665625' arousal='4.275625' dominance='5.686875'>the fire</entity>, and put it quite out.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='202'>"Now," said the cunning creature to himself, "I shall be able in the dark to steal his meat!"  But the rabbit had grown as cunning as he, and standing in a corner hid the meat behind him, so that the baboon could not find it.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='3' num='203'>"O Gudu!" he cried, laughing aloud, "it is you who have taught me to be clever."  And calling to the people of <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='hut;friend;people' adjectives='' verbs='kindle;bid;call;sleep;pass' valence='5.99083333333' arousal='3.9525' dominance='5.57083333333'>the house</entity>, he bade them kindle <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='hut;friend;people' adjectives='' verbs='kindle;bid;call;sleep;pass' valence='5.99083333333' arousal='3.9525' dominance='5.57083333333'>the fire</entity>, for <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='hut;friend;people' adjectives='' verbs='kindle;bid;call;sleep;pass' valence='5.99083333333' arousal='3.9525' dominance='5.57083333333'>Gudu</entity> would sleep by it, but that he would pass the night with some friends in another hut.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='3' num='204'>It was still quite dark when Isuro heard his name called very softly, and, on opening his eyes, beheld Gudu standing by him.  Laying his finger on his nose, in token of silence, he signed to <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='distance;finger;silence;nose' adjectives='token' verbs='be;get;sign;lay;follow;speak' valence='5.52307692308' arousal='3.53153846154' dominance='5.42230769231'>Isuro</entity> to get up and follow him, and it was not until they were some distance from <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='distance;finger;silence;nose' adjectives='token' verbs='be;get;sign;lay;follow;speak' valence='5.52307692308' arousal='3.53153846154' dominance='5.42230769231'>the hut</entity> that <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='distance;finger;silence;nose' adjectives='token' verbs='be;get;sign;lay;follow;speak' valence='5.52307692308' arousal='3.53153846154' dominance='5.42230769231'>Gudu</entity> spoke.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='4' num='205'>"I am hungry and want something to eat better than that nasty porridge that I had for supper.  So I am going to kill one of those goats, and as you are a good cook you must boil the flesh for me."  The rabbit nodded, and Gudu disappeared behind a rock, but soon returned dragging the dead goat with him.  The two then set about skinning it, after which they stuffed the skin with dried leaves, so that no one would have guessed it was not alive, and set it up in the middle of a lump of bushes, which kept it firm on its feet.  While he was doing this, <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='water;meat;fire;pot;hut;stick;branch;ground' adjectives='' verbs='be;plant;do;hang;collect;kindle;hasten;steal;fill' valence='5.39782608696' arousal='4.01652173913' dominance='5.37869565217'>Isuro</entity> collected sticks for a fire, and when it was kindled, <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='water;meat;fire;pot;hut;stick;branch;ground' adjectives='' verbs='be;plant;do;hang;collect;kindle;hasten;steal;fill' valence='5.39782608696' arousal='4.01652173913' dominance='5.37869565217'>Gudu</entity> hastened to another hut to steal a pot which he filled with water from <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='water;meat;fire;pot;hut;stick;branch;ground' adjectives='' verbs='be;plant;do;hang;collect;kindle;hasten;steal;fill' valence='5.39782608696' arousal='4.01652173913' dominance='5.37869565217'>the river</entity>, and, planting two branches in the ground, they hung the pot with the meat in it over <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='water;meat;fire;pot;hut;stick;branch;ground' adjectives='' verbs='be;plant;do;hang;collect;kindle;hasten;steal;fill' valence='5.39782608696' arousal='4.01652173913' dominance='5.37869565217'>the fire</entity>.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='206'>"It will not be fit to eat for two hours at least," said Gudu, "so we can both have a nap."  And he stretched himself out on the ground, and pretended to fall fast asleep, but, in reality, he was only waiting till it was safe to take all the meat for himself.  "Surely I hear him snore," he thought; and he stole to the place where <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='eye;s;wood;pile;rabbit;place' adjectives='wide;open' verbs='be;snore;lie;hear;steal;think' valence='5.25176470588' arousal='4.09117647059' dominance='5.48'>Isuro</entity> was lying on a pile of wood, but the rabbit"s eyes were wide open.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='207'>"How tiresome," muttered Gudu, as he went back to his place; and after waiting a little longer he got up, and peeped again, but still the rabbit"s pink eyes stared widely.  If Gudu had only known, Isuro was asleep all the time; but this he never guessed, and by-and- bye he grew so tired with watching that he went to sleep himself.  Soon after, Isuro woke up, and he too felt hungry, so he crept softly to the pot and ate all the meat, while he tied the bones together and hung them in Gudu"s fur.  After that he went back to the wood-pile and slept again.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='208'>In the morning the mother of Gudu"s betrothed came out to milk her goats, and on going to the bushes where the largest one seemed entangled, she found out the trick.  She made such lament that the people of the village came running, and Gudu and Isuro jumped up also, and pretended to be as surprised and interested as the rest.  But they must have looked guilty after all, for suddenly an old man pointed to them, and cried:</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='209'>"Those are thieves."  And at the sound of his voice the big <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='sound;voice' adjectives='big' verbs='tremble' valence='5.4425' arousal='4.26' dominance='5.28'>Gudu</entity> trembled all over.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='210'>"How dare you say such things?  I defy you to prove it," answered Isuro boldly.  And he danced forward, and turned head over heels, and shook himself before them all.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='211'>"I spoke hastily; you are innocent," said the old man; "but now let the baboon do likewise."  And when Gudu began to jump the goat"s bones rattled and the people cried: "It is Gudu who is the goat-slayer!"  But <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='' verbs='answer' valence='6.1' arousal='4.0' dominance='5.95'>Gudu</entity> answered:</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='212'>"Nay, I did not kill your goat; it was Isuro, and he ate the meat, and hung the bones round my neck.  So it is he who should die!"  And the people looked at each other, for they knew not what to believe.  At length one man said:</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='213'>"Let them both die, but they may choose their own deaths."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='214'>Then <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='' verbs='answer' valence='6.1' arousal='4.0' dominance='5.95'>Isuro</entity> answered:</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='215'>"If we must die, put us in the place where <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='fire;slayer;place;goat;heap' adjectives='other' verbs='be;cut;die;burn;set;escape;put;round' valence='5.20541666667' arousal='3.96375' dominance='5.315'>the wood</entity> is cut, and heap it up all round us, so that we cannot escape, and set fire to <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='fire;slayer;place;goat;heap' adjectives='other' verbs='be;cut;die;burn;set;escape;put;round' valence='5.20541666667' arousal='3.96375' dominance='5.315'>the wood</entity>; and if one is burned and the other is not, then he that is burned is the goat- slayer."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='4' num='216'>And the people did as Isuro had said.  But <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='wood-pile;hole' adjectives='' verbs='be;run;know;die;kindle' valence='5.12' arousal='4.47' dominance='4.62625'>Isuro</entity> knew of a hole under the wood-pile, and when <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='wood-pile;hole' adjectives='' verbs='be;run;know;die;kindle' valence='5.12' arousal='4.47' dominance='4.62625'>the fire</entity> was kindled he ran into <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='wood-pile;hole' adjectives='' verbs='be;run;know;die;kindle' valence='5.12' arousal='4.47' dominance='4.62625'>the hole</entity>, but <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='wood-pile;hole' adjectives='' verbs='be;run;know;die;kindle' valence='5.12' arousal='4.47' dominance='4.62625'>Gudu</entity> died there.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='3' num='217'>When <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='hole;ash;people' adjectives='' verbs='be;burn;leave;say;have;come' valence='5.43' arousal='4.00416666667' dominance='5.39083333333'>the fire</entity> had burned itself out and only ashes were left where <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='hole;ash;people' adjectives='' verbs='be;burn;leave;say;have;come' valence='5.43' arousal='4.00416666667' dominance='5.39083333333'>the wood</entity> had been, <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='hole;ash;people' adjectives='' verbs='be;burn;leave;say;have;come' valence='5.43' arousal='4.00416666667' dominance='5.39083333333'>Isuro</entity> came out of his hole, and said to the people:</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='218'>"Lo! did I not speak well?  He who killed your goat is among those ashes."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='219'>[Mashona Story.]</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='220'></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='221'></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='222'><entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='soldier;s;son' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='5.78666666667' arousal='5.11' dominance='5.28'>Ian</entity>, the Soldier"s Son</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='223'></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='224'>There dwelt a knight in Grianaig of the land of the West, who had three daughters, and for goodness and beauty they had not their like in all the isles.  All the people loved them, and loud was the weeping when one day, as the three maidens sat on the rocks on the edge of the sea, dipping their feet in the water, there arose a great beast from under the waves and swept them away beneath the ocean.  And none knew whither they had gone, or how to seek them.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='225'>Now there lived in a town a few miles off a soldier who had three sons, fine youths and strong, and the best players at shinny in that country.  At Christmastide that year, when families met together and great feasts were held, <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='feast;christmastide;family;brother' adjectives='youngest;great' verbs='meet;say;hold;be' valence='6.391' arousal='4.137' dominance='5.95'>Ian</entity>, the youngest of the three brothers, said:</paragraph>
