<document name='fairytales-corpus-data/RedFairyBook.txt'>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='0'>THE RED FAIRY BOOK</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='1'>By Various</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='2'>Edited by <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='' verbs='edit' valence='4.95' arousal='4.1' dominance='6.64'>Andrew Lang</entity></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='3'>TO</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='4'>MASTER <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='miles;master' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='5.72' arousal='4.4' dominance='4.17'>BILLY TREMAYNE</entity> MILES</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='5'>A PROFOUND STUDENT</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='6'>YET</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='7'>AN AMIABLE CRITIC</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='8'></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='9'>PREFACE</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='10'>IN a second gleaning of the fields of Fairy Land we cannot expect to find a second Perrault. But there are good stories enough left, and it is hoped that some in the Red Fairy Book may have the attraction of being less familiar than many of the old friends. The tales have been translated, or, in the case of those from Madame d"Aulnoy"s long stories, adapted, by Mrs. Hunt from the Norse, by Miss Minnie Wright from Madame d"Aulnoy, by Mrs. Lang and Miss Bruce from other French sources, by Miss May Sellar, Miss Farquharson, and Miss Blackley from the German, while the story of "Sigurd" is condensed by the Editor from Mr. William Morris"s prose version of the "Volsunga Saga." The Editor has to thank his friend, <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='golden;hood;regard;sillies;permission;la;pied;piper;drakestail;version;editor;privilege;tradition;friend' adjectives='little;same' verbs='reproduce;thank;have' valence='5.93' arousal='3.85285714286' dominance='5.79'>M. Charles Marelles</entity>, for permission to reproduce his versions of the "Pied Piper," of "Drakestail," and of "Little Golden Hood" from the French, and <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='golden;hood;regard;sillies;permission;la;pied;piper;drakestail;version;editor;privilege;tradition;friend' adjectives='little;same' verbs='reproduce;thank;have' valence='5.93' arousal='3.85285714286' dominance='5.79'>M. Henri Carnoy</entity> for the same privilege in regard to "The Six Sillies" from La Tradition.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='4' num='11'><entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='publication;s;elder;beanstalk;version;mr.' adjectives='old' verbs='copy;have;permit' valence='5.44538461538' arousal='3.68923076923' dominance='5.05076923077'>Lady Frances Balfour</entity> has kindly copied an old version of "<entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='publication;s;elder;beanstalk;version;mr.' adjectives='old' verbs='copy;have;permit' valence='5.44538461538' arousal='3.68923076923' dominance='5.05076923077'>Jack</entity> and the Beanstalk," and <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='publication;s;elder;beanstalk;version;mr.' adjectives='old' verbs='copy;have;permit' valence='5.44538461538' arousal='3.68923076923' dominance='5.05076923077'>Messrs. Smith</entity> and Elder have permitted the publication of two of Mr. <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='publication;s;elder;beanstalk;version;mr.' adjectives='old' verbs='copy;have;permit' valence='5.44538461538' arousal='3.68923076923' dominance='5.05076923077'>Ralston</entity>"s versions from the Russian.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='12'>A. L.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='13'></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='14'>CONTENTS</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='15'></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='16'>The Twelve Dancing Princesses</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='17'>The <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='7.64' arousal='5.42' dominance='5.74'>Princess Mayblossom</entity></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='18'><entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='6.42' arousal='4.72' dominance='6.35'>Soria Moria Castle</entity></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='19'>The Death of <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='death' adjectives='deathless' verbs='' valence='1.89' arousal='5.53' dominance='3.42'>Koschei</entity> the Deathless</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='20'>The Black Thief and <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='thief' adjectives='black' verbs='' valence='3.86' arousal='4.815' dominance='4.31'>Knight</entity> of the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='thief' adjectives='black' verbs='' valence='3.86' arousal='4.815' dominance='4.31'>Glen</entity></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='21'>The Master Thief</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='22'>Brother and Sister</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='23'><entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='7.64' arousal='5.42' dominance='5.74'>Princess Rosette</entity></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='24'>The Enchanted Pig</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='25'>The Norka</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='26'>The Wonderful Birch</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='27'><entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='5.0' arousal='5.0' dominance='5.0'>Jack</entity> and the <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='5.0' arousal='5.0' dominance='5.0'>Beanstalk</entity></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='28'>The Little Good Mouse</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='29'><entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='5.0' arousal='5.0' dominance='5.0'>Graciosa</entity> and <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='5.0' arousal='5.0' dominance='5.0'>Percinet</entity></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='30'>The Three Princesses of <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='princess' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='6.535' arousal='4.4' dominance='5.595'>Whiteland</entity></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='31'>The Voice of Death</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='32'>The Six Sillies</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='33'><entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='5.0' arousal='5.0' dominance='5.0'>Kari Woodengown</entity></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='34'>Drakestail</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='35'>The Ratcatcher</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='36'>The True History of Little Goldenhood</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='37'>The Golden Branch</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='38'>The Three Dwarfs</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='39'><entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='5.0' arousal='5.0' dominance='5.0'>Dapplegrim</entity></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='40'>The Enchanted Canary</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='41'>The Twelve Brothers</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='42'>Rapunzel</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='43'>The Nettle Spinner</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='44'>Farmer Weatherbeard</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='45'><entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='7.53' arousal='4.73' dominance='6.11'>Mother Holle</entity></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='46'><entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='5.0' arousal='5.0' dominance='5.0'>Minnikin</entity></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='47'>Bushy Bride</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='48'><entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='5.0' arousal='5.0' dominance='5.0'>Snowdrop</entity></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='49'>The Golden Goose</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='50'>The Seven Foals</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='51'>The Marvellous Musician</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='52'>The Story of <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='story' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='7.27' arousal='3.52' dominance='5.33'>Sigurd</entity></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='53'></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='54'></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='55'>THE TWELVE DANCING PRINCESSES</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='56'>I</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='57'>ONCE upon a time there lived in the village of Montignies-sur-Roc a little cow-boy, without either father or mother. His real name was <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='head;name;cow;air;common;nothing;pasture' adjectives='real;gaping' verbs='go;be;seek;call;drive' valence='6.15933333333' arousal='3.85' dominance='5.57733333333'>Michael</entity>, but he was always called the Star Gazer, because when he drove his cows over the commons to seek for pasture, he went along with his head in the air, gaping at nothing.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='58'>As he had a white skin, blue eyes, and hair that curled all over his head, the village girls used to cry after him, "Well, Star Gazer, what are you doing?" and <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='nothing;way' adjectives='' verbs='answer;go;look;turn' valence='5.94' arousal='3.80166666667' dominance='5.635'>Michael</entity> would answer, "Oh, nothing," and go on his way without even turning to look at them.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='59'>The fact was he thought them very ugly, with their sun-burnt necks, their great red hands, their coarse petticoats and their wooden shoes. He had heard that somewhere in the world there were girls whose necks were white and whose hands were small, who were always dressed in the finest silks and laces, and were called princesses, and while his companions round <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='lace;hand;flame;companion;nothing;world;girl;silk;princess;happiness;neck' adjectives='small;white;finest;common;everyday' verbs='be;dream;marry;fancy;see;hear;have;call;dress;round' valence='6.29875' arousal='4.195625' dominance='5.6290625'>the fire</entity> saw nothing in the flames but common everyday fancies, he dreamed that he had the happiness to marry a princess.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='60'>II</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='61'>One morning about the middle of August, just at mid-day when the sun was hottest, Michael ate his dinner of a piece of dry bread, and went to sleep under an oak. And while he slept he dreamt that there appeared before him a beautiful lady, dressed in a robe of cloth of gold, who said to him: "Go to <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='cloth;robe;lady;princess;gold' adjectives='beautiful' verbs='appear;dress;marry;say;sleep;go;dream' valence='6.33833333333' arousal='4.51111111111' dominance='5.69444444444'>the castle</entity> of <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='cloth;robe;lady;princess;gold' adjectives='beautiful' verbs='appear;dress;marry;say;sleep;go;dream' valence='6.33833333333' arousal='4.51111111111' dominance='5.69444444444'>Beloeil</entity>, and there you shall marry a princess."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='62'>That evening the little cow-boy, who had been thinking a great deal about the advice of the lady in the golden dress, told his dream to the farm people. But, as was natural, they only laughed at the Star Gazer.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='3' num='63'>The next day at the same hour he went to sleep again under the same tree. <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='princess;time' adjectives='' verbs='go;say;marry;appear' valence='6.01916666667' arousal='4.3875' dominance='5.56666666667'>The lady</entity> appeared to him a second time, and said: "Go to <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='princess;time' adjectives='' verbs='go;say;marry;appear' valence='6.01916666667' arousal='4.3875' dominance='5.56666666667'>the castle</entity> of <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='princess;time' adjectives='' verbs='go;say;marry;appear' valence='6.01916666667' arousal='4.3875' dominance='5.56666666667'>Beloeil</entity>, and you shall marry a princess."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='64'>In the evening Michael told his friends that he had dreamed the same dream again, but they only laughed at him more than before. "Never mind," he thought to himself; "if <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='time' adjectives='' verbs='do;tell;mind;think;appear' valence='5.55538461538' arousal='4.07538461538' dominance='5.48769230769'>the lady</entity> appears to me a third time, I will do as she tells me."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='65'>The following day, to the great astonishment of all <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='voice;singing;astonishment;o;clock' adjectives='great' verbs='be;hear' valence='6.05166666667' arousal='3.78166666667' dominance='5.59'>the village</entity>, about two o"clock in the afternoon a voice was heard singing:</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='66'>"Raleo, raleo, How the cattle go!"</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='67'>It was the little cow-boy driving his herd back to the byre.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='68'><entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='good-bye;fortune;friend;bundle;clothes' adjectives='' verbs='be;begin;set;make;scold;go;say;answer;seek' valence='5.833125' arousal='4.050625' dominance='5.74'>The farmer</entity> began to scold him furiously, but he answered quietly, "I am going away," made his clothes into a bundle, said good-bye to all his friends, and boldly set out to seek his fortunes.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='69'>There was great excitement through all <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='star;stick;people;top;bundle;excitement;gazer;laughing;end;side;hill' adjectives='great' verbs='be;hold;watch;stand;trudge' valence='5.9525' arousal='3.89625' dominance='5.80625'>the village</entity>, and on the top of the hill the people stood holding their sides with laughing, as they watched the Star Gazer trudging bravely along <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='star;stick;people;top;bundle;excitement;gazer;laughing;end;side;hill' adjectives='great' verbs='be;hold;watch;stand;trudge' valence='5.9525' arousal='3.89625' dominance='5.80625'>the valley</entity> with his bundle at the end of his stick.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='70'>It was enough to make anyone laugh, certainly.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='71'>III</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='72'>It was well known for full twenty miles round that there lived in <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='beauty;presence;bed;princess;mile;blood;mattress;pea' adjectives='beautiful;full;proud;royal;sensitive;wonderful;such' verbs='be;feel;live;know;have;round;lay' valence='6.206' arousal='3.95866666667' dominance='5.75133333333'>the castle</entity> of <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='beauty;presence;bed;princess;mile;blood;mattress;pea' adjectives='beautiful;full;proud;royal;sensitive;wonderful;such' verbs='be;feel;live;know;have;round;lay' valence='6.206' arousal='3.95866666667' dominance='5.75133333333'>Beloeil</entity> twelve princesses of wonderful beauty, and as proud as they were beautiful, and who were besides so very sensitive and of such truly royal blood, that they would have felt at once the presence of a pea in their beds, even if the mattresses had been laid over it.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='73'>It was whispered about that they led exactly the lives that princesses ought to lead, sleeping far into the morning, and never getting up till mid-day. They had twelve beds all in the same room, but what was very extraordinary was the fact that though they were locked in by triple bolts, every morning their satin shoes were found worn into holes.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='74'>When they were asked what they had been doing all night, they always answered that they had been asleep; and, indeed, no noise was ever heard in <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='noise;shoe' adjectives='' verbs='be;do;answer;hear;wear;have;ask' valence='5.80941176471' arousal='3.57941176471' dominance='5.65176470588'>the room</entity>, yet the shoes could not wear themselves out alone!</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='75'>At last the Duke of <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='duke;daughter;wife;proclamation;shoe;trumpet' adjectives='last' verbs='sound;be;make;discover;wear;order;choose' valence='6.075' arousal='3.97625' dominance='5.844375'>Beloeil</entity> ordered the trumpet to be sounded, and a proclamation to be made that whoever could discover how his daughters wore out their shoes should choose one of them for his wife.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='76'>On hearing the proclamation a number of princes arrived at the castle to try their luck. They watched all night behind the open door of the princesses, but when the morning came they had all disappeared, and no one could tell what had become of them.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='77'>IV</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='78'>When he reached the castle, Michael went straight to the gardener and offered his services. Now it happened that <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='boy;curl;princess;gardener;face' adjectives='golden;pretty;sturdy' verbs='be;look;do;please;send;think;take;have;happen;agree' valence='6.4025' arousal='3.985' dominance='5.9545'>the garden</entity> boy had just been sent away, and though the Star Gazer did not look very sturdy, the gardener agreed to take him, as he thought that his pretty face and golden curls would please the princesses.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='79'>The first thing he was told was that when the princesses got up he was to present each one with a bouquet, and <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='bouquet;thing;nothing;princess' adjectives='unpleasant;more' verbs='do;be;get;tell;have;think' valence='5.98117647059' arousal='3.94941176471' dominance='5.58823529412'>Michael</entity> thought that if he had nothing more unpleasant to do than that he should get on very well.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='80'>Accordingly he placed himself behind the door of the princesses" room, with the twelve bouquets in a basket. He gave one to each of the sisters, and they took them without even deigning to look at the lad, except Lina the youngest, who fixed her large black eyes as soft as velvet on him, and exclaimed, "Oh, how pretty he is--our new flower boy!" The rest all burst out laughing, and the eldest pointed out that a princess ought never to lower herself by looking at a garden boy.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='81'>Now Michael knew quite well what had happened to all the princes, but notwithstanding, the beautiful eyes of the Princess Lina inspired him with a violent longing to try his fate. Unhappily he did not dare to come forward, being afraid that he should only be jeered at, or even turned away from <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='account;impudence' adjectives='afraid' verbs='do;be;jeer;turn;come;dare' valence='5.244' arousal='4.073' dominance='5.205'>the castle</entity> on account of his impudence.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='82'>V</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='83'>Nevertheless, the Star Gazer had another dream. The lady in the golden dress appeared to him once more, holding in one hand two young laurel trees, a cherry laurel and a rose laurel, and in the other hand a little golden rake, a little golden bucket, and a silken towel. She thus addressed him:</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='84'>"Plant these two laurels in two large pots, rake them over with the rake, water them with the bucket, and wipe them with the towel. When they have grown as tall as a girl of fifteen, say to each of them, ""My beautiful laurel, with the golden rake I have raked you, with the golden bucket I have watered you, with the silken towel I have wiped you."" Then after that ask anything you choose, and the laurels will give it to you."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='85'>Michael thanked the lady in the golden dress, and when he woke he found the two laurel bushes beside him. So he carefully obeyed the orders he had been given by <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='order' adjectives='' verbs='be;obey;have;give' valence='6.27166666667' arousal='3.81' dominance='5.63333333333'>the lady</entity>.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='86'>The trees grew very fast, and when they were as tall as a girl of fifteen he said to the cherry laurel, "My lovely cherry laurel, with the golden rake I have raked thee, with the golden bucket I have watered thee, with the silken towel I have wiped thee. Teach me how to become invisible." Then there instantly appeared on the laurel a pretty white flower, which <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='laurel;flower;button-hole' adjectives='white' verbs='gather;appear;stick' valence='6.06' arousal='4.03857142857' dominance='5.88285714286'>Michael</entity> gathered and stuck into his button-hole.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='87'>VI</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='88'>That evening, when the princesses went upstairs to bed, he followed them barefoot, so that he might make no noise, and hid himself under one of the twelve beds, so as not to take up much room.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='89'>The princesses began at once to open their wardrobes and boxes. They took out of them the most magnificent dresses, which they put on before their mirrors, and when they had finished, turned themselves all round to admire their appearances.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='90'>Michael could see nothing from his hiding-place, but he could hear everything, and he listened to the princesses laughing and jumping with pleasure. At last the eldest said, "Be quick, my sisters, our partners will be impatient." At the end of an hour, when the Star Gazer heard no more noise, he peeped out and saw the twelve sisters in splendid garments, with their satin shoes on their feet, and in their hands the bouquets he had brought them.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='91'>"Are you ready?" asked the eldest.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='92'>"Yes," replied the other eleven in chorus, and they took their places one by one behind her.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='93'>Then the eldest Princess clapped her hands three times and a trap door opened. All the princesses disappeared down a secret staircase, and <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='princess;staircase' adjectives='secret' verbs='follow;disappear' valence='5.34833333333' arousal='4.32833333333' dominance='5.33666666667'>Michael</entity> hastily followed them.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='94'>As he was following on <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='dress' adjectives='' verbs='be;tread;follow' valence='5.78833333333' arousal='4.01666666667' dominance='5.69333333333'>the steps</entity> of the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='dress' adjectives='' verbs='be;tread;follow' valence='5.78833333333' arousal='4.01666666667' dominance='5.69333333333'>Princess Lina</entity>, he carelessly trod on her dress.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='95'>"There is somebody behind me," cried the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='dress;somebody' adjectives='' verbs='be;hold;cry' valence='5.81285714286' arousal='4.61714285714' dominance='5.23'>Princess</entity>; "they are holding my dress."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='96'>"You foolish thing," said her eldest sister, "you are always afraid of something. It is only a nail which caught you."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='97'>VII</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='98'>They went down, down, down, till at last they came to a passage with a door at one end, which was only fastened with a latch. The eldest <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='leaf;light;drop;moon;wood;silver' adjectives='brilliant;little;lovely;eldest' verbs='shine;be;open;find;spangle' valence='6.45866666667' arousal='4.21733333333' dominance='5.94066666667'>Princess</entity> opened it, and they found themselves immediately in a lovely little wood, where the leaves were spangled with drops of silver which shone in the brilliant light of the moon.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='99'>They next crossed another wood where the leaves were sprinkled with gold, and after that another still, where the leaves glittered with diamonds.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='100'>At last the Star Gazer perceived a large lake, and on <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='star;lake;princess;gazer;oar;awning;prince;boat' adjectives='large;little;last' verbs='grasp;be;await;perceive;seat' valence='5.96777777778' arousal='3.90166666667' dominance='5.53444444444'>the shores</entity> of <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='star;lake;princess;gazer;oar;awning;prince;boat' adjectives='large;little;last' verbs='grasp;be;await;perceive;seat' valence='5.96777777778' arousal='3.90166666667' dominance='5.53444444444'>the lake</entity> twelve little boats with awnings, in which were seated twelve princes, who, grasping their oars, awaited the princesses.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='101'>Each princess entered one of the boats, and Michael slipped into that which held the youngest. The boats glided along rapidly, but Lina"s, from being heavier, was always behind the rest. "We never went so slowly before," said the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='reason' adjectives='' verbs='go;be;say' valence='6.455' arousal='4.10166666667' dominance='6.0'>Princess</entity>; "what can be the reason?"</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='102'>"I don"t know," answered the Prince. "I assure you I am rowing as hard as I can."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='103'>On the other side of <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='boy;kettle-drum;whence;fiddle;music;castle;side' adjectives='beautiful;other;lively' verbs='come;see;illuminate;trumpet' valence='6.14866666667' arousal='4.39266666667' dominance='5.84666666667'>the lake the garden</entity> boy saw a beautiful castle splendidly illuminated, whence came the lively music of fiddles, kettle-drums, and trumpets.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='104'>In a moment they touched land, and the company jumped out of the boats; and the princes, after having securely fastened their barques, gave their arms to the princesses and conducted them to <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='princess;land;barque;company;arm;moment;prince;boat' adjectives='' verbs='give;jump;have;conduct;touch;fasten' valence='6.144' arousal='4.26266666667' dominance='5.77933333333'>the castle</entity>.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='105'>VIII</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='106'>Michael followed, and entered the ball-room in their train. Everywhere were mirrors, lights, flowers, and damask hangings.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='107'>The Star Gazer was quite bewildered at the magnificence of the sight.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='108'>He placed himself out of the way in a corner, admiring the grace and beauty of the princesses. Their loveliness was of every kind. Some were fair and some were dark; some had chestnut hair, or curls darker still, and some had golden locks. Never were so many beautiful princesses seen together at one time, but the one whom the cow-boy thought the most beautiful and the most fascinating was the little <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='eye;velvet;princess;time' adjectives='beautiful;many;little;fascinating;cow-boy' verbs='be;see;think' valence='6.65466666667' arousal='4.19866666667' dominance='5.716'>Princess</entity> with the velvet eyes.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='109'>With what eagerness she danced! leaning on her partner"s shoulder she swept by like a whirlwind. Her cheeks flushed, her eyes sparkled, and it was plain that she loved dancing better than anything else.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='110'>The poor boy envied those handsome young men with whom she danced so gracefully, but he did not know how little reason he had to be jealous of them.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='111'>The young men were really the princes who, to the number of fifty at least, had tried to steal the princesses" secret. The princesses had made them drink something of a philtre, which froze the heart and left nothing but the love of dancing.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='112'>IX</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='113'>They danced on till the shoes of the princesses were worn into holes. When the cock crowed the third time the fiddles stopped, and a delicious supper was served by negro boys, consisting of sugared orange flowers, crystallised rose leaves, powdered violets, cracknels, wafers, and other dishes, which are, as everyone knows, the favourite food of princesses.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='114'>After supper, the dancers all went back to their boats, and this time the Star Gazer entered that of the eldest Princess. They crossed again the wood with the diamond-spangled leaves, the wood with gold-sprinkled leaves, and the wood whose leaves glittered with drops of silver, and as a proof of what he had seen, the boy broke a small branch from a tree in the last wood. <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='noise;breaking;branch' adjectives='' verbs='turn;make;hear' valence='5.346' arousal='3.838' dominance='5.838'>Lina</entity> turned as she heard the noise made by the breaking of the branch.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='115'>"What was that noise?" she said.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='116'>"It was nothing," replied her eldest sister; "it was only the screech of the barn-owl that roosts in one of the turrets of <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='nothing;turret;sister;screech;barn-owl' adjectives='eldest' verbs='be;roost;reply' valence='5.69222222222' arousal='4.02555555556' dominance='5.74333333333'>the castle</entity>."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='3' num='117'>While she was speaking Michael managed to slip in front, and running up the staircase, he reached the princesses" room first. He flung open <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='sun;work;vine;time' adjectives='open' verbs='be;begin;set;fling;rise;slide;climb;find' valence='6.00294117647' arousal='3.72764705882' dominance='5.62294117647'>the window</entity>, and sliding down the vine which climbed up <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='sun;work;vine;time' adjectives='open' verbs='be;begin;set;fling;rise;slide;climb;find' valence='6.00294117647' arousal='3.72764705882' dominance='5.62294117647'>the wall</entity>, found himself in <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='sun;work;vine;time' adjectives='open' verbs='be;begin;set;fling;rise;slide;climb;find' valence='6.00294117647' arousal='3.72764705882' dominance='5.62294117647'>the garden</entity> just as the sun was beginning to rise, and it was time for him to set to his work.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='118'>X</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='119'>That day, when he made up the bouquets, <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='bouquet;nosegay;silver;branch' adjectives='youngest' verbs='intend;make;drop;hide' valence='6.03' arousal='3.81' dominance='5.68'>Michael</entity> hid the branch with the silver drops in the nosegay intended for the youngest <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='bouquet;nosegay;silver;branch' adjectives='youngest' verbs='intend;make;drop;hide' valence='6.03' arousal='3.81' dominance='5.68'>Princess</entity>.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='120'>When Lina discovered it she was much surprised. However, she said nothing to her sisters, but as she met <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='sister;accident;way;elm;mind;shade;nothing' adjectives='' verbs='be;stop;walk;say;go;meet;alter;speak' valence='5.78066666667' arousal='3.932' dominance='5.50933333333'>the boy</entity> by accident while she was walking under the shade of the elms, she suddenly stopped as if to speak to him; then, altering her mind, went on her way.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='121'>The same evening the twelve sisters went again to the ball, and the Star Gazer again followed them and crossed the lake in Lina"s boat. This time it was the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='boat;time' adjectives='heavy' verbs='be;seem;complain' valence='5.27285714286' arousal='4.01571428571' dominance='4.72571428571'>Prince</entity> who complained that the boat seemed very heavy.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='122'>"It is the heat," replied the Princess. "I, too, have been feeling very warm."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='123'>During the ball she looked everywhere for the gardener"s boy, but she never saw him.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='3' num='124'>As they came back, <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='noise;leaf;breaking;branch' adjectives='gold-spangled;eldest' verbs='hear;be;make;gather;come' valence='5.68333333333' arousal='3.83083333333' dominance='5.73166666667'>Michael</entity> gathered a branch from <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='noise;leaf;breaking;branch' adjectives='gold-spangled;eldest' verbs='hear;be;make;gather;come' valence='5.68333333333' arousal='3.83083333333' dominance='5.73166666667'>the wood</entity> with the gold-spangled leaves, and now it was the eldest <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='noise;leaf;breaking;branch' adjectives='gold-spangled;eldest' verbs='hear;be;make;gather;come' valence='5.68333333333' arousal='3.83083333333' dominance='5.73166666667'>Princess</entity> who heard the noise that it made in breaking.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='125'>"It is nothing," said <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='nothing;owl;cry;roost;turret' adjectives='' verbs='be;say' valence='5.39142857143' arousal='4.31857142857' dominance='5.40428571429'>Lina</entity>; "only the cry of the owl which roosts in the turrets of <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='nothing;owl;cry;roost;turret' adjectives='' verbs='be;say' valence='5.39142857143' arousal='4.31857142857' dominance='5.40428571429'>the castle</entity>."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='126'>XI</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='127'>As soon as she got up she found the branch in her bouquet. When the sisters went down she stayed a little behind and said to the cow-boy: "Where does this branch come from?"</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='128'>"Your Royal Highness knows well enough," answered <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='royal;highness' adjectives='' verbs='answer;know' valence='5.955' arousal='4.06' dominance='6.2'>Michael</entity>.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='129'>"So you have followed us?"</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='130'>"Yes, <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='7.64' arousal='5.42' dominance='5.74'>Princess</entity>."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='131'>"How did you manage it? we never saw you."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='132'>"I hid myself," replied the Star Gazer quietly.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='133'>The <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='moment' adjectives='silent' verbs='be;say' valence='5.995' arousal='4.25666666667' dominance='5.95166666667'>Princess</entity> was silent a moment, and then said:</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='134'>"You know our secret!--keep it. Here is the reward of your discretion." And she flung <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='purse;gold' adjectives='' verbs='fling' valence='5.95' arousal='4.724' dominance='5.616'>the boy</entity> a purse of gold.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='135'>"I do not sell my silence," answered <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='purse;silence' adjectives='' verbs='sell;do;answer;go;pick' valence='5.65875' arousal='4.00375' dominance='5.79875'>Michael</entity>, and he went away without picking up the purse.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='136'>For three nights Lina neither saw nor heard anything extraordinary; on the fourth she heard a rustling among the diamond-spangled leaves of the wood. That day there was a branch of the trees in her bouquet.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='137'>She took the Star Gazer aside, and said to him in a harsh voice:</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='138'>"You know what price my father has promised to pay for our secret?"</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='139'>"I know, <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='' verbs='answer;know' valence='6.39' arousal='4.415' dominance='5.6175'>Princess</entity>," answered <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='' verbs='answer;know' valence='6.39' arousal='4.415' dominance='5.6175'>Michael</entity>.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='140'>"Don"t you mean to tell him?"</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='141'>"That is not my intention."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='142'>"Are you afraid?"</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='143'>"No, <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='7.64' arousal='5.42' dominance='5.74'>Princess</entity>."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='144'>"What makes you so discreet, then?"</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='145'>But <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='silent' verbs='be' valence='5.66' arousal='3.32' dominance='6.045'>Michael</entity> was silent.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='146'>XII</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='147'><entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='talking;s;boy;sister;garden' adjectives='little' verbs='see;jeer;have' valence='6.16142857143' arousal='4.04285714286' dominance='5.58857142857'>Lina</entity>"s sisters had seen her talking to the little garden boy, and jeered at her for it.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='148'>"What prevents your marrying him?" asked the eldest, "you would become a gardener too; it is a charming profession. You could live in a cottage at the end of <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='cottage;water;end;bouquet;husband' adjectives='' verbs='draw;bring;live;help;get' valence='6.44083333333' arousal='3.88166666667' dominance='5.815'>the park</entity>, and help your husband to draw up water from <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='cottage;water;end;bouquet;husband' adjectives='' verbs='draw;bring;live;help;get' valence='6.44083333333' arousal='3.88166666667' dominance='5.815'>the well</entity>, and when we get up you could bring us our bouquets."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='149'>The <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='bouquet;gazer;star;manner' adjectives='angry;disdainful' verbs='receive;be;present' valence='5.847' arousal='4.622' dominance='5.53'>Princess Lina</entity> was very angry, and when the Star Gazer presented her bouquet, she received it in a disdainful manner.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='150'>Michael behaved most respectfully. He never raised his eyes to her, but nearly all day she felt him at her side without ever seeing him.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='151'>One day she made up her mind to tell everything to her eldest sister.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='152'>"What!" said she, "this rogue knows our secret, and you never told me! I must lose no time in getting rid of him."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='153'>"But how?"</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='154'>"Why, by having him taken to <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='dungeon;course' adjectives='' verbs='take;have' valence='4.86' arousal='4.2575' dominance='4.92'>the tower</entity> with the dungeons, of course."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='155'>For this was <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='people;princess;time' adjectives='beautiful;rid;much;old' verbs='be;know;get' valence='5.872' arousal='4.019' dominance='5.447'>the way</entity> that in old times beautiful princesses got rid of people who knew too much.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='156'>But the astonishing part of it was that the youngest sister did not seem at all to relish this method of stopping the mouth of the gardener"s boy, who, after all, had said nothing to their father.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='157'>XIII</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='158'>It was agreed that the question should be submitted to the other ten sisters. All were on the side of the eldest. Then the youngest sister declared that if they laid a finger on the little garden boy, she would herself go and tell their father the secret of the holes in their shoes.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='159'>At last it was decided that <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='ball;end;philtre;rest;supper;test' adjectives='last' verbs='be;give;take;decide;put;enchant' valence='6.10733333333' arousal='3.732' dominance='5.51933333333'>Michael</entity> should be put to the test; that they would take him to the ball, and at the end of supper would give him the philtre which was to enchant him like the rest.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='160'>They sent for the Star Gazer, and asked him how he had contrived to learn their secret; but still he remained silent.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='161'>Then, in commanding tones, the eldest sister gave him the order they had agreed upon.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='162'>He only answered:</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='163'>"I will obey."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='164'>He had really been present, invisible, at the council of princesses, and had heard all; but he had made up his mind to drink of the philtre, and sacrifice himself to the happiness of her he loved.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='165'>Not wishing, however, to cut a poor figure at the ball by the side of the other dancers, he went at once to the laurels, and said:</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='166'>"My lovely rose laurel, with the golden rake I have raked thee, with the golden bucket I have watered thee, with a silken towel I have dried thee. Dress me like a prince."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='167'>A beautiful pink flower appeared. <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='diamond;eye;aigrette;blossom;rose;cap;button-hole;moment;laurel;velvet' adjectives='little;black' verbs='be;gather;find;match;clothe' valence='5.98210526316' arousal='4.15473684211' dominance='5.63052631579'>Michael</entity> gathered it, and found himself in a moment clothed in velvet, which was as black as the eyes of the little <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='diamond;eye;aigrette;blossom;rose;cap;button-hole;moment;laurel;velvet' adjectives='little;black' verbs='be;gather;find;match;clothe' valence='5.98210526316' arousal='4.15473684211' dominance='5.63052631579'>Princess</entity>, with a cap to match, a diamond aigrette, and a blossom of the rose laurel in his button-hole.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='168'>Thus dressed, he presented himself that evening before the Duke of Beloeil, and obtained leave to try and discover his daughters" secret. He looked so distinguished that hardly anyone would have known who he was.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='169'>XIV</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='170'>The twelve princesses went upstairs to bed. <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='signal;door;departure' adjectives='open' verbs='follow;give;wait' valence='5.42714285714' arousal='3.89571428571' dominance='5.75'>Michael</entity> followed them, and waited behind the open door till they gave the signal for departure.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='171'>This time he did not cross in Lina"s boat. He gave his arm to the eldest sister, danced with each in turn, and was so graceful that everyone was delighted with him. At last the time came for him to dance with the little Princess. She found him the best partner in the world, but he did not dare to speak a single word to her.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='172'>When he was taking her back to her place she said to him in a mocking voice:</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='173'>"Here you are at <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='wish;prince' adjectives='' verbs='be;treat' valence='6.21111111111' arousal='4.17444444444' dominance='5.53111111111'>the summit</entity> of your wishes: you are being treated like a prince."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='174'>"Don"t be afraid," replied the Star Gazer gently. "You shall never be a gardener"s wife."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='175'>The little <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='answer;face' adjectives='little;frightened' verbs='stare;leave;wait' valence='5.214' arousal='4.66' dominance='5.304'>Princess</entity> stared at him with a frightened face, and he left her without waiting for an answer.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='176'>When the satin slippers were worn through the fiddles stopped, and the negro boys set the table. <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='sister' adjectives='youngest;opposite;eldest;next' verbs='be;place' valence='5.9525' arousal='3.56' dominance='5.6425'>Michael</entity> was placed next to the eldest sister, and opposite to the youngest.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='177'>They gave him the most exquisite dishes to eat, and the most delicate wines to drink; and in order to turn his head more completely, compliments and flattery were heaped on him from every side.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='178'>But he took care not to be intoxicated, either by the wine or the compliments.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='179'>XV</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='180'>At last the eldest sister made a sign, and one of the black pages brought in a large golden cup.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='181'>"The enchanted castle has no more secrets for you," she said to the Star Gazer. "Let us drink to your triumph."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='182'>He cast a lingering glance at the little <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='glance;hesitation;cup' adjectives='little' verbs='cast;lift;linger' valence='5.48888888889' arousal='4.04333333333' dominance='5.23222222222'>Princess</entity>, and without hesitation lifted the cup.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='183'>"Don"t drink!" suddenly cried out the little <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='gardener' adjectives='little' verbs='marry;cry' valence='5.765' arousal='4.66875' dominance='5.2325'>Princess</entity>; "I would rather marry a gardener."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='184'>And she burst into tears.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='185'>Michael flung the contents of the cup behind him, sprang over the table, and fell at Lina"s feet. The rest of the princes fell likewise at the knees of the princesses, each of whom chose a husband and raised him to her side. The charm was broken.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='3' num='186'>The twelve couples embarked in the boats, which crossed back many times in order to carry over the other princes. Then they all went through the three woods, and when they had passed <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='castle;wood;noise;passage' adjectives='enchanted;great' verbs='be;crumble;hear;have;pass;go' valence='5.81833333333' arousal='4.15666666667' dominance='5.64111111111'>the door</entity> of <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='castle;wood;noise;passage' adjectives='enchanted;great' verbs='be;crumble;hear;have;pass;go' valence='5.81833333333' arousal='4.15666666667' dominance='5.64111111111'>the underground</entity> passage a great noise was heard, as if the enchanted castle was crumbling to <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='castle;wood;noise;passage' adjectives='enchanted;great' verbs='be;crumble;hear;have;pass;go' valence='5.81833333333' arousal='4.15666666667' dominance='5.64111111111'>the earth</entity>.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='187'>They went straight to the room of the Duke of Beloeil, who had just awoke. <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='secret;cup;shoe;hole;hand' adjectives='golden' verbs='reveal;hold' valence='6.00375' arousal='3.81125' dominance='5.565'>Michael</entity> held in his hand the golden cup, and he revealed the secret of the holes in the shoes.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='188'>"Choose, then," said the Duke, "whichever you prefer."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='189'>"My choice is already made," replied <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='boy;hand;eye;choice' adjectives='youngest' verbs='be;lower;offer;make;reply;blush' valence='6.36636363636' arousal='3.88181818182' dominance='5.81363636364'>the garden</entity> boy, and he offered his hand to the youngest <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='boy;hand;eye;choice' adjectives='youngest' verbs='be;lower;offer;make;reply;blush' valence='6.36636363636' arousal='3.88181818182' dominance='5.81363636364'>Princess</entity>, who blushed and lowered her eyes.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='190'>XVI</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='3' num='191'>The <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='ceremony;star;wife;secret;gazer;s;contrary;lover;marriage;gardener' adjectives='' verbs='do;be;discover;insist;become;come;tell' valence='6.12727272727' arousal='4.51681818182' dominance='5.69681818182'>Princess Lina</entity> did not become a gardener"s wife; on the contrary, it was the Star Gazer who became a <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='ceremony;star;wife;secret;gazer;s;contrary;lover;marriage;gardener' adjectives='' verbs='do;be;discover;insist;become;come;tell' valence='6.12727272727' arousal='4.51681818182' dominance='5.69681818182'>Prince</entity>: but before the marriage ceremony the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='ceremony;star;wife;secret;gazer;s;contrary;lover;marriage;gardener' adjectives='' verbs='do;be;discover;insist;become;come;tell' valence='6.12727272727' arousal='4.51681818182' dominance='5.69681818182'>Princess</entity> insisted that her lover should tell her how he came to discover the secret.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='192'>So he showed her the two laurels which had helped him, and she, like a prudent girl, thinking they gave him too much advantage over his wife, cut them off at the root and threw them in the fire. And this is why <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='girl;singing' adjectives='' verbs='go;be' valence='6.4475' arousal='4.3075' dominance='5.6125'>the country</entity> girls go about singing:</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='193'></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='194'>Nous n"irons plus au bois,</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='195'>Les lauriers sont coupes,"</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='196'>and dancing in summer by the light of the moon.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='197'></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='198'>THE PRINCESS <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='princess' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='7.64' arousal='5.42' dominance='5.74'>MAYBLOSSOM</entity></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='199'>ONCE upon a time there lived a King and Queen whose children had all died, first one and then another, until at last only one little daughter remained, and the Queen was at her wits" end to know where to find a really good nurse who would take care of her, and bring her up. A herald was sent who blew a trumpet at every street corner, and commanded all the best nurses to appear before the Queen, that she might choose one for the little Princess. So on the appointed day the whole palace was crowded with nurses, who came from the four corners of the world to offer themselves, until the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='world;palace;wood;half;corner;nurse' adjectives='shady;whole' verbs='appoint;be;crowd;offer;sit;bring;see;come;declare' valence='5.66346153846' arousal='3.88538461538' dominance='5.51153846154'>Queen</entity> declared that if she was ever to see the half of them, they must be brought out to her, one by one, as she sat in a shady wood near <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='world;palace;wood;half;corner;nurse' adjectives='shady;whole' verbs='appoint;be;crowd;offer;sit;bring;see;come;declare' valence='5.66346153846' arousal='3.88538461538' dominance='5.51153846154'>the palace</entity>.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='200'>This was accordingly done, and the nurses, after they had made their curtsey to the King and Queen, ranged themselves in a line before her that she might choose. Most of them were fair and fat and charming, but there was one who was dark-skinned and ugly, and spoke a strange language which nobody could understand. The Queen wondered how she dared offer herself, and she was told to go away, as she certainly would not do. Upon which she muttered something and passed on, but hid herself in a hollow tree, from which she could see all that happened. The Queen, without giving her another thought, chose a pretty rosy-faced nurse, but no sooner was her choice made than a snake, which was hidden in the grass, bit that very nurse on her foot, so that she fell down as if dead. The Queen was very much vexed by this accident, but she soon selected another, who was just stepping forward when an eagle flew by and dropped a large tortoise upon her head, which was cracked in pieces like an egg-shell. At this the Queen was much horrified; nevertheless, she chose a third time, but with no better fortune, for the nurse, moving quickly, ran into the branch of a tree and blinded herself with a thorn. Then the Queen in dismay cried that there must be some malignant influence at work, and that she would choose no more that day; and she had just risen to return to the palace when she heard peals of malicious laughter behind her, and turning round saw the ugly stranger whom she had dismissed, who was making very merry over the disasters and mocking everyone, but especially the Queen. This annoyed Her Majesty very much, and she was about to order that she should be arrested, when the witch--for she was a witch--with two blows from a wand summoned a chariot of fire drawn by winged dragons, and was whirled off through the air uttering threats and cries. When <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='' verbs='see;cry' valence='4.46' arousal='4.69333333333' dominance='4.25333333333'>the King</entity> saw this he cried:</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='201'>"Alas! now we are ruined indeed, for that was no other than the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='porridge;boy;grudge;fun;carabosse;sulphur' adjectives='other' verbs='put;be;ruin;have' valence='5.49' arousal='4.17684210526' dominance='5.51631578947'>Fairy</entity> Carabosse, who has had a grudge against me ever since I was a boy and put sulphur into her porridge one day for fun."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='202'>Then the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='' verbs='begin;cry' valence='5.39333333333' arousal='4.45' dominance='4.77333333333'>Queen</entity> began to cry.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='203'>"If I had only known who it was," she said, "I would have done my best to make friends with her; now I suppose all is lost."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='204'><entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='misfortune;council' adjectives='sorry;little' verbs='be;avert;do;propose;bring;have;frighten;go;hold;mean' valence='5.31157894737' arousal='4.32052631579' dominance='5.19631578947'>The King</entity> was sorry to have frightened her so much, and proposed that they should go and hold a council as to what was best to be done to avert the misfortunes which Carabosse certainly meant to bring upon the little <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='misfortune;council' adjectives='sorry;little' verbs='be;avert;do;propose;bring;have;frighten;go;hold;mean' valence='5.31157894737' arousal='4.32052631579' dominance='5.19631578947'>Princess</entity>.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='3' num='205'>So all the counsellors were summoned to <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='ceremony;affair;head;door;league;counsellor;secret;christening;case;window;keyhole;time;carabosse;fairy;round' adjectives='profound' verbs='be;shut;decide;attend;overhear;summon;stuff;take;have;keep;talk;invite' valence='5.75942857143' arousal='4.02742857143' dominance='5.67542857143'>the palace</entity>, and when they had shut every door and window, and stuffed up every keyhole that they might not be overheard, they talked the affair over, and decided that every fairy for a thousand leagues round should be invited to the christening of the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='ceremony;affair;head;door;league;counsellor;secret;christening;case;window;keyhole;time;carabosse;fairy;round' adjectives='profound' verbs='be;shut;decide;attend;overhear;summon;stuff;take;have;keep;talk;invite' valence='5.75942857143' arousal='4.02742857143' dominance='5.67542857143'>Princess</entity>, and that the time of the ceremony should be kept a profound secret, in case the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='ceremony;affair;head;door;league;counsellor;secret;christening;case;window;keyhole;time;carabosse;fairy;round' adjectives='profound' verbs='be;shut;decide;attend;overhear;summon;stuff;take;have;keep;talk;invite' valence='5.75942857143' arousal='4.02742857143' dominance='5.67542857143'>Fairy</entity> Carabosse should take it into her head to attend it.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='206'>The Queen and her ladies set to work to prepare presents for the fairies who were invited: for each one a blue velvet cloak, a petticoat of apricot satin, a pair of high-heeled shoes, some sharp needles, and a pair of golden scissors. Of all the fairies the Queen knew, only five were able to come on the day appointed, but they began immediately to bestow gifts upon the Princess. One promised that she should be perfectly beautiful, the second that she should understand anything--no matter what--the first time it was explained to her, the third that she should sing like a nightingale, the fourth that she should succeed in everything she undertook, and the fifth was opening her mouth to speak when a tremendous rumbling was heard in <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='anything;everything;soot;matter;mouth;time;carabosse;nightingale' adjectives='beautiful;tremendous' verbs='be;come;explain;cry;cover;rumble;succeed;understand;undertake;sing;hear;promise;open;roll;speak' valence='5.8971875' arousal='4.05625' dominance='5.6221875'>the chimney</entity>, and Carabosse, all covered with soot, came rolling down, crying:</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='207'>"I say that she shall be the unluckiest of the unlucky until she is twenty years old."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='208'>Then the Queen and all the fairies began to beg and beseech her to think better of it, and not be so unkind to the poor little Princess, who had never done her any harm. But the ugly old Fairy only grunted and made no answer. So the last Fairy, who had not yet given her gift, tried to mend matters by promising the Princess a long and happy life after the fatal time was over. At this Carabosse laughed maliciously, and climbed away up the chimney, leaving them all in great consternation, and especially the Queen. However, she entertained the fairies splendidly, and gave them beautiful ribbons, of which they are very fond, in addition to the other presents.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='209'>When they were going away the oldest Fairy said that they were of opinion that it would be best to shut the Princess up in some place, with her waiting-women, so that she might not see anyone else until she was twenty years old. So the King had a tower built on purpose. It had no windows, so it was lighted with wax candles, and the only way into it was by an underground passage, which had iron doors only twenty feet apart, and guards were posted everywhere.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='210'>The Princess had been named Mayblossom, because she was as fresh and blooming as Spring itself, and she grew up tall and beautiful, and everything she did and said was charming. Every time the King and Queen came to see her they were more delighted with her than before, but though she was weary of the tower, and often begged them to take her away from it, they always refused. The Princess"s nurse, who had never left her, sometimes told her about the world outside the tower, and though the Princess had never seen anything for herself, yet she always understood exactly, thanks to the second Fairy"s gift. Often <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='' verbs='say' valence='6.14333333333' arousal='4.64333333333' dominance='6.15'>the King</entity> said to the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='' verbs='say' valence='6.14333333333' arousal='4.64333333333' dominance='6.15'>Queen</entity>:</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='211'>"We were cleverer than Carabosse after all. Our Mayblossom will be happy in spite of her predictions."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='5' num='212'>And the Queen laughed until she was tired at the idea of having outwitted the old Fairy. They had caused the Princess"s portrait to be painted and sent to all the neighbouring Courts, for in four days she would have completed her twentieth year, and it was time to decide whom she should marry. All the town was rejoicing at the thought of the Princess"s approaching freedom, and when the news came that King Merlin was sending his ambassador to ask her in marriage for his son, they were still more delighted. The nurse, who kept the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='ambassador;description;procession;everything;splendour;news;nurse' adjectives='wild;concerned' verbs='do;repeat;give;be;keep;inform;see;enter;go;fail' valence='5.68' arousal='4.29347826087' dominance='5.62260869565'>Princess</entity> informed of everything that went forward in <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='ambassador;description;procession;everything;splendour;news;nurse' adjectives='wild;concerned' verbs='do;repeat;give;be;keep;inform;see;enter;go;fail' valence='5.68' arousal='4.29347826087' dominance='5.62260869565'>the town</entity>, did not fail to repeat the news that so nearly concerned her, and gave such a description of the splendour in which the ambassador <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='ambassador;description;procession;everything;splendour;news;nurse' adjectives='wild;concerned' verbs='do;repeat;give;be;keep;inform;see;enter;go;fail' valence='5.68' arousal='4.29347826087' dominance='5.62260869565'>Fanfaronade</entity> would enter <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='ambassador;description;procession;everything;splendour;news;nurse' adjectives='wild;concerned' verbs='do;repeat;give;be;keep;inform;see;enter;go;fail' valence='5.68' arousal='4.29347826087' dominance='5.62260869565'>the town</entity>, that the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='ambassador;description;procession;everything;splendour;news;nurse' adjectives='wild;concerned' verbs='do;repeat;give;be;keep;inform;see;enter;go;fail' valence='5.68' arousal='4.29347826087' dominance='5.62260869565'>Princess</entity> was wild to see the procession for herself.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='213'>"What an unhappy creature I am," she cried, "to be shut up in this dismal tower as if I had committed some crime! I have never seen the sun, or the stars, or a horse, or a monkey, or a lion, except in pictures, and though <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='picture;horse;star;monkey;sun;lion' adjectives='free' verbs='be;set;amuse;say;keep;see;let;have;believe;tell;mean' valence='5.82484848485' arousal='4.40090909091' dominance='5.49454545455'>the King</entity> and <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='picture;horse;star;monkey;sun;lion' adjectives='free' verbs='be;set;amuse;say;keep;see;let;have;believe;tell;mean' valence='5.82484848485' arousal='4.40090909091' dominance='5.49454545455'>Queen</entity> tell me I am to be set free when I am twenty, I believe they only say it to keep me amused, when they never mean to let me out at all."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='214'>And then she began to cry, and her nurse, and the nurse"s daughter, and the cradle-rocker, and the nursery-maid, who all loved her dearly, cried too for company, so that nothing could be heard but sobs and sighs. It was a scene of woe. When the Princess saw that they all pitied her she made up her mind to have her own way. So she declared that she would starve herself to death if they did not find some means of letting her see <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='entry;s;death;means' adjectives='grand' verbs='starve;do;declare;see;let;find' valence='5.1375' arousal='4.0425' dominance='5.50833333333'>Fanfaronade</entity>"s grand entry into <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='entry;s;death;means' adjectives='grand' verbs='starve;do;declare;see;let;find' valence='5.1375' arousal='4.0425' dominance='5.50833333333'>the town</entity>.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='215'>"If you really love me," she said, "you will manage it, somehow or other, and <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='anything' adjectives='other' verbs='need;say;manage;love;know' valence='5.914' arousal='4.11' dominance='5.87'>the King</entity> and <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='anything' adjectives='other' verbs='need;say;manage;love;know' valence='5.914' arousal='4.11' dominance='5.87'>Queen</entity> need never know anything about it."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='216'>Then the nurse and all the others cried harder than ever, and said everything they could think of to turn the Princess from her idea. But the more they said the more determined she was, and at last they consented to make a tiny hole in <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='gate;hole;side' adjectives='last;tiny;more' verbs='be;look;consent;make;say;determine' valence='5.68692307692' arousal='4.07538461538' dominance='5.79153846154'>the tower</entity> on the side that looked towards <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='gate;hole;side' adjectives='last;tiny;more' verbs='be;look;consent;make;say;determine' valence='5.68692307692' arousal='4.07538461538' dominance='5.79153846154'>the city</entity> gates.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='217'>After scratching and scraping all day and all night, they presently made a hole through which they could, with great difficulty, push a very slender needle, and out of this the Princess looked at the daylight for the first time. She was so dazzled and delighted by what she saw, that there she stayed, never taking her eyes away from the peep-hole for a single minute, until presently the ambassador"s procession appeared in sight.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='218'>At the head of it rode Fanfaronade himself upon a white horse, which pranced and caracoled to the sound of the trumpets. Nothing could have been more splendid than the ambassador"s attire. His coat was nearly hidden under an embroidery of pearls and diamonds, his boots were solid gold, and from his helmet floated scarlet plumes. At the sight of him the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='nobody;wit;sight' adjectives='' verbs='marry;determine;lose' valence='6.21857142857' arousal='4.63571428571' dominance='5.77'>Princess</entity> lost her wits entirely, and determined that <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='nobody;wit;sight' adjectives='' verbs='marry;determine;lose' valence='6.21857142857' arousal='4.63571428571' dominance='5.77'>Fanfaronade</entity> and nobody else would she marry.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='219'>"It is quite impossible," she said, "that his master should be half as handsome and delightful. I am not ambitious, and having spent all my life in this tedious tower, anything--even a house in the country--will seem a delightful change. I am sure that bread and water shared with <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='sweetmeat;anybody;water;roast;chicken;bread' adjectives='sure' verbs='be;please;share' valence='5.979' arousal='3.782' dominance='5.841'>Fanfaronade</entity> will please me far better than roast chicken and sweetmeats with anybody else."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='220'>And so she went on talk, talk, talking, until her waiting-women wondered where she got it all from. But when they tried to stop her, and represented that her high rank made it perfectly impossible that she should do any such thing, she would not listen, and ordered them to be silent.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='221'>As soon as the ambassador arrived at <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='ambassador;daughter' adjectives='' verbs='start;arrive;fetch' valence='6.14142857143' arousal='4.64142857143' dominance='5.80571428571'>the palace</entity>, the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='ambassador;daughter' adjectives='' verbs='start;arrive;fetch' valence='6.14142857143' arousal='4.64142857143' dominance='5.80571428571'>Queen</entity> started to fetch her daughter.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='222'>All the streets were spread with carpets, and the windows were full of ladies who were waiting to see the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='flower;sweetmeat;shower;window;street;basket;lady;carpet' adjectives='full' verbs='be;see;spread;pass;carry;wait' valence='6.14823529412' arousal='3.67941176471' dominance='5.68647058824'>Princess</entity>, and carried baskets of flowers and sweetmeats to shower upon her as she passed.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='223'>They had hardly begun to get the Princess ready when a dwarf arrived, mounted upon an elephant. He came from the five fairies, and brought for the Princess a crown, a sceptre, and a robe of golden brocade, with a petticoat marvellously embroidered with butterflies" wings. They also sent a casket of jewels, so splendid that no one had ever seen anything like it before, and the Queen was perfectly dazzled when she opened it. But the Princess scarcely gave a glance to any of these treasures, for she thought of nothing but Fanfaronade. The Dwarf was rewarded with a gold piece, and decorated with so many ribbons that it was hardly possible to see him at all. The <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='treasure;distaff;wood;cedar;something;spinning-wheel;fairy' adjectives='new;charming' verbs='say;look;send;find' valence='6.344375' arousal='4.458125' dominance='5.86125'>Princess</entity> sent to each of the fairies a new spinning-wheel with a distaff of cedar wood, and the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='treasure;distaff;wood;cedar;something;spinning-wheel;fairy' adjectives='new;charming' verbs='say;look;send;find' valence='6.344375' arousal='4.458125' dominance='5.86125'>Queen</entity> said she must look through her treasures and find something very charming to send them also.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='224'>When the Princess was arrayed in all the gorgeous things the Dwarf had brought, she was more beautiful than ever, and as she walked along the streets the people cried: "How pretty she is! How pretty she is!"</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='225'>The procession consisted of the Queen, the Princess, five dozen other princesses her cousins, and ten dozen who came from the neighbouring kingdoms; and as they proceeded at a stately pace the sky began to grow dark, then suddenly the thunder growled, and rain and hail fell in torrents. The Queen put her royal mantle over her head, and all the princesses did the same with their trains. Mayblossom was just about to follow their example when a terrific croaking, as of an immense army of crows, rooks, ravens, screech-owls, and all birds of ill-omen was heard, and at the same instant a huge owl skimmed up to the Princess, and threw over her a scarf woven of spiders" webs and embroidered with bats" wings. And then peals of mocking laughter rang through the air, and they guessed that this was another of the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='joke;s;air;peal;carabosse;laughter' adjectives='unpleasant' verbs='be;ring;guess;mock' valence='5.914' arousal='4.581' dominance='5.445'>Fairy</entity> Carabosse"s unpleasant jokes.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='226'>The <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='shoulder;s;omen;scarf' adjectives='black;evil' verbs='be;pull;nail;try;cling;seem;terrify' valence='5.17611111111' arousal='4.16888888889' dominance='5.07055555556'>Queen</entity> was terrified at such an evil omen, and tried to pull the black scarf from the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='shoulder;s;omen;scarf' adjectives='black;evil' verbs='be;pull;nail;try;cling;seem;terrify' valence='5.17611111111' arousal='4.16888888889' dominance='5.07055555556'>Princess</entity>"s shoulders, but it really seemed as if it must be nailed on, it clung so closely.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='227'>While she lamented in this way, and everybody was as wet as if they had been dragged through a river, the Princess still thought of nothing but the ambassador, and just at this moment he appeared before her, with the King, and there was a great blowing of trumpets, and all the people shouted louder than ever. Fanfaronade was not generally at a loss for something to say, but when he saw the Princess, she was so much more beautiful and majestic than he had expected that he could only stammer out a few words, and entirely forgot the harangue which he had been learning for months, and knew well enough to have repeated it in his sleep. To gain time to remember at least part of it, he made several low bows to the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='curtsey;bow;embarrassment;part;time;side' adjectives='evident;several;low;least' verbs='relieve;remember;make;drop;stop;say;gain;think' valence='5.518125' arousal='3.914375' dominance='5.53125'>Princess</entity>, who on her side dropped half-a-dozen curtseys without stopping to think, and then said, to relieve his evident embarrassment:</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='228'>"Sir Ambassador, I am sure that everything you intend to say is charming, since it is you who mean to say it; but let us make haste into the palace, as it is pouring cats and dogs, and the wicked Fairy Carabosse will be amused to see us all stand dripping here. When we are once under shelter we can laugh at her."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='229'>Upon this the Ambassador found his tongue, and replied gallantly that the Fairy had evidently foreseen the flames that would be kindled by the bright eyes of the Princess, and had sent this deluge to extinguish them. Then he offered his hand to conduct the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='hand' adjectives='' verbs='say;conduct;offer' valence='6.066' arousal='4.194' dominance='6.012'>Princess</entity>, and she said softly:</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='230'>"As you could not possibly guess how much I like you, Sir Fanfaronade, I am obliged to tell you plainly that, since I saw you enter the town on your beautiful prancing horse, I have been sorry that you came to speak for another instead of for yourself. So, if you think about it as I do, I will marry you instead of your master. Of course I know you are not a prince, but I shall be just as fond of you as if you were, and we can go and live in some cosy little corner of the world, and be as happy as the days are long."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='231'>The Ambassador thought he must be dreaming, and could hardly believe what the lovely Princess said. He dared not answer, but only squeezed the Princess"s hand until he really hurt her little finger, but she did not cry out. When they reached <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='cheek;daughter' adjectives='' verbs='say;reach;kiss' valence='6.31428571429' arousal='4.48857142857' dominance='5.78428571429'>the palace</entity> <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='cheek;daughter' adjectives='' verbs='say;reach;kiss' valence='6.31428571429' arousal='4.48857142857' dominance='5.78428571429'>the King</entity> kissed his daughter on both cheeks, and said:</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='232'>"My little lambkin, are you willing to marry the great <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='ambassador;s;lambkin;behalf;son' adjectives='little;willing;great' verbs='be;marry;come;fetch;have' valence='6.145' arousal='4.08166666667' dominance='5.7075'>King Merlin</entity>"s son, for this Ambassador has come on his behalf to fetch you?"</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='233'>"If you please, sire," said the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='curtsey;sire' adjectives='' verbs='say;drop;please' valence='5.632' arousal='4.612' dominance='5.582'>Princess</entity>, dropping a curtsey.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='234'>"I consent also," said the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='banquet' adjectives='' verbs='consent;say;let;prepare;be' valence='5.92625' arousal='4.1525' dominance='6.04'>Queen</entity>; "so let the banquet be prepared."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='235'>This was done with all speed, and everybody feasted except <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='everybody;everything;speed' adjectives='' verbs='be;forget;feast;look;do' valence='5.94857142857' arousal='4.28857142857' dominance='5.65428571429'>Mayblossom</entity> and <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='everybody;everything;speed' adjectives='' verbs='be;forget;feast;look;do' valence='5.94857142857' arousal='4.28857142857' dominance='5.65428571429'>Fanfaronade</entity>, who looked at one another and forgot everything else.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='236'>After the banquet came a ball, and after that again a ballet, and at last they were all so tired that everyone fell asleep just where he sat. Only the lovers were as wide-awake as mice, and the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='nothing;fanfaronade;mouse;lover' adjectives='wide-awake' verbs='be;see;fear;say' valence='5.995' arousal='4.6975' dominance='5.45'>Princess</entity>, seeing that there was nothing to fear, said to Fanfaronade:</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='237'>"Let us be quick and run away, for we shall never have a better chance than this."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='238'>Then she took the King"s dagger, which was in a diamond sheath, and the Queen"s neck-handkerchief, and gave her hand to Fanfaronade, who carried a lantern, and they ran out together into the muddy street and down to the sea-shore. Here they got into a little boat in which the poor old boatman was sleeping, and when he woke up and saw the lovely Princess, with all her diamonds and her spiders"--web scarf, he did not know what to think, and obeyed her instantly when she commanded him to set out. They could see neither moon nor stars, but in the Queen"s neck-handkerchief there was a carbuncle which glowed like fifty torches. <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='long' verbs='do;answer;like;be;go;ask;care' valence='6.491' arousal='4.06' dominance='5.927'>Fanfaronade</entity> asked the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='long' verbs='do;answer;like;be;go;ask;care' valence='6.491' arousal='4.06' dominance='5.927'>Princess</entity> where she would like to go, but she only answered that she did not care where she went as long as he was with her.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='239'>"But, Princess," said he, "I dare not take you back to King Merlin"s court. He would think hanging too good for me."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='240'>"Oh, in that case," she answered, "we had better go to <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='case;anyone' adjectives='lonely' verbs='answer;go;follow;have;be' valence='5.55777777778' arousal='4.09' dominance='5.32777777778'>Squirrel Island</entity>; it is lonely enough, and too far off for anyone to follow us there."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='241'>So she ordered the old boatman to steer for <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='boatman' adjectives='old' verbs='order;steer' valence='5.49333333333' arousal='4.175' dominance='5.70833333333'>Squirrel Island</entity>.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='242'>Meanwhile the day was breaking, and the King and Queen and all the courtiers began to wake up and rub their eyes, and think it was time to finish the preparations for the wedding. And the Queen asked for her neck-handkerchief, that she might look smart. Then there was a scurrying hither and thither, and a hunting everywhere: they looked into every place, from the wardrobes to the stoves, and the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='cellar;handkerchief;hunting;stove;place;garret;wardrobe' adjectives='' verbs='be;run;look;scurry;find' valence='5.6025' arousal='4.053125' dominance='5.54'>Queen</entity> herself ran about from the garret to the cellar, but the handkerchief was nowhere to be found.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='3' num='243'>By this time the King had missed his dagger, and the search began all over again. They opened boxes and chests of which the keys had been lost for a hundred years, and found numbers of curious things, but not the dagger, and <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='box;dagger;handkerchief;number;hair;thing;chest;key;beard' adjectives='curious;valuable' verbs='be;tear;have;lose;open;find' valence='5.52296296296' arousal='4.13925925926' dominance='5.69740740741'>the King</entity> tore his beard, and the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='box;dagger;handkerchief;number;hair;thing;chest;key;beard' adjectives='curious;valuable' verbs='be;tear;have;lose;open;find' valence='5.52296296296' arousal='4.13925925926' dominance='5.69740740741'>Queen</entity> tore her hair, for the handkerchief and the dagger were the most valuable things in <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='box;dagger;handkerchief;number;hair;thing;chest;key;beard' adjectives='curious;valuable' verbs='be;tear;have;lose;open;find' valence='5.52296296296' arousal='4.13925925926' dominance='5.69740740741'>the kingdom</entity>.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='244'>When <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='search' adjectives='hopeless' verbs='be;see;say' valence='5.00166666667' arousal='4.14333333333' dominance='5.07'>the King</entity> saw that the search was hopeless he said:</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='245'>"Never mind, let us make haste and get the wedding over before anything else is lost." And then he asked where the Princess was. Upon this her nurse came forward and said:</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='246'>"Sire, I have been seeking her these two hours, but she is nowhere to be found." This was more than the Queen could bear. She gave a shriek of alarm and fainted away, and they had to pour two barrels of eau-de-cologne over her before she recovered. When she came to herself everybody was looking for the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='everybody;terror;page;confusion' adjectives='greatest' verbs='be;appear;do;say;come;look' valence='5.46727272727' arousal='4.21909090909' dominance='5.41636363636'>Princess</entity> in the greatest terror and confusion, but as she did not appear, <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='everybody;terror;page;confusion' adjectives='greatest' verbs='be;appear;do;say;come;look' valence='5.46727272727' arousal='4.21909090909' dominance='5.41636363636'>the King</entity> said to his page:</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='247'>"Go and find the Ambassador <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='ambassador;news;corner' adjectives='doubtless;sad' verbs='go;be;find;tell' valence='5.34555555556' arousal='3.67333333333' dominance='5.08222222222'>Fanfaronade</entity>, who is doubtless asleep in some corner, and tell him the sad news."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='248'>So the page hunted hither and thither, but <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='dagger;page;neck-handkerchief' adjectives='more' verbs='be;hunt;find' valence='5.82285714286' arousal='4.30571428571' dominance='5.64'>Fanfaronade</entity> was no more to be found than the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='dagger;page;neck-handkerchief' adjectives='more' verbs='be;hunt;find' valence='5.82285714286' arousal='4.30571428571' dominance='5.64'>Princess</entity>, the dagger, or the neck-handkerchief!</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='249'>Then the King summoned his counsellors and his guards, and, accompanied by the Queen, went into his great hall. As he had not had time to prepare his speech beforehand, <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='end;speech;silence;time' adjectives='' verbs='be;prepare;keep;have;follow;order;speak' valence='5.585625' arousal='3.671875' dominance='5.654375'>the King</entity> ordered that silence should be kept for three hours, and at the end of that time he spoke as follows:</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='250'>"Listen, great and small! My dear daughter Mayblossom is lost: whether she has been stolen away or has simply disappeared I cannot tell. The Queen"s neck-handkerchief and my sword, which are worth their weight in gold, are also missing, and, what is worst of all, the Ambassador Fanfaronade is nowhere to be found. I greatly fear that the King, his master, when he receives no tidings from him, will come to seek him among us, and will accuse us of having made mince-meat of him. Perhaps I could bear even that if I had any money, but I assure you that the expenses of the wedding have completely ruined me. Advise me, then, my dear subjects, what had I better do to recover my daughter, <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='thing;daughter;subject' adjectives='other' verbs='do;advise;recover;have' valence='5.613' arousal='4.11' dominance='5.723'>Fanfaronade</entity>, and the other things."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='251'>This was the most eloquent speech <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='everybody;prime;answer;speech;minister' adjectives='eloquent' verbs='be;do;make;admire;know;have' valence='6.11466666667' arousal='3.92466666667' dominance='6.05666666667'>the King</entity> had been known to make, and when everybody had done admiring it the Prime Minister made answer:</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='252'>"Sire, we are all very sorry to see you so sorry. We would give everything we value in the world to take away the cause of your sorrow, but this seems to be another of the tricks of the Fairy Carabosse. The Princess"s twenty unlucky years were not quite over, and really, if the truth must be told, I noticed that Fanfaronade and the Princess appeared to admire one another greatly. Perhaps this may give some clue to the mystery of their disappearance."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='253'>Here the Queen interrupted him, saying, "Take care what you say, sir. Believe me, the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='ambassador;love' adjectives='' verbs='be;fall;believe;think;bring' valence='6.062' arousal='4.373' dominance='5.597'>Princess Mayblossom</entity> was far too well brought up to think of falling in love with an Ambassador."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='254'>At this the nurse came forward, and, falling on her knees, confessed how they had made the little needle-hole in the tower, and how the Princess had declared when she saw the Ambassador that she would marry him and nobody else. Then the Queen was very angry, and gave the nurse, and the cradle-rocker, and the nursery-maid such a scolding that they shook in their shoes. But the Admiral <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='admiral' adjectives='' verbs='interrupt;cry' valence='3.76' arousal='4.62' dominance='4.05666666667'>Cocked-Hat</entity> interrupted her, crying:</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='255'>"Let us be off after this good-for-nothing <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='doubt' adjectives='good-for-nothing' verbs='be;run;let;have' valence='5.76' arousal='4.23571428571' dominance='5.21714285714'>Fanfaronade</entity>, for with out a doubt he has run away with our <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='doubt' adjectives='good-for-nothing' verbs='be;run;let;have' valence='5.76' arousal='4.23571428571' dominance='5.21714285714'>Princess</entity>."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='256'>Then there was a great clapping of hands, and everybody shouted, "By all means let us be after him."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='257'>So while some embarked upon <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='kingdom;other;drum;beating;crowd' adjectives='' verbs='blow;run;cry;collect;embark;trumpet' valence='5.73307692308' arousal='4.32923076923' dominance='5.49769230769'>the sea</entity>, the others ran from kingdom to kingdom beating drums and blowing trumpets, and wherever a crowd collected they cried:</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='258'>"Whoever wants a beautiful doll, sweetmeats of all kinds, a little pair of scissors, a golden robe, and a satin cap has only to say where <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='kind;doll;cap;sweetmeat;mayblossom;pair;scissors;robe' adjectives='beautiful;golden;little;satin' verbs='say;hide;have;want' valence='5.9445' arousal='4.2' dominance='5.751'>Fanfaronade</entity> has hidden the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='kind;doll;cap;sweetmeat;mayblossom;pair;scissors;robe' adjectives='beautiful;golden;little;satin' verbs='say;hide;have;want' valence='5.9445' arousal='4.2' dominance='5.751'>Princess</entity> Mayblossom."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='259'>But the answer everywhere was, "You must go farther, we have not seen them."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='260'>However, those who went by sea were more fortunate, for after sailing about for some time they noticed a light before them which burned at night like a great fire. At first they dared not go near it, not knowing what it might be, but by-and-by it remained stationary over Squirrel Island, for, as you have guessed already, the light was the glowing of the carbuncle. The <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='gold;thing;landing;boatman;fleet;midst;piece;fanfaronade;boat' adjectives='' verbs='be;give;make;get;send;see;promise;take;have;escape;happen;tell;row' valence='5.94870967742' arousal='3.98516129032' dominance='5.65322580645'>Princess</entity> and Fanfaronade on landing upon <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='gold;thing;landing;boatman;fleet;midst;piece;fanfaronade;boat' adjectives='' verbs='be;give;make;get;send;see;promise;take;have;escape;happen;tell;row' valence='5.94870967742' arousal='3.98516129032' dominance='5.65322580645'>the island</entity> had given the boatman a hundred gold pieces, and made him promise solemnly to tell no one where he had taken them; but the first thing that happened was that, as he rowed away, he got into the midst of the fleet, and before he could escape the Admiral had seen him and sent a boat after him.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='261'>When he was searched they found the gold pieces in his pocket, and as they were quite new coins, struck in honour of the Princess"s wedding, the Admiral felt certain that the boatman must have been paid by the Princess to aid her in her flight. But he would not answer any questions, and pretended to be deaf and dumb.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='262'>Then the Admiral said: "Oh! deaf and dumb is he? Lash him to the mast and give him a taste of the cat-o"-nine-tails. I don"t know anything better than that for curing the deaf and dumb!"</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='5' num='263'>And when the old boatman saw that he was in earnest, he told all he knew about the cavalier and <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='fleet;boatman;order;admiral;earnest' adjectives='old;cavalier' verbs='be;land;give;surround;see;know;have;tell' valence='5.96043478261' arousal='3.91086956522' dominance='5.59347826087'>the lady</entity> whom he had landed upon <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='fleet;boatman;order;admiral;earnest' adjectives='old;cavalier' verbs='be;land;give;surround;see;know;have;tell' valence='5.96043478261' arousal='3.91086956522' dominance='5.59347826087'>Squirrel Island</entity>, and the Admiral knew it must be the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='fleet;boatman;order;admiral;earnest' adjectives='old;cavalier' verbs='be;land;give;surround;see;know;have;tell' valence='5.96043478261' arousal='3.91086956522' dominance='5.59347826087'>Princess</entity> and <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='fleet;boatman;order;admiral;earnest' adjectives='old;cavalier' verbs='be;land;give;surround;see;know;have;tell' valence='5.96043478261' arousal='3.91086956522' dominance='5.59347826087'>Fanfaronade</entity>; so he gave the order for the fleet to surround <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='fleet;boatman;order;admiral;earnest' adjectives='old;cavalier' verbs='be;land;give;surround;see;know;have;tell' valence='5.96043478261' arousal='3.91086956522' dominance='5.59347826087'>the island</entity>.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='264'>Meanwhile the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='slumber;shade;bank;time' adjectives='hungry;sleepy;grassy;profound' verbs='be;throw;say;wake;have;fall;happen;come;find' valence='5.64739130435' arousal='3.86869565217' dominance='5.37782608696'>Princess Mayblossom</entity>, who was by this time terribly sleepy, had found a grassy bank in the shade, and throwing herself down had already fallen into a profound slumber, when <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='slumber;shade;bank;time' adjectives='hungry;sleepy;grassy;profound' verbs='be;throw;say;wake;have;fall;happen;come;find' valence='5.64739130435' arousal='3.86869565217' dominance='5.37782608696'>Fanfaronade</entity>, who happened to be hungry and not sleepy, came and woke her up, saying, very crossly:</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='265'>"Pray, madam, how long do you mean to stay here? I see nothing to eat, and though you may be very charming, the sight of you does not prevent me from famishing."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='266'>"What! Fanfaronade," said the Princess, sitting up and rubbing her eyes, "is it possible that when I am here with you you can want anything else? You ought to be thinking all the time how happy you are."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='267'>"Happy!" cried he; "say rather unhappy. I wish with all my heart that you were back in your dark tower again."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='268'>"Darling, don"t be cross," said the Princess. "I will go and see if I can find some wild fruit for you."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='269'>"I wish you might find a wolf to eat you up," growled <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='wolf' adjectives='' verbs='wish;growl;find;eat' valence='5.91142857143' arousal='4.35428571429' dominance='5.67142857143'>Fanfaronade</entity>.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='270'>The Princess, in great dismay, ran hither and thither all about the wood, tearing her dress, and hurting her pretty white hands with the thorns and brambles, but she could find nothing good to eat, and at last she had to go back sorrowfully to Fanfaronade. When he saw that she came empty-handed he got up and left her, grumbling to himself.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='271'>The next day they searched again, but with no better success.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='272'>"Alas!" said the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='something' adjectives='hungry' verbs='be;say;mind;find;eat' valence='5.94666666667' arousal='4.64777777778' dominance='5.81111111111'>Princess</entity>, "if only I could find something for you to eat, I should not mind being hungry myself."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='273'>"No, I should not mind that either," answered <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='' verbs='answer;mind' valence='5.93333333333' arousal='4.68333333333' dominance='5.68'>Fanfaronade</entity>.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='274'>"Is it possible," said she, "that you would not care if I died of hunger? Oh, Fanfaronade, you said you loved me!"</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='275'>"That was when we were in quite another place and I was not hungry," said he. "It makes a great difference in one"s ideas to be dying of hunger and thirst on a desert island."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='276'>At this the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='white' verbs='be;begin;cry;sit;rise;vex' valence='5.81555555556' arousal='3.79555555556' dominance='5.27888888889'>Princess</entity> was dreadfully vexed, and she sat down under a white rose <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='white' verbs='be;begin;cry;sit;rise;vex' valence='5.81555555556' arousal='3.79555555556' dominance='5.27888888889'>bush</entity> and began to cry bitterly.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='277'>"Happy roses," she thought to herself, "they have only to blossom in the sunshine and be admired, and there is nobody to be unkind to them." And the tears ran down her cheeks and splashed on to the rose-tree roots. Presently she was surprised to see the whole bush rustling and shaking, and a soft little voice from the prettiest rosebud said:</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='278'>"Poor Princess! look in the trunk of that tree, and you will find a honeycomb, but don"t be foolish enough to share it with <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='t;honeycomb;tree;look;trunk' adjectives='enough;foolish' verbs='be;share;don;find' valence='5.66181818182' arousal='3.77363636364' dominance='5.59090909091'>Fanfaronade</entity>."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='279'>Mayblossom ran to the tree, and sure enough there was the honey. Without losing a moment she ran with it to <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='moment' adjectives='' verbs='cry;run;lose' valence='4.864' arousal='5.034' dominance='4.678'>Fanfaronade</entity>, crying gaily:</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='280'>"See, here is a honeycomb that I have found. I might have eaten it up all by myself, but I had rather share it with you."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='281'>But without looking at her or thanking her he snatched the honey comb out of her hands and ate it all up--every bit, without offering her a morsel. Indeed, when she humbly asked for some he said mockingly that it was too sweet for her, and would spoil her teeth.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='282'>Mayblossom, more downcast than ever, went sadly away and sat down under an oak tree, and her tears and sighs were so piteous that the oak fanned her with his rustling leaves, and said:</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='283'>"Take courage, pretty Princess, all is not lost yet. Take this pitcher of milk and drink it up, and whatever you do, don"t leave a drop for Fanfaronade."</paragraph>
