<document name='fairytales-corpus-data/The Scottish Fairy Book.txt'>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='0'>THE SCOTTISH FAIRY BOOK BOOKS IN THE "FAIRY SERIES"</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='1'></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='2'>_The English <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='6.88' arousal='4.085' dominance='6.395'>Fairy</entity> Book_</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='3'>_The Welsh <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='welsh;book' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='6.09666666667' arousal='4.05666666667' dominance='5.89333333333'>Fairy</entity> Book_</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='4'>_The Irish <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='book' adjectives='irish' verbs='' valence='6.88' arousal='4.085' dominance='6.395'>Fairy</entity> Book_</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='5'>_The Scottish <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='book' adjectives='scottish' verbs='' valence='6.88' arousal='4.085' dominance='6.395'>Fairy</entity> Book_</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='6'>_The Italian <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='6.88' arousal='4.085' dominance='6.395'>Fairy</entity> Book_</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='7'>_The Hungarian <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='6.88' arousal='4.085' dominance='6.395'>Fairy</entity> Book_</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='8'>_The Indian <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='book' adjectives='indian' verbs='' valence='6.88' arousal='4.085' dominance='6.395'>Fairy</entity> Book_</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='9'>_The Spanish <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='6.88' arousal='4.085' dominance='6.395'>Fairy</entity> Book_</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='10'>_The Danish <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='6.88' arousal='4.085' dominance='6.395'>Fairy</entity> Book_</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='11'>_The Norwegian <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='6.88' arousal='4.085' dominance='6.395'>Fairy</entity> Book_</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='12'>_The Jewish <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='6.88' arousal='4.085' dominance='6.395'>Fairy</entity> Book_</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='13'>_The Swedish <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='6.88' arousal='4.085' dominance='6.395'>Fairy</entity> Book_</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='14'>_The Chinese <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='6.88' arousal='4.085' dominance='6.395'>Fairy</entity> Book_</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='15'></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='16'>THE SCOTTISH FAIRY</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='17'>BOOK  BY <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='book' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='7.05' arousal='3.13' dominance='6.41'>ELIZABETH W.</entity></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='18'><entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='illustration' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='6.37' arousal='4.0' dominance='6.26'>GRIERSON</entity>  WITH ILLUSTRATIONS</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='19'>BY <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='5.0' arousal='5.0' dominance='5.0'>MORRIS</entity></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='20'><entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='5.0' arousal='5.0' dominance='5.0'>MEREDITH WILLIAMS</entity></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='21'></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='22'>[Illustration]</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='23'></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='24'><entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='company' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='5.64' arousal='3.29' dominance='5.0'>J. B. LIPPINCOTT</entity> COMPANY</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='25'><entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='5.0' arousal='5.0' dominance='5.0'>PHILADELPHIA</entity></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='26'><entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='7.68' arousal='5.14' dominance='5.22'>NEW YORK</entity></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='27'></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='28'>Printed in <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='printed' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='5.0' arousal='5.0' dominance='5.0'>U.S.A.</entity></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='29'></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='30'>"Of _<entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='_;buke' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='6.0' arousal='3.48' dominance='6.06'>Brownys</entity> and of <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='_;buke' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='6.0' arousal='3.48' dominance='6.06'>Bogillis Full</entity> this Buke_."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='31'></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='32'>--<entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='5.0' arousal='5.0' dominance='5.0'>GAVIN DOUGLAS</entity></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='33'></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='34'>PREFACE</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='35'>There are, roughly speaking, two distinct types of Scottish <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='tale;type' adjectives='distinct;scottish' verbs='be;speak' valence='6.09428571429' arousal='3.65857142857' dominance='5.67142857143'>Fairy</entity> Tales.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='36'>There are what may be called "Celtic Stories," which were handed down for centuries by word of mouth by professional story-tellers, who went about from clachan to clachan in the "Highlands and <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='clachan;celtic;highlands;word;entertainment;shelter;s;other;stories;mouth;story-teller' adjectives='professional' verbs='be;earn;clachan;give;hand;collect;call;have;go;classify' valence='6.02153846154' arousal='4.04807692308' dominance='5.58307692308'>Islands</entity>," earning a night"s shelter by giving a night"s entertainment, and which have now been collected and classified for us by Campbell of Isla and others.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='37'>These stories, which are also common to the North of Ireland, are wild and fantastic, and very often somewhat monotonous, and their themes are strangely alike. They almost always tell of some hero or heroine who sets out on some dangerous quest, and who is met by giants, generally three in number, who appear one after the other; with whom they hold quaint dialogues, and whom eventually they slay. Most of them are fairly long, and although they have a peculiar fascination of their own, they are quite distinct from the ordinary <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='fascination;tale' adjectives='distinct;most;ordinary;own;peculiar' verbs='be;have' valence='5.841' arousal='3.917' dominance='5.765'>Fairy</entity> Tale.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='38'>These latter, in <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='country;character;date;existence;goblin;spirit' adjectives='latter;own;recent' verbs='be;believe;have' valence='5.88714285714' arousal='4.11071428571' dominance='5.57285714286'>Scotland</entity>, have also a character of their own, for there is no country where the existence of Spirits and Goblins has been so implicitly believed in up to a comparatively recent date.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='39'>As a proof of this we can go to Hogg"s tale of "The Wool-gatherer," and see how the countryman, Barnaby, voices the belief of his day. "Ye had need to tak care how ye dispute the existence of fairies, brownies, and apparitions! Ye may as weel dispute the Gospel of Saint <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='gospel;saint;dispute' adjectives='' verbs='weel' valence='4.9375' arousal='3.48' dominance='4.935'>Matthew</entity>."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='40'>Perhaps it was the bleak and stern character of their climate, and the austerity of their religious beliefs which made our Scottish forefathers think of the spirits in whom they so firmly believed, as being, for the most part, mischievous and malevolent.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='41'>Their Bogies, their Witches, their Kelpies, even their <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='league;tiend;being;kelpy;cost;witch;bogie;hell' adjectives='uncanny' verbs='be;pay;compel;suppose;dread;fear;find;wonder' valence='5.20846153846' arousal='4.27615384615' dominance='5.24730769231'>Fairy Queen</entity> herself, were supposed to be in league with the Evil One, and to be compelled, as <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='league;tiend;being;kelpy;cost;witch;bogie;hell' adjectives='uncanny' verbs='be;pay;compel;suppose;dread;fear;find;wonder' valence='5.20846153846' arousal='4.27615384615' dominance='5.24730769231'>Thomas of Ercildoune</entity> was near finding out to his cost, to pay a "Tiend to Hell" every seven years; so it was not to be wondered at, that these uncanny beings were dreaded and feared.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='42'>But along with this dark and gloomy view, we find touches of delicate playfulness and brightness. The <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='sith;league;dwelling;sward;tale;case;knowe;satan;earshot;respect;law;folk;subject' adjectives='rocky;many;same;charming;dewy;silent' verbs='be;dance;bind;make;come;tell;speak' valence='5.88583333333' arousal='3.99416666667' dominance='5.94583333333'>Fairy Queen</entity> might be in league with Satan, but her subjects were not all bound by the same law, and many charming tales are told of the "sith" or silent folk, who were always spoken of with respect, in case they might be within earshot, who made their dwellings under some rocky knowe, and who came out and danced on the dewy sward at midnight.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='43'>Akin to them are the tales which are told about a mysterious region under the sea, "far below the abode of fishes," where a strange race of beings lived, who, in their own land closely resembled human beings, and were of such surpassing beauty that they charmed the hearts of all who looked on them. They were spoken of as Mermaids and Mermen, and as their lungs were not adapted for breathing under water, they had the extraordinary power of entering into the skin of some fish or sea animal, and in this way passing from their own abode to our upper world, where they held converse with mortal men, and, as often as not, tried to lure them to destruction.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='44'>The popular idea always represents Mer-folk as wearing the tails of fishes; in Scottish Folklore they are quite as often found in the form of seals.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='45'>Then we frequently come across the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='notice;shaggy;helper;appearance;beast;drudgery;half;wages;creature;sin;man' adjectives='lovable;unkempt;strange' verbs='be;entail;forbid;work;ordain;receive;say;take;come;disappear;look' valence='5.5976' arousal='4.1304' dominance='5.5856'>Brownie</entity>, that strange, kindly, lovable creature, with its shaggy, unkempt appearance, half man, half beast, who was said to be the ordained helper of man in the drudgery entailed by sin, and was therefore forbidden to receive wages; who always worked when no one was looking, and who disappeared if any notice were taken of him.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='3' num='46'>There are also, as in all other countries, animal tales, where the animals are endowed with the power of speech; and weird tales of enchantment; and last, but not least, there are the legendary stories, many of them half real, half mythical, which are to be found in the pages of <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='minstrelsy;sir;story;power;enchantment;country;tale;s;speech;animal;border;page' adjectives='real;last;mythical;endowed;half;least;other;legendary;many;weird' verbs='be;find' valence='6.12291666667' arousal='4.08708333333' dominance='5.70958333333'>Hogg</entity>, and <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='minstrelsy;sir;story;power;enchantment;country;tale;s;speech;animal;border;page' adjectives='real;last;mythical;endowed;half;least;other;legendary;many;weird' verbs='be;find' valence='6.12291666667' arousal='4.08708333333' dominance='5.70958333333'>Leyden</entity>, and above all, in Sir <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='minstrelsy;sir;story;power;enchantment;country;tale;s;speech;animal;border;page' adjectives='real;last;mythical;endowed;half;least;other;legendary;many;weird' verbs='be;find' valence='6.12291666667' arousal='4.08708333333' dominance='5.70958333333'>Walter Scott</entity>"s "Border Minstrelsy."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='47'>In preparing this book I have tried to make a representative collection from these different classes of Scottish Folklore, taking, when possible, the stories which are least well known, in the hope that some of them, at least, may be new to the children of this generation.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='3' num='48'>It may interest some of these children to know that when <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='boy;story;red-etin;sir;tutor;s;child;knee' adjectives='little;same' verbs='be;use;sit;write;know;interest;listen' valence='5.88791666667' arousal='3.88875' dominance='5.59541666667'>James IV</entity> was a little boy, nearly four hundred years ago, he used to sit on his tutor, Sir <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='boy;story;red-etin;sir;tutor;s;child;knee' adjectives='little;same' verbs='be;use;sit;write;know;interest;listen' valence='5.88791666667' arousal='3.88875' dominance='5.59541666667'>David Lindsay</entity>"s, knee, and listen to some of the same stories that are written here:--to the story of <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='boy;story;red-etin;sir;tutor;s;child;knee' adjectives='little;same' verbs='be;use;sit;write;know;interest;listen' valence='5.88791666667' arousal='3.88875' dominance='5.59541666667'>Thomas the Rhymer</entity>, of the Red-Etin, and of The Black Bull of Norroway.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='5' num='49'>Although in every case I have told the tale in my own words, I am indebted for the originals to Campbell"s "Popular Tales of the <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='case;poem;word;journal;rhymes;tale;s;minstrelsy;folklore;popular;chambers;border;original' adjectives='indebted;own' verbs='be;tell;have' valence='5.55608695652' arousal='4.24652173913' dominance='5.45304347826'>Western Highlands</entity>," <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='case;poem;word;journal;rhymes;tale;s;minstrelsy;folklore;popular;chambers;border;original' adjectives='indebted;own' verbs='be;tell;have' valence='5.55608695652' arousal='4.24652173913' dominance='5.45304347826'>Leyden</entity>"s Poems, <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='case;poem;word;journal;rhymes;tale;s;minstrelsy;folklore;popular;chambers;border;original' adjectives='indebted;own' verbs='be;tell;have' valence='5.55608695652' arousal='4.24652173913' dominance='5.45304347826'>Hogg</entity>"s Poems, <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='case;poem;word;journal;rhymes;tale;s;minstrelsy;folklore;popular;chambers;border;original' adjectives='indebted;own' verbs='be;tell;have' valence='5.55608695652' arousal='4.24652173913' dominance='5.45304347826'>Scott</entity>"s "Border Minstrelsy," Chambers" "Popular Rhymes of <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='case;poem;word;journal;rhymes;tale;s;minstrelsy;folklore;popular;chambers;border;original' adjectives='indebted;own' verbs='be;tell;have' valence='5.55608695652' arousal='4.24652173913' dominance='5.45304347826'>Scotland</entity>," "The Folklore Journal," etc.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='50'></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='51'><entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='5.0' arousal='5.0' dominance='5.0'>ELIZABETH W. GRIERSON</entity>.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='52'></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='53'>_Whitchesters, <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='n.b.;whitchester;_' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='5.0' arousal='5.0' dominance='5.0'>Hawick</entity>, N.B.,</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='54'>12th April, 1910._</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='55'></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='56'>CONTENTS</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='57'></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='58'>PAGE</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='59'><entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='rhymer' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='5.0' arousal='5.0' dominance='5.0'>Thomas</entity> the Rhymer</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='60'>1</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='61'>Gold-Tree and <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='gold-tree' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='5.0' arousal='5.0' dominance='5.0'>Silver-Tree</entity></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='62'>17</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='63'>Whippety-Stourie</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='64'>33</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='65'>The Red-Etin</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='66'>42</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='67'>The Seal Catcher and the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='catcher;seal' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='5.195' arousal='2.88' dominance='5.215'>Merman</entity></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='68'>58</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='69'>The Page-boy and the Silver Goblet</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='70'>67</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='71'>The Black Bull of <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='bull' adjectives='black' verbs='' valence='4.675' arousal='4.24' dominance='6.185'>Norroway</entity></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='72'>74</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='73'>The Wee Bannock</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='74'>93</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='75'>The Elfin <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='elfin' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='5.0' arousal='5.0' dominance='5.0'>Knight</entity></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='76'>101</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='77'>What to say to the New Mune</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='78'>114</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='79'>Habetrot the Spinstress</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='80'>115</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='81'>Nippit Fit and Clippit Fit</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='82'>130</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='83'>The Fairies of <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='s;crag;fairies' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='5.0' arousal='5.0' dominance='5.0'>Merlin</entity>"s Crag</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='84'>136</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='85'>The Wedding of <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='wedding' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='6.99' arousal='3.98' dominance='4.715'>Robin Redbreast</entity> and <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='wedding' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='6.99' arousal='3.98' dominance='4.715'>Jenny Wren</entity></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='86'>144</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='87'>The Dwarfie Stone</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='88'>150</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='3' num='89'>Canonbie <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='canonbie' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='3.06' arousal='5.6' dominance='3.44'>Dick</entity> and <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='canonbie' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='3.06' arousal='5.6' dominance='3.44'>Thomas</entity> of <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='canonbie' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='3.06' arousal='5.6' dominance='3.44'>Ercildoune</entity></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='90'>169</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='91'>The Laird o" Co"</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='92'>179</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='93'><entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='5.0' arousal='5.0' dominance='5.0'>Poussie Baudrons</entity></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='94'>186</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='95'>The Milk-white Doo</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='96'>188</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='97'>The Draiglin" Hogney</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='98'>196</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='99'>The Brownie o" Ferne-Den</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='100'>204</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='101'>The <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='fife' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='3.14' arousal='5.3' dominance='4.79'>Witch</entity> of Fife</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='102'>211</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='103'><entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='5.0' arousal='5.0' dominance='5.0'>Assipattle</entity> and the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='5.0' arousal='5.0' dominance='5.0'>Mester Stoorworm</entity></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='104'>221</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='105'>The Fox and the Wolf</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='106'>245</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='107'><entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='5.0' arousal='5.0' dominance='5.0'>Katherine Crackernuts</entity></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='108'>253</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='109'>Times to Sneeze</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='110'>268</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='111'>The Well o" the World"s End</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='112'>272</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='113'><entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='5.0' arousal='5.0' dominance='5.0'>Farquhar MacNeill</entity></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='114'>277</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='115'>Peerifool</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='116'>284</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='117'>Birthdays</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='118'>298</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='119'></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='120'>THOMAS THE RHYMER</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='4' num='121'>Of all the young gallants in <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='gallant;none;ercildoune;castle' adjectives='young;debonair;gracious' verbs='be' valence='6.31333333333' arousal='4.035' dominance='5.76666666667'>Scotland</entity> in the thirteenth century, there was none more gracious and debonair than <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='gallant;none;ercildoune;castle' adjectives='young;debonair;gracious' verbs='be' valence='6.31333333333' arousal='4.035' dominance='5.76666666667'>Thomas Learmont</entity>, <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='gallant;none;ercildoune;castle' adjectives='young;debonair;gracious' verbs='be' valence='6.31333333333' arousal='4.035' dominance='5.76666666667'>Laird</entity> of the Castle of Ercildoune, in <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='gallant;none;ercildoune;castle' adjectives='young;debonair;gracious' verbs='be' valence='6.31333333333' arousal='4.035' dominance='5.76666666667'>Berwickshire</entity>.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='122'>He loved books, poetry, and music, which were uncommon tastes in those days; and, above all, he loved to study nature, and to watch the habits of the beasts and birds that made their abode in the fields and woods round about his home.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='123'>Now it chanced that, one sunny May morning, Thomas left his Tower of Ercildoune, and went wandering into the woods that lay about the Huntly Burn, a little stream that came rushing down from the slopes of the Eildon Hills. It was a lovely morning--fresh, and bright, and warm, and everything was so beautiful that it looked as Paradise might look.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='124'>The tender leaves were bursting out of their sheaths, and covering all the trees with a fresh soft mantle of green; and amongst the carpet of moss under the young man"s feet, yellow primroses and starry anemones were turning up their faces to the morning sky.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='125'>The little birds were singing like to burst their throats, and hundreds of insects were flying backwards and forwards in the sunshine; while down by the burnside the bright-eyed water-rats were poking their noses out of their holes, as if they knew that summer had come, and wanted to have a share in all that was going on.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='126'><entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='living;tree;thing;root;gladness' adjectives='happy' verbs='feel;watch;throw' valence='6.15125' arousal='4.08875' dominance='5.9325'>Thomas</entity> felt so happy with the gladness of it all, that he threw himself down at the root of a tree, to watch the living things around him.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='127'>As he was lying there, he heard the trampling of a horse"s hooves, as it forced its way through the bushes; and, looking up, he saw the most beautiful lady that he had ever seen coming riding towards him on a grey palfrey.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='128'>She wore a hunting dress of glistening silk, the colour of the fresh spring grass; and from her shoulders hung a velvet mantle, which matched the riding-skirt exactly. Her yellow hair, like rippling gold, hung loosely round her shoulders, and on her head sparkled a diadem of precious stones, which flashed like fire in the sunlight.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='129'>Her saddle was of pure ivory, and her saddle-cloth of blood-red satin, while her saddle girths were of corded silk and her stirrups of cut crystal. Her horse"s reins were of beaten gold, all hung with little silver bells, so that, as she rode along, she made a sound like fairy music.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='130'>Apparently she was bent on the chase, for she carried a hunting-horn and a sheaf of arrows; and she led seven greyhounds along in a leash, while as many scenting hounds ran loose at her horse"s side.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='3' num='131'>As she rode down <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='song;scotch;worship;air;bit;dress;side' adjectives='queenly;magnificent;old' verbs='be;ride;lilt;carry;think;kneel' valence='5.85791666667' arousal='4.08875' dominance='5.45'>the glen</entity>, she lilted a bit of an old Scotch song; and she carried herself with such a queenly air, and her dress was so magnificent, that <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='song;scotch;worship;air;bit;dress;side' adjectives='queenly;magnificent;old' verbs='be;ride;lilt;carry;think;kneel' valence='5.85791666667' arousal='4.08875' dominance='5.45'>Thomas</entity> was like to kneel by the side of <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='song;scotch;worship;air;bit;dress;side' adjectives='queenly;magnificent;old' verbs='be;ride;lilt;carry;think;kneel' valence='5.85791666667' arousal='4.08875' dominance='5.45'>the path</entity> and worship her, for he thought that it must be the Blessed Virgin herself.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='132'>But when the rider came to where he was, and understood his thoughts, she shook her head sadly.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='4' num='133'>"I am not that Blessed Lady, as thou thinkest," she said. "Men call me <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='country;man' adjectives='other' verbs='be;call' valence='5.96692307692' arousal='4.31384615385' dominance='5.59538461538'>Queen</entity>, but it is of a far other country; for I am the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='country;man' adjectives='other' verbs='be;call' valence='5.96692307692' arousal='4.31384615385' dominance='5.59538461538'>Queen</entity> of Fairy-land, and not the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='country;man' adjectives='other' verbs='be;call' valence='5.96692307692' arousal='4.31384615385' dominance='5.59538461538'>Queen</entity> of <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='country;man' adjectives='other' verbs='be;call' valence='5.96692307692' arousal='4.31384615385' dominance='5.59538461538'>Heaven</entity>."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='134'>And certainly it seemed as if what she said were true; for, from that moment, it was as if a spell were cast over <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='caution;moment;spell;prudence' adjectives='common-sense;true' verbs='be;forget;make;cast;say;seem' valence='5.60285714286' arousal='3.99357142857' dominance='5.54071428571'>Thomas</entity>, making him forget prudence, and caution, and common-sense itself.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='135'>For he knew that it was dangerous for mortals to meddle with Fairies, yet he was so entranced with the Lady"s beauty that he begged her to give him a kiss. This was just what she wanted, for she knew that if she once kissed him she had him in her power.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='136'>And, to the young man"s horror, as soon as their lips had met, an awful change came over her. For her beautiful mantle and riding-skirt of silk seemed to fade away, leaving her clad in a long grey garment, which was just the colour of ashes. Her beauty seemed to fade away also, and she grew old and wan; and, worst of all, half of her abundant yellow hair went grey before his very eyes. She saw the poor man"s astonishment and terror, and she burst into a mocking laugh.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='137'>"I am not so fair to look on now as I was at first," she said, "but that matters little, for thou hast sold thyself, Thomas, to be my servant for seven long years. For whoso kisseth the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='kisseth;time' adjectives='whoso' verbs='go;be;serve' valence='5.80333333333' arousal='4.36666666667' dominance='5.48'>Fairy Queen</entity> must e"en go with her to Fairy-land, and serve her there till that time is past."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='138'>When he heard these words poor Thomas fell on his knees and begged for mercy. But mercy he could not obtain. The Elfin <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='palfrey;face' adjectives='dapple-grey' verbs='bring;stand;laugh;be' valence='6.11428571429' arousal='4.41285714286' dominance='6.06285714286'>Queen</entity> only laughed in his face, and brought her dapple-grey palfrey close up to where he was standing.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='139'>"No, no," she said, in answer to his entreaties. "Thou didst ask the kiss, and now thou must pay the price. So dally no longer, but mount behind me, for it is full time that I was gone."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='140'>So <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='groan;steed;sigh;bridle;terror;rein' adjectives='many;grey' verbs='do;mount;gallop;have;shake' valence='4.818' arousal='4.209' dominance='5.147'>Thomas</entity>, with many a sigh and groan of terror, mounted behind her; and as soon as he had done so, she shook her bridle rein, and the grey steed galloped off.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='141'>On and on they went, going swifter than the wind; till they left <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='horizon;edge;desert;wind' adjectives='dry;far;great;desolate;bare' verbs='go;leave;live;come;stretch' valence='5.57058823529' arousal='4.22470588235' dominance='5.31823529412'>the land</entity> of the living behind, and came to the edge of a great desert, which stretched before them, dry, and bare, and desolate, to the edge of the far horizon.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='142'>At least, so it seemed to the weary eyes of <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='chance;side;eye;desert;companion' adjectives='alive;strange;other;least;weary' verbs='be;reach;cross;have;seem;wonder' valence='5.74133333333' arousal='3.664' dominance='5.546'>Thomas of Ercildoune</entity>, and he wondered if he and his strange companion had to cross this desert; and, if so, if there were any chance of reaching the other side of it alive.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='143'>But the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='career;rein;palfrey' adjectives='wild;grey' verbs='tighten;stop' valence='5.68375' arousal='4.43' dominance='5.49125'>Fairy Queen</entity> suddenly tightened her rein, and the grey palfrey stopped short in its wild career.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='144'>"Now must thou descend to earth, <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='shoulder;head;eye;thing;lout;captive;knee;earth' adjectives='unhappy;mortal' verbs='be;hide;show;see;say;descend;glance;lay' valence='5.40590909091' arousal='3.85954545455' dominance='5.40545454545'>Thomas</entity>," said the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='shoulder;head;eye;thing;lout;captive;knee;earth' adjectives='unhappy;mortal' verbs='be;hide;show;see;say;descend;glance;lay' valence='5.40590909091' arousal='3.85954545455' dominance='5.40545454545'>Lady</entity>, glancing over her shoulder at her unhappy captive, "and lout down, and lay thy head on my knee, and I will show thee hidden things, which cannot be seen by mortal eyes."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='145'>So Thomas dismounted, and louted down, and rested his head on the Fairy Queen"s knee; and lo, as he looked once more over the desert, everything seemed changed. For he saw three roads leading across it now, which he had not noticed before, and each of these three roads was different.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='146'>One of them was broad, and level, and even, and it ran straight on across the sand, so that no one who was travelling by it could possibly lose his way.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='147'>And the second road was as different from the first as it well could be. It was narrow, and winding, and long; and there was a thorn hedge on one side of it, and a briar hedge on the other; and those hedges grew so high, and their branches were so wild and tangled, that those who were travelling along that road would have some difficulty in persevering on their journey at all.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='148'>And the third road was unlike any of the others. It was a bonnie, bonnie road, winding up a hillside among brackens, and heather, and golden-yellow whins, and it looked as if it would be pleasant travelling, to pass that way.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='149'>"Now," said the Fairy Queen, "an" thou wilt, I shall tell thee where these three roads lead to. The first road, as thou seest, is broad, and even, and easy, and there be many that choose it to travel on. But though it be a good road, it leadeth to a bad end, and the folk that choose it repent their choice for ever.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='150'>"And as for the narrow road, all hampered and hindered by the thorns and the briars, there be few that be troubled to ask where that leadeth to. But did they ask, perchance more of them might be stirred up to set out along it. For that is the Road of Righteousness; and, although it be hard and irksome, yet it endeth in a glorious City, which is called the City of the Great <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='city;righteousness;great;endeth;road' adjectives='hard;glorious;irksome' verbs='be;call' valence='5.96' arousal='4.25461538462' dominance='5.62153846154'>King</entity>.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='151'>"And the third road--the bonnie road--that runs up the brae among the ferns, and leadeth no mortal kens whither, but I ken where it leadeth, <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='ken;whither;bonnie;fern;road;leadeth;elf-land;bra' adjectives='fair;unto;mortal' verbs='leadeth;ken;run;take' valence='5.63181818182' arousal='3.88545454545' dominance='5.38'>Thomas</entity>--for it leadeth unto fair Elf-land; and that road take we.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='152'>"And, mark "ee, <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='ercildoune;ee;word;mark;anyone;journey;lip;end;tower;tongue;care' adjectives='single;own;mortal' verbs='hopest;reach;see;s;take;openeth;bide;save;speak' valence='5.69277777778' arousal='4.10611111111' dominance='5.53555555556'>Thomas</entity>, if ever thou hopest to see thine own Tower of Ercildoune again, take care of thy tongue when we reach our journey"s end, and speak no single word to anyone save me--for the mortal who openeth his lips rashly in Fairy-land must bide there for ever."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='153'>Then she bade him mount her palfrey again, and they rode on. The ferny road was not so bonnie all the way as it had been at first, however. For they had not ridden along it very far before it led them into a narrow ravine, which seemed to go right down under the earth, where there was no ray of light to guide them, and where the air was dank and heavy. There was a sound of rushing water everywhere, and at last the grey palfrey plunged right into it; and it crept up, cold and chill, first over <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='sound;water;s;foot;knee;palfrey;chill' adjectives='cold;last;grey' verbs='be;rush;plunge;creep' valence='5.34' arousal='4.35214285714' dominance='5.57428571429'>Thomas</entity>"s feet, and then over his knees.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='154'>His courage had been slowly ebbing ever since he had been parted from the daylight, but now he gave himself up for lost; for it seemed to him certain that his strange companion and he would never come safe to their journey"s end.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='155'>He fell forward in a kind of swoon; and, if it had not been that he had tight hold of the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='gown;kind;swoon;seat;s;hold' adjectives='ash-grey;tight' verbs='be;drown;warrant;have;fall' valence='5.35052631579' arousal='4.16631578947' dominance='5.27315789474'>Fairy</entity>"s ash-grey gown, I warrant he had fallen from his seat, and had been drowned.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='156'>But all things, be they good or bad, pass in time, and at last the darkness began to lighten, and the light grew stronger, until they were back in broad sunshine.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='157'>Then Thomas took courage, and looked up; and lo, they were riding through a beautiful orchard, where apples and pears, dates and figs and wine-berries grew in great abundance. And his tongue was so parched and dry, and he felt so faint, that he longed for some of the fruit to restore him.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='158'>He stretched out his hand to pluck some of it; but his companion turned in her saddle and forbade him.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='159'>"There is nothing safe for thee to eat here," she said, "save an apple, which I will give thee presently. If thou touch aught else thou art bound to remain in Fairy-land for ever."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='160'>So poor Thomas had to restrain himself as best he could; and they rode slowly on, until they came to a tiny tree all covered with red apples. The <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='companion' adjectives='bent' verbs='pluck;hand' valence='6.06166666667' arousal='4.16' dominance='5.94666666667'>Fairy Queen</entity> bent down and plucked one, and handed it to her companion.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='161'>"This I can give thee," she said, "and I do it gladly, for these apples are the Apples of Truth; and whoso eateth them gaineth this reward, that his lips will never more be able to frame a lie."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='162'><entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='thomas;apple;lip;truth;grace;man' adjectives='true' verbs='be;call;take;rest;eat' valence='6.45545454545' arousal='3.87090909091' dominance='6.05181818182'>Thomas</entity> took the apple, and ate it; and for evermore the Grace of Truth rested on his lips; and that is why, in after years, men called him "True Thomas."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='163'>They had only a little way to go after this, before they came in sight of a magnificent Castle standing on a hillside.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='164'>"Yonder is my abode," said the Queen, pointing to it proudly. "There dwelleth my Lord and all the Nobles of his court; and, as my Lord hath an uncertain temper and shows no liking for any strange gallant whom he sees in my company, I pray thee, both for thy sake and mine, to utter no word to anyone who speaketh to thee; and, if anyone should ask me who and what thou art, I will tell them that thou art dumb. So wilt thou pass unnoticed in the crowd."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='165'>With these words the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='gown;word;riding-skirt;mantle;face;hair;blast;change' adjectives='fair;marvellous;piercing;grey;ugly;green;ash-covered;young;hunting-horn;loud' verbs='blow;do;raise;drop;vanish;come;grow;appear' valence='5.55954545455' arousal='4.06681818182' dominance='5.43227272727'>Lady</entity> raised her hunting-horn, and blew a loud and piercing blast; and, as she did so, a marvellous change came over her again; for her ugly ash-covered gown dropped off her, and the grey in her hair vanished, and she appeared once more in her green riding-skirt and mantle, and her face grew young and fair.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='166'>And a wonderful change passed over <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='country;shoon;cloth;suit;foot;glance;downward;change;clothes' adjectives='brown;rough;wonderful;fine;satin' verbs='be;transform;chance;wear;have;pass;find' valence='5.75045454545' arousal='3.82727272727' dominance='5.50136363636'>Thomas</entity> also; for, as he chanced to glance downwards, he found that his rough country clothes had been transformed into a suit of fine brown cloth, and that on his feet he wore satin shoon.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='3' num='167'>Immediately the sound of the horn rang out, the doors of the Castle flew open, and <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='sound;ladies;door;knight;number;horn;difficulty;page-boys;wish;minstrels;castle;palfrey' adjectives='unobserved;open' verbs='fly;accompany;obey;slide;have;pass;meet;ring;hurry' valence='5.72727272727' arousal='4.19727272727' dominance='5.58818181818'>the King</entity> hurried out to meet the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='sound;ladies;door;knight;number;horn;difficulty;page-boys;wish;minstrels;castle;palfrey' adjectives='unobserved;open' verbs='fly;accompany;obey;slide;have;pass;meet;ring;hurry' valence='5.72727272727' arousal='4.19727272727' dominance='5.58818181818'>Queen</entity>, accompanied by such a number of Knights and Ladies, Minstrels and Page-boys, that <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='sound;ladies;door;knight;number;horn;difficulty;page-boys;wish;minstrels;castle;palfrey' adjectives='unobserved;open' verbs='fly;accompany;obey;slide;have;pass;meet;ring;hurry' valence='5.72727272727' arousal='4.19727272727' dominance='5.58818181818'>Thomas</entity>, who had slid from his palfrey, had no difficulty in obeying her wishes and passing into the Castle unobserved.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='168'>Everyone seemed very glad to see the Queen back again, and they crowded into the Great Hall in her train, and she spoke to them all graciously, and allowed them to kiss her hand. Then she passed, with her husband, to a dais at the far end of the huge apartment, where two thrones stood, on which the Royal pair seated themselves to watch the revels which now began.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='169'>Poor <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='poor;end;hall;scene' adjectives='extraordinary;lonely;other' verbs='feel;be;gaze;stand;fascinate' valence='5.57166666667' arousal='3.82083333333' dominance='5.38833333333'>Thomas</entity>, meanwhile, stood far away at the other end of the Hall, feeling very lonely, yet fascinated by the extraordinary scene on which he was gazing.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='170'>For, although all the fine Ladies, and Courtiers, and Knights were dancing in one part of the Hall, there were huntsmen coming and going in another part, carrying in great antlered deer, which apparently they had killed in the chase, and throwing them down in heaps on the floor. And there were rows of cooks standing beside the dead animals, cutting them up into joints, and bearing away the joints to be cooked.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='171'>Altogether it was such a strange, fantastic scene that Thomas took no heed of how the time flew, but stood and gazed, and gazed, never speaking a word to anybody. This went on for three long days, then the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='throne;dais;hall' adjectives='long' verbs='be;rise;cross;step;stand;go' valence='5.98909090909' arousal='3.68727272727' dominance='5.49363636364'>Queen</entity> rose from her throne, and, stepping from the dais, crossed the Hall to where he was standing.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='172'>""Tis time to mount and ride, <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='castle;time;ercildoune;tis' adjectives='fair' verbs='mount;see;ride;say;wouldst' valence='6.14142857143' arousal='4.13428571429' dominance='5.80285714286'>Thomas</entity>," she said, "if thou wouldst ever see the fair Castle of Ercildoune again."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='173'>Thomas looked at her in amazement. "Thou spokest of seven long years, <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='' adjectives='spokest;long' verbs='be;exclaim;have' valence='5.79875' arousal='3.76625' dominance='5.5725'>Lady</entity>," he exclaimed, "and I have been here but three days."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='174'>The Queen smiled. "Time passeth quickly in Fairy-land, my friend," she replied. "Thou thinkest that thou hast been here but three days. "Tis seven years since we two met. And now it is time for thee to go. I would fain have had thy presence with me longer, but I dare not, for thine own sake. For every seventh year an Evil Spirit cometh from the Regions of Darkness, and carrieth back with him one of our followers, whomsoever he chanceth to choose. And, as thou art a goodly fellow, I fear that he might choose thee.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='175'>"So, as I would be loth to let harm befall thee, I will take thee back to thine own country this very night."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='176'>Once more the grey palfrey was brought, and <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='palfrey;burn;huntly' adjectives='grey' verbs='be;return;mount;bring;have;come' valence='5.83666666667' arousal='3.92333333333' dominance='5.53111111111'>Thomas</entity> and the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='palfrey;burn;huntly' adjectives='grey' verbs='be;return;mount;bring;have;come' valence='5.83666666667' arousal='3.92333333333' dominance='5.53111111111'>Queen</entity> mounted it; and, as they had come, so they returned to the Eildon Tree near the Huntly Burn.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='177'>Then the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='gift;people;farewell;something;fairy-land;parting' adjectives='' verbs='be;give;bid;let;know;have;ask' valence='5.81642857143' arousal='4.01642857143' dominance='5.64428571429'>Queen</entity> bade <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='gift;people;farewell;something;fairy-land;parting' adjectives='' verbs='be;give;bid;let;know;have;ask' valence='5.81642857143' arousal='4.01642857143' dominance='5.64428571429'>Thomas</entity> farewell; and, as a parting gift, he asked her to give him something that would let people know that he had really been to Fairy-land.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='178'>"I have already given thee the Gift of Truth," she replied. "I will now give thee the Gifts of Prophecy and Poesie; so that thou wilt be able to foretell the future, and also to write wondrous verses. And, besides these unseen gifts, here is something that mortals can see with their own eyes--a Harp that was fashioned in Fairy-land. Fare thee well, my friend. Some day, perchance, I will return for thee again."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='179'>With these words the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='man;word;parting;truth;haunt' adjectives='radiant;such;little;sorry;ordinary' verbs='be;feel;leave;vanish;come;tell' valence='5.43043478261' arousal='4.10782608696' dominance='5.45652173913'>Lady</entity> vanished, and <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='man;word;parting;truth;haunt' adjectives='radiant;such;little;sorry;ordinary' verbs='be;feel;leave;vanish;come;tell' valence='5.43043478261' arousal='4.10782608696' dominance='5.45652173913'>Thomas</entity> was left alone, feeling a little sorry, if the truth must be told, at parting with such a radiant Being and coming back to the ordinary haunts of men.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='3' num='180'>After this he lived for many a long year in his Castle of Ercildoune, and the fame of his poetry and of his prophecies spread all over <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='prophecy;people;rhymer;fame;poetry' adjectives='many;long' verbs='live;spread;name' valence='6.07333333333' arousal='4.1675' dominance='5.89333333333'>the country</entity>, so that people named him <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='prophecy;people;rhymer;fame;poetry' adjectives='many;long' verbs='live;spread;name' valence='6.07333333333' arousal='4.1675' dominance='5.89333333333'>True Thomas</entity>, and <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='prophecy;people;rhymer;fame;poetry' adjectives='many;long' verbs='live;spread;name' valence='6.07333333333' arousal='4.1675' dominance='5.89333333333'>Thomas</entity> the Rhymer.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='181'>I cannot write down for you all the prophecies which <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='prophecy' adjectives='' verbs='write;utter;come;tell;pass' valence='5.6325' arousal='3.82833333333' dominance='5.38583333333'>Thomas</entity> uttered, and which most surely came to pass, but I will tell you one or two.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='182'>He foretold the Battle of <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='battle;word' adjectives='' verbs='foretell' valence='4.645' arousal='5.125' dominance='5.925'>Bannockburn</entity> in these words:</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='183'></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='184'>"The Burn of <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='burn' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='3.73' arousal='5.4' dominance='3.9'>Breid</entity></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='185'>Shall rin fou reid,"</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='186'>which came to pass on that terrible day when the waters of the little <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='water;blood' adjectives='little;terrible' verbs='be;defeat;redden;come;pass' valence='4.99888888889' arousal='4.19888888889' dominance='4.76444444444'>Bannockburn</entity> were reddened by the blood of the defeated English.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='5' num='187'>He also foretold the Union of the Crowns of <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='union;vein;blood;crowns;son' adjectives='' verbs='be;foretell;bear' valence='5.482' arousal='4.607' dominance='4.871'>England</entity> and <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='union;vein;blood;crowns;son' adjectives='' verbs='be;foretell;bear' valence='5.482' arousal='4.607' dominance='4.871'>Scotland</entity>, under a <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='union;vein;blood;crowns;son' adjectives='' verbs='be;foretell;bear' valence='5.482' arousal='4.607' dominance='4.871'>Prince</entity> who was the son of a French <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='union;vein;blood;crowns;son' adjectives='' verbs='be;foretell;bear' valence='5.482' arousal='4.607' dominance='4.871'>Queen</entity>, and who yet bore the blood of <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='union;vein;blood;crowns;son' adjectives='' verbs='be;foretell;bear' valence='5.482' arousal='4.607' dominance='4.871'>Bruce</entity> in his veins.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='188'></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='189'>"A French Quen shall bearre the <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='' adjectives='' verbs='bearre' valence='5.43' arousal='4.26' dominance='5.445'>Sonne</entity>;</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='190'>Shall rule all Britainne to <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='britainne;rule;shall' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='5.64' arousal='3.33' dominance='4.90666666667'>the sea</entity>,</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='191'>As neere as is the ninth degree,"</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='192'>which thing came true in 1603, when <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='thing;monarch;country;son' adjectives='true' verbs='become;come' valence='6.10222222222' arousal='4.05111111111' dominance='5.69222222222'>King James</entity>, son of <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='thing;monarch;country;son' adjectives='true' verbs='become;come' valence='6.10222222222' arousal='4.05111111111' dominance='5.69222222222'>Mary</entity>, Queen of Scots, became Monarch of both countries.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='193'></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='194'>*</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='195'>*</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='196'>*</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='197'>*</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='198'>*</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='4' num='199'>Fourteen long years went by, and people were beginning to forget that <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='tower;army;people;fairy-land;tweed;war;bank' adjectives='long' verbs='be;begin;forget;rest;have;go;come' valence='5.5525' arousal='3.8815' dominance='5.2525'>Thomas the Rhymer</entity> had ever been in Fairy-land; but at last a day came when <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='tower;army;people;fairy-land;tweed;war;bank' adjectives='long' verbs='be;begin;forget;rest;have;go;come' valence='5.5525' arousal='3.8815' dominance='5.2525'>Scotland</entity> was at war with <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='tower;army;people;fairy-land;tweed;war;bank' adjectives='long' verbs='be;begin;forget;rest;have;go;come' valence='5.5525' arousal='3.8815' dominance='5.2525'>England</entity>, and the Scottish army was resting by the banks of the Tweed, not far from the Tower of <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='tower;army;people;fairy-land;tweed;war;bank' adjectives='long' verbs='be;begin;forget;rest;have;go;come' valence='5.5525' arousal='3.8815' dominance='5.2525'>Ercildoune</entity>.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='200'>[Illustration]</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='201'>And the Master of the Tower determined to make a feast, and invite all the Nobles and Barons who were leading the army to sup with him.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='202'>That feast was long remembered.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='3' num='203'>For the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='guest;song;everything;place;meal;care' adjectives='magnificent;long' verbs='be;end;rise;take;assemble;sing' valence='6.29111111111' arousal='3.86055555556' dominance='6.04'>Laird</entity> of <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='guest;song;everything;place;meal;care' adjectives='magnificent;long' verbs='be;end;rise;take;assemble;sing' valence='6.29111111111' arousal='3.86055555556' dominance='6.04'>Ercildoune</entity> took care that everything was as magnificent as it could possibly be; and when the meal was ended he rose in his place, and, taking his <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='guest;song;everything;place;meal;care' adjectives='magnificent;long' verbs='be;end;rise;take;assemble;sing' valence='6.29111111111' arousal='3.86055555556' dominance='6.04'>Elfin Harp</entity>, he sang to his assembled guests song after song of the days of long ago.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='204'>The guests listened breathlessly, for they felt that they would never hear such wonderful music again. And so it fell out.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='3' num='205'>For that very night, after all the Nobles had gone back to their tents, a soldier on guard saw, in the moonlight, a snow-white <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='moonlight;soldier;guard;hind;nobles;saw;tent' adjectives='snow-white' verbs='go;move;run;have' valence='5.65529411765' arousal='4.12117647059' dominance='5.31176470588'>Hart</entity> and Hind moving slowly down <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='moonlight;soldier;guard;hind;nobles;saw;tent' adjectives='snow-white' verbs='go;move;run;have' valence='5.65529411765' arousal='4.12117647059' dominance='5.31176470588'>the road</entity> that ran past <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='moonlight;soldier;guard;hind;nobles;saw;tent' adjectives='snow-white' verbs='go;move;run;have' valence='5.65529411765' arousal='4.12117647059' dominance='5.31176470588'>the camp</entity>.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='206'>There was something so unusual about the animals that he called to his officer to come and look at them. And the officer called to his brother officers, and soon there was quite a crowd softly following the dumb creatures, who paced solemnly on, as if they were keeping time to music unheard by mortal ears.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='207'>"There is something uncanny about this," said one soldier at last. "Let us send for <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='omen' adjectives='able' verbs='be;let;tell;send' valence='5.63555555556' arousal='3.66111111111' dominance='5.40444444444'>Thomas of Ercildoune</entity>, perchance he may be able to tell us if it be an omen or no."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='208'>"Ay, send for Thomas of Ercildoune," cried every one at once. So a little page was sent in haste to the old Tower to rouse the Rhymer from his slumbers.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='209'>When he heard <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='wrapt;s;message;grave;seer' adjectives='' verbs='hear;grow;face' valence='5.45444444444' arousal='4.11555555556' dominance='5.51'>the boy</entity>"s message, the Seer"s face grew grave and wrapt.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='210'>""Tis a summons," he said softly, "a summons from the Queen of Fairy-land. I have waited long for it, and it hath come at last."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='211'>And when he went out, instead of joining the little company of waiting men, he walked straight up to the snow-white Hart and Hind. As soon as he reached them they paused for a moment as if to greet him. Then all three moved slowly down a steep bank that sloped to the little river Leader, and disappeared in its foaming waters, for <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='water;flood;river;leader;bank' adjectives='little;full;steep' verbs='slope;be;foam;move;disappear' valence='5.57375' arousal='4.14125' dominance='5.169375'>the stream</entity> was in full flood.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='4' num='212'>And, although a careful search was made, no trace of <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='search;messenger;folk;trace' adjectives='careful' verbs='go;be;make;believe;find' valence='5.90944444444' arousal='3.61166666667' dominance='5.66111111111'>Thomas of Ercildoune</entity> was found; and to this day <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='search;messenger;folk;trace' adjectives='careful' verbs='go;be;make;believe;find' valence='5.90944444444' arousal='3.61166666667' dominance='5.66111111111'>the country</entity> folk believe that the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='search;messenger;folk;trace' adjectives='careful' verbs='go;be;make;believe;find' valence='5.90944444444' arousal='3.61166666667' dominance='5.66111111111'>Hart</entity> and the Hind were messengers from the Elfin <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='search;messenger;folk;trace' adjectives='careful' verbs='go;be;make;believe;find' valence='5.90944444444' arousal='3.61166666667' dominance='5.66111111111'>Queen</entity>, and that he went back to Fairy-land with them.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='213'>[Illustration]</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='214'>[Illustration: And she set sail for her own Country.]</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='215'></paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='216'>GOLD-TREE AND SILVER-TREE</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='217'>In bygone days there lived a little <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='world;child' adjectives='prettiest;little;bygone;whole' verbs='be;live;name' valence='6.31181818182' arousal='4.11' dominance='5.59272727273'>Princess</entity> named <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='world;child' adjectives='prettiest;little;bygone;whole' verbs='be;live;name' valence='6.31181818182' arousal='4.11' dominance='5.59272727273'>Gold-Tree</entity>, and she was one of the prettiest children in the whole world.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='218'>Although her mother was dead, she had a very happy life, for her father loved her dearly, and thought that nothing was too much trouble so long as it gave his little daughter pleasure. But by and by he married again, and then the little <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='s;sorrow' adjectives='little' verbs='marry;begin' valence='5.83833333333' arousal='4.42333333333' dominance='5.185'>Princess</entity>"s sorrows began.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='219'>For his new wife, whose name, curious to say, was <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='fear;someone;name;wife' adjectives='beautiful;curious;better;miserable;jealous;new' verbs='look;be;say;make;meet' valence='5.74444444444' arousal='4.29333333333' dominance='5.485'>Silver-Tree</entity>, was very beautiful, but she was also very jealous, and she made herself quite miserable for fear that, some day, she should meet someone who was better looking than she was herself.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='220'>When she found that her step-daughter was so very pretty, she took a dislike to her at once, and was always looking at her and wondering if people would think her prettier than she was. And because, in her heart of hearts, she was afraid that they would do so, she was very unkind indeed to the poor girl.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='221'>At last, one day, when <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='middle;tree;glen;lady;walk' adjectives='last;deep' verbs='go;be;grow;surround;lay' valence='6.08944444444' arousal='3.82555555556' dominance='5.365'>Princess Gold-Tree</entity> was quite grown up, the two ladies went for a walk to a little well which lay, all surrounded by trees, in the middle of a deep glen.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='222'>Now the water in this well was so clear that everyone who looked into it saw his face reflected on the surface; and the proud <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='depths;everyone;picture;well;surface;face;water;peep' adjectives='own;clear;proud' verbs='be;love;look;reflect;see;mirror;come' valence='6.15529411765' arousal='4.01647058824' dominance='5.91941176471'>Queen</entity> loved to come and peep into its depths, so that she could see her own picture mirrored in the water.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='223'>But to-day, as she was looking in, what should she see but a little trout, which was swimming quietly backwards and forwards not very far from the surface.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='224'>"Troutie, troutie, answer me this one question," said the Queen. "Am not I the most beautiful woman in the world?"</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='225'>"No, indeed, you are not," replied the trout promptly, jumping out of the water, as he spoke, in order to swallow a fly.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='226'>"Who is the most beautiful woman, then?" asked the disappointed <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='answer' adjectives='different;disappointed' verbs='ask;expect;have' valence='5.4925' arousal='4.29125' dominance='5.555'>Queen</entity>, for she had expected a far different answer.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='3' num='227'>"Thy step-daughter, the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='look;thy;bottom;fish;step-daughter;s;doubt' adjectives='jealous;little;black' verbs='frighten;say;come;dive;face' valence='5.205' arousal='4.421875' dominance='5.1975'>Princess Gold-Tree</entity>, without a doubt," said the little fish; then, frightened by the black look that came upon the jealous <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='look;thy;bottom;fish;step-daughter;s;doubt' adjectives='jealous;little;black' verbs='frighten;say;come;dive;face' valence='5.205' arousal='4.421875' dominance='5.1975'>Queen</entity>"s face, he dived to the bottom of <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='look;thy;bottom;fish;step-daughter;s;doubt' adjectives='jealous;little;black' verbs='frighten;say;come;dive;face' valence='5.205' arousal='4.421875' dominance='5.1975'>the well</entity>.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='228'>It was no wonder that he did so, for the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='distance;flower;step-daughter;glance;expression;wonder' adjectives='little;busy;fair;angry;young;pleasant' verbs='be;look;do;dart;s;pick' valence='5.77904761905' arousal='4.01380952381' dominance='5.61666666667'>Queen</entity>"s expression was not pleasant to look at, as she darted an angry glance at her fair young step-daughter, who was busy picking flowers some little distance away.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='229'>Indeed, she was so annoyed at the thought that anyone should say that <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='anyone;room;thought;passion;self-control;home' adjectives='ill;violent;annoyed;prettier' verbs='be;feel;reach;declare;say;lose;go;throw' valence='5.68473684211' arousal='4.36578947368' dominance='5.55894736842'>the girl</entity> was prettier than she was, that she quite lost her self-control; and when she reached home she went up, in a violent passion, to her room, and threw herself on <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='anyone;room;thought;passion;self-control;home' adjectives='ill;violent;annoyed;prettier' verbs='be;feel;reach;declare;say;lose;go;throw' valence='5.68473684211' arousal='4.36578947368' dominance='5.55894736842'>the bed</entity>, declaring that she felt very ill indeed.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='230'>It was in vain that Princess Gold-Tree asked her what the matter was, and if she could do anything for her. She would not let the poor girl touch her, but pushed her away as if she had been some evil thing. So at last the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='apartment' adjectives='last;sad' verbs='leave;go;feel;have' valence='5.33375' arousal='4.17875' dominance='5.30375'>Princess</entity> had to leave her alone, and go out of the apartment, feeling very sad indeed.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='231'>By and by the King came home from his hunting, and he at once asked for the Queen. He was told that she had been seized with sudden illness, and that she was lying on her bed in her own room, and that no one, not even the Court Physician, who had been hastily summoned, could make out what was wrong with her.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='232'>In great anxiety--for he really loved her--<entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='bedside;anxiety;anything' adjectives='great' verbs='do;love;be;feel;relieve;ask;go' valence='6.11' arousal='4.19666666667' dominance='5.8175'>the King</entity> went up to her bedside, and asked the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='bedside;anxiety;anything' adjectives='great' verbs='do;love;be;feel;relieve;ask;go' valence='6.11' arousal='4.19666666667' dominance='5.8175'>Queen</entity> how she felt, and if there was anything that he could do to relieve her.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='233'>"Yes, there is one thing that thou couldst do," she answered harshly, "but I know full well that, even although it is the only thing that will cure me, thou wilt not do it."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='234'>"Nay," said <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='kingdom;mouth;nay;word;half' adjectives='better;knowest' verbs='be;aught;give;deserve;say;carest;ask' valence='6.04583333333' arousal='4.25083333333' dominance='5.92916666667'>the King</entity>, "I deserve better words at thy mouth than these; for thou knowest that I would give thee aught thou carest to ask, even if it be the half of my Kingdom."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='235'>"Then give me thy daughter"s heart to eat," cried the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='heart;s;daughter' adjectives='' verbs='die;cry;obtain;eat;give' valence='5.48285714286' arousal='4.72357142857' dominance='5.36428571429'>Queen</entity>, "for unless I can obtain that, I will die, and that speedily."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='4' num='236'>She spoke so wildly, and looked at him in such a strange fashion, that the poor King really thought that her brain was turned, and he was at his wits" end what to do. He left <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='daughter;distress;country;hand;s;marriage;son' adjectives='great;last' verbs='remember;leave;pace;have;ask;arrive' valence='5.91681818182' arousal='4.08181818182' dominance='5.66909090909'>the room</entity>, and paced up and down <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='daughter;distress;country;hand;s;marriage;son' adjectives='great;last' verbs='remember;leave;pace;have;ask;arrive' valence='5.91681818182' arousal='4.08181818182' dominance='5.66909090909'>the corridor</entity> in great distress, until at last he remembered that that very morning the son of a great <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='daughter;distress;country;hand;s;marriage;son' adjectives='great;last' verbs='remember;leave;pace;have;ask;arrive' valence='5.91681818182' arousal='4.08181818182' dominance='5.66909090909'>King</entity> had arrived from a country far over <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='daughter;distress;country;hand;s;marriage;son' adjectives='great;last' verbs='remember;leave;pace;have;ask;arrive' valence='5.91681818182' arousal='4.08181818182' dominance='5.66909090909'>the sea</entity>, asking for his daughter"s hand in marriage.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='237'>"Here is a way out of the difficulty," he said to himself. "This marriage pleaseth me well, and I will have it celebrated at once. Then, when my daughter is safe out of the country, I will send a lad up the hillside, and he shall kill a he-goat, and I will have its heart prepared and dressed, and send it up to my wife. Perhaps the sight of it will cure her of this madness."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='4' num='238'>So he had the strange <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='malady;illness;thing;consent;brain;s;marriage;place;dislike' adjectives='good;strange;sudden;maiden' verbs='be;work;summon;leave;take;have;seem;recover;cause;tell' valence='5.45684210526' arousal='4.18842105263' dominance='5.39947368421'>Prince</entity> summoned before him, and told him how the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='malady;illness;thing;consent;brain;s;marriage;place;dislike' adjectives='good;strange;sudden;maiden' verbs='be;work;summon;leave;take;have;seem;recover;cause;tell' valence='5.45684210526' arousal='4.18842105263' dominance='5.39947368421'>Queen</entity> had taken a sudden illness that had wrought on her brain, and had caused her to take a dislike to the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='malady;illness;thing;consent;brain;s;marriage;place;dislike' adjectives='good;strange;sudden;maiden' verbs='be;work;summon;leave;take;have;seem;recover;cause;tell' valence='5.45684210526' arousal='4.18842105263' dominance='5.39947368421'>Princess</entity>, and how it seemed as if it would be a good thing if, with the maiden"s consent, the marriage could take place at once, so that the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='malady;illness;thing;consent;brain;s;marriage;place;dislike' adjectives='good;strange;sudden;maiden' verbs='be;work;summon;leave;take;have;seem;recover;cause;tell' valence='5.45684210526' arousal='4.18842105263' dominance='5.39947368421'>Queen</entity> might be left alone to recover from her strange malady.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='4' num='239'>Now the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='country;bride;s;place;pair;marriage;hatred' adjectives='delighted;glad;step-mother' verbs='be;set;wed;take;escape;gain' valence='5.98904761905' arousal='4.28476190476' dominance='5.64142857143'>Prince</entity> was delighted to gain his bride so easily, and the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='country;bride;s;place;pair;marriage;hatred' adjectives='delighted;glad;step-mother' verbs='be;set;wed;take;escape;gain' valence='5.98904761905' arousal='4.28476190476' dominance='5.64142857143'>Princess</entity> was glad to escape from her step-mother"s hatred, so the marriage took place at once, and the newly wedded pair set off across <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='country;bride;s;place;pair;marriage;hatred' adjectives='delighted;glad;step-mother' verbs='be;set;wed;take;escape;gain' valence='5.98904761905' arousal='4.28476190476' dominance='5.64142857143'>the sea</entity> for the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='country;bride;s;place;pair;marriage;hatred' adjectives='delighted;glad;step-mother' verbs='be;set;wed;take;escape;gain' valence='5.98904761905' arousal='4.28476190476' dominance='5.64142857143'>Prince</entity>"s country.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='240'>Then the King sent a lad up the hillside to kill a he-goat; and when it was killed he gave orders that its heart should be dressed and cooked, and sent to the Queen"s apartment on a silver dish. And the wicked woman tasted it, believing it to be the heart of her step-daughter; and when she had done so, she rose from her bed and went about the Castle looking as well and hearty as ever.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='241'>I am glad to be able to tell you that the marriage of <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='hurry;marriage;success' adjectives='great;able;powerful;rich;glad;happy' verbs='be;love;wed;turn;have;come;tell' valence='6.36103448276' arousal='4.39517241379' dominance='5.82655172414'>Princess Gold-Tree</entity>, which had come about in such a hurry, turned out to be a great success; for the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='hurry;marriage;success' adjectives='great;able;powerful;rich;glad;happy' verbs='be;love;wed;turn;have;come;tell' valence='6.36103448276' arousal='4.39517241379' dominance='5.82655172414'>Prince</entity> whom she had wedded was rich, and great, and powerful, and he loved her dearly, and she was as happy as the day was long.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='242'>So things went peacefully on for a year. <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='home;step-daughter;time' adjectives='prosperous;satisfied;dead;contented;new;happy' verbs='be;think' valence='6.54076923077' arousal='4.39692307692' dominance='5.66692307692'>Queen Silver-Tree</entity> was satisfied and contented, because she thought that her step-daughter was dead; while all the time the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='home;step-daughter;time' adjectives='prosperous;satisfied;dead;contented;new;happy' verbs='be;think' valence='6.54076923077' arousal='4.39692307692' dominance='5.66692307692'>Princess</entity> was happy and prosperous in her new home.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='243'>But at the end of the year it chanced that the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='glen;water;order;face' adjectives='little;more' verbs='go;reflect;chance;see' valence='6.07545454545' arousal='4.03909090909' dominance='5.76181818182'>Queen</entity> went once more to <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='glen;water;order;face' adjectives='little;more' verbs='go;reflect;chance;see' valence='6.07545454545' arousal='4.03909090909' dominance='5.76181818182'>the well</entity> in the little glen, in order to see her face reflected in the water.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='244'>And it chanced also that the same little trout was swimming backwards and forwards, just as he had done the year before. And the foolish <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='answer;question;time' adjectives='better;foolish;last' verbs='have;determine' valence='5.58888888889' arousal='4.15777777778' dominance='5.51777777778'>Queen</entity> determined to have a better answer to her question this time than she had last.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='245'>"Troutie, troutie," she whispered, leaning over the edge of <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='world;woman;edge;troutie' adjectives='beautiful' verbs='whisper;lean;be' valence='6.1575' arousal='4.32' dominance='5.44125'>the well</entity>, "am not I the most beautiful woman in the world?"</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='246'>"By my troth, thou art not," answered the trout, in his very straightforward way.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='247'>"Who is the most beautiful woman, then?" asked the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='thought;rival;pale;face' adjectives='' verbs='ask;grow;have' valence='5.8025' arousal='3.92375' dominance='5.5725'>Queen</entity>, her face growing pale at the thought that she had yet another rival.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='248'>"Why, your Majesty"s step-daughter, the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='s;step-daughter;majesty;trout' adjectives='sure' verbs='answer;be' valence='6.29142857143' arousal='4.26857142857' dominance='5.98428571429'>Princess Gold-Tree</entity>, to be sure," answered the trout.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='249'>The Queen threw back her head with a sigh of relief. "Well, at any rate, people cannot admire her now," she said, "for it is a year since she died. I ate her heart for my supper."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='250'>"Art thou sure of that, your Majesty?" asked the trout, with a twinkle in his eye. "Methinks it is but a year since she married the gallant young <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='methinks;country;hand' adjectives='gallant;own;young' verbs='return;be;marry;seek;come' valence='6.0025' arousal='4.21' dominance='5.61916666667'>Prince</entity> who came from abroad to seek her hand, and returned with him to his own country."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='251'>When the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='word;palace;rage;time;step-daughter;knee;anger;home;ship;order;husband' adjectives='ready;such;cold;long;best' verbs='be;hide;have;give;wish;make;rise;ask;turn;see;hear;know;deceive;visit;go' valence='5.83212121212' arousal='4.0803030303' dominance='5.66363636364'>Queen</entity> heard these words she turned quite cold with rage, for she knew that her husband had deceived her; and she rose from her knees and went straight home to the Palace, and, hiding her anger as best she could, she asked him if he would give orders to have the Long Ship made ready, as she wished to go and visit her dear step-daughter, for it was such a very long time since she had seen her.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='252'><entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='daughter;hatred;request;order;ship' adjectives='ready;long;glad' verbs='be;get;make;give;have;surprise;think' valence='6.15705882353' arousal='4.07529411765' dominance='5.69117647059'>The King</entity> was somewhat surprised at her request, but he was only too glad to think that she had got over her hatred towards his daughter, and he gave orders that the Long Ship should be made ready at once.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='3' num='253'>Soon it was speeding over the water, its prow turned in the direction of <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='direction;prow;water;course;s;journey;haste;helm;boat' adjectives='such' verbs='be;end;turn;live;know;allow;speed;steer;take' valence='5.88458333333' arousal='4.05875' dominance='5.64041666667'>the land</entity> where the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='direction;prow;water;course;s;journey;haste;helm;boat' adjectives='such' verbs='be;end;turn;live;know;allow;speed;steer;take' valence='5.88458333333' arousal='4.05875' dominance='5.64041666667'>Princess</entity> lived, steered by the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='direction;prow;water;course;s;journey;haste;helm;boat' adjectives='such' verbs='be;end;turn;live;know;allow;speed;steer;take' valence='5.88458333333' arousal='4.05875' dominance='5.64041666667'>Queen</entity> herself; for she knew the course that the boat ought to take, and she was in such haste to be at her journey"s end that she would allow no one else to take the helm.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='254'>Now it chanced that Princess Gold-Tree was alone that day, for her husband had gone a-hunting. And as she looked out of one of the Castle windows she saw a boat coming sailing over the sea towards the landing place. She recognised it as her father"s Long Ship, and she guessed only too well whom it carried on board.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='255'>She was almost beside herself with terror at the thought, for she knew that it was for no good purpose that Queen Silver-Tree had taken the trouble to set out to visit her, and she felt that she would have given almost anything she possessed if her husband had but been at home. In her distress she hurried into the servants" hall.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='256'>"Oh, what shall I do, what shall I do?" she cried, "for I see my father"s Long Ship coming over the sea, and I know that my step-mother is on board. And if she hath a chance she will kill me, for she hateth me more than anything else upon earth."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='257'>Now the servants worshipped the ground that their young Mistress trod on, for she was always kind and considerate to them, and when they saw how frightened she was, and heard her piteous words, they crowded round her, as if to shield her from any harm that threatened her.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='258'>"Do not be afraid, your Highness," they cried; "we will defend thee with our very lives if need be. But in case thy <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='case;chamber;spell;step-mother;power' adjectives='great;mullioned;evil;nigh' verbs='lock;throw;have;get' valence='5.58461538462' arousal='4.06846153846' dominance='5.77923076923'>Lady</entity> Step-Mother should have the power to throw any evil spell over thee, we will lock thee in the great Mullioned Chamber, then she cannot get nigh thee at all."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='3' num='259'>Now the Mullioned Chamber was a strong-room, which was in a part of <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='woman;door;oaken;part;stout;mischief;strong-room;step-mother' adjectives='thick;safe;wicked' verbs='break;be;devise;know' valence='5.6544' arousal='3.9468' dominance='5.4976'>the castle</entity> all by itself, and its door was so thick that no one could possibly break through it; and the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='woman;door;oaken;part;stout;mischief;strong-room;step-mother' adjectives='thick;safe;wicked' verbs='break;be;devise;know' valence='5.6544' arousal='3.9468' dominance='5.4976'>Princess</entity> knew that if she were once inside <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='woman;door;oaken;part;stout;mischief;strong-room;step-mother' adjectives='thick;safe;wicked' verbs='break;be;devise;know' valence='5.6544' arousal='3.9468' dominance='5.4976'>the room</entity>, with its stout oaken door between her and her step-mother, she would be perfectly safe from any mischief that that wicked woman could devise.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='260'>So she consented to her faithful servants" suggestion, and allowed them to lock her in the Mullioned Chamber.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='261'>So it came to pass that when <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='door;lackey;royal;bow;key;castle;strong-room;mistress' adjectives='impossible;great;low' verbs='lock;be;get;open;command;take;pass;arrive;come;tell;know' valence='5.65107142857' arousal='4.07821428571' dominance='5.55821428571'>Queen Silver-Tree</entity> arrived at the great door of the Castle, and commanded the lackey who opened it to take her to his Royal Mistress, he told her, with a low bow, that that was impossible, because the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='door;lackey;royal;bow;key;castle;strong-room;mistress' adjectives='impossible;great;low' verbs='lock;be;get;open;command;take;pass;arrive;come;tell;know' valence='5.65107142857' arousal='4.07821428571' dominance='5.55821428571'>Princess</entity> was locked in the strong-room of the Castle, and could not get out, because no one knew where the key was.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='262'>(Which was quite true, for the old butler had tied it round the neck of the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='butler;s;master;neck;sheep-dog' adjectives='favourite;old;true' verbs='be;send;have;tie;seek;round' valence='5.65866666667' arousal='3.784' dominance='5.462'>Prince</entity>"s favourite sheep-dog, and had sent him away to <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='butler;s;master;neck;sheep-dog' adjectives='favourite;old;true' verbs='be;send;have;tie;seek;round' valence='5.65866666667' arousal='3.784' dominance='5.462'>the hills</entity> to seek his master.)</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='263'>"Take me to the door of the apartment," commanded the Queen. "At least I can speak to my dear daughter through it." And the lackey, who did not see what harm could possibly come from this, did as he was bid.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='264'>"If the key is really lost, and thou canst not come out to welcome me, dear <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='kiss;keyhole;finger;key' adjectives='put;little;least;deceitful' verbs='be;canst;welcome;say;lose;come' valence='5.524375' arousal='4.365' dominance='5.621875'>Gold-Tree</entity>," said the deceitful <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='kiss;keyhole;finger;key' adjectives='put;little;least;deceitful' verbs='be;canst;welcome;say;lose;come' valence='5.524375' arousal='4.365' dominance='5.621875'>Queen</entity>, "at least put thy little finger through the keyhole that I may kiss it."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='265'>The Princess did so, never dreaming that evil could come to her through such a simple action. But it did. For instead of kissing the tiny finger, her step-mother stabbed it with a poisoned needle, and, so deadly was the poison, that, before she could utter a single cry, the poor <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='cry;needle;finger;poison;step-mother' adjectives='poor;deadly;dead;single;tiny;utter' verbs='be;stab;poison;kiss;fall' valence='4.496' arousal='4.613' dominance='4.7065'>Princess</entity> fell, as one dead, on <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='cry;needle;finger;poison;step-mother' adjectives='poor;deadly;dead;single;tiny;utter' verbs='be;stab;poison;kiss;fall' valence='4.496' arousal='4.613' dominance='4.7065'>the floor</entity>.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='266'>When she heard the fall, a smile of satisfaction crept over Queen Silver-Tree"s face. "Now I can say that I am the handsomest woman in the world," she whispered; and she went back to the lackey who stood waiting at the end of <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='woman;end;daughter;lackey;world;home' adjectives='handsomest' verbs='be;return;whisper;say;stand;have;go;tell;wait' valence='5.76833333333' arousal='3.95208333333' dominance='5.59333333333'>the passage</entity>, and told him that she had said all that she had to say to her daughter, and that now she must return home.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='267'>So <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='ceremony;harm;neck;hunting;mullioned;country;sail;hand;chamber;s;key;home;castle;mistress;boat' adjectives='own;due;sheep-dog' verbs='set;attend;befall;know;have;come;take' valence='5.49461538462' arousal='4.08769230769' dominance='5.55076923077'>the man</entity> attended her to the boat with all due ceremony, and she set sail for her own country; and no one in the Castle knew that any harm had befallen their dear Mistress until the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='ceremony;harm;neck;hunting;mullioned;country;sail;hand;chamber;s;key;home;castle;mistress;boat' adjectives='own;due;sheep-dog' verbs='set;attend;befall;know;have;come;take' valence='5.49461538462' arousal='4.08769230769' dominance='5.55076923077'>Prince</entity> came home from his hunting with the key of the Mullioned Chamber, which he had taken from his sheep-dog"s neck, in his hand.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='268'>[Illustration]</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='269'>He laughed when he heard the story of <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='servant;story;visit;s;wife' adjectives='' verbs='do;run;laugh;hear;have;release;open;tell' valence='6.09666666667' arousal='4.27666666667' dominance='5.78866666667'>Queen Silver-Tree</entity>"s visit, and told the servants that they had done well; then he ran upstairs to open <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='servant;story;visit;s;wife' adjectives='' verbs='do;run;laugh;hear;have;release;open;tell' valence='6.09666666667' arousal='4.27666666667' dominance='5.78866666667'>the door</entity> and release his wife.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='270'>But what was his horror and dismay, when he did so, to find her lying dead at his feet on <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='foot;dismay;horror' adjectives='dead' verbs='be;lie;find;do' valence='4.30555555556' arousal='3.82444444444' dominance='5.03'>the floor</entity>.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='271'>He was nearly beside himself with rage and grief; and, because he knew that a deadly poison such as <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='body;burial;rage;poison;couch;grief;chamber;s;need;mullioned' adjectives='silken;deadly;such' verbs='preserve;be;use;look;please;leave;know;have;go;lay' valence='5.25892857143' arousal='4.30857142857' dominance='5.3575'>Queen Silver-Tree</entity> had used would preserve the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='body;burial;rage;poison;couch;grief;chamber;s;need;mullioned' adjectives='silken;deadly;such' verbs='preserve;be;use;look;please;leave;know;have;go;lay' valence='5.25892857143' arousal='4.30857142857' dominance='5.3575'>Princess</entity>"s body so that it had no need of burial, he had it laid on a silken couch and left in the Mullioned Chamber, so that he could go and look at it whenever he pleased.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='272'>He was so terribly lonely, however, that in a little time he married again, and his second wife was just as sweet and as good as the first one had been. This new wife was very happy, there was only one little thing that caused her any trouble at all, and she was too sensible to let it make her miserable.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='273'>That one thing was that there was one room in the Castle--a room which stood at the end of a passage by itself--which she could never enter, as her husband always carried the key. And as, when she asked him the reason of this, he always made an excuse of some kind, she made up her mind that she would not seem as if she did not trust him, so she asked no more questions about the matter.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='3' num='274'>But one day the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='couch' adjectives='silken' verbs='do;look;see;lie;unlock;leave;chance;have;go;be;tell' valence='5.69368421053' arousal='3.80105263158' dominance='5.48736842105'>Prince</entity> chanced to leave <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='couch' adjectives='silken' verbs='do;look;see;lie;unlock;leave;chance;have;go;be;tell' valence='5.69368421053' arousal='3.80105263158' dominance='5.48736842105'>the door</entity> unlocked, and as he had never told her not to do so, she went in, and there she saw <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='couch' adjectives='silken' verbs='do;look;see;lie;unlock;leave;chance;have;go;be;tell' valence='5.69368421053' arousal='3.80105263158' dominance='5.48736842105'>Princess Gold-Tree</entity> lying on the silken couch, looking as if she were asleep.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='275'>"Is she dead, or is she only sleeping?" she said to herself, and she went up to the couch and looked closely at the Princess. And there, sticking in her little finger, she discovered a curiously shaped needle.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='276'>"There hath been evil work here," she thought to herself. "If that needle be not poisoned, then I know naught of medicine." And, being skilled in leechcraft, she drew it carefully out.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='277'>In a moment <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='moment;eye;story' adjectives='other;whole' verbs='recover;open;tell;have;sit' valence='6.22923076923' arousal='4.07461538462' dominance='5.75307692308'>Princess Gold-Tree</entity> opened her eyes and sat up, and presently she had recovered sufficiently to tell the Other <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='moment;eye;story' adjectives='other;whole' verbs='recover;open;tell;have;sit' valence='6.22923076923' arousal='4.07461538462' dominance='5.75307692308'>Princess</entity> the whole story.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='278'>Now, if her step-mother had been jealous, the Other <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='step-mother;hand' adjectives='jealous;little;other;best;glad' verbs='be;love;marry;cry;hear;know;have;happen;clap' valence='5.75695652174' arousal='4.27217391304' dominance='5.52956521739'>Princess</entity> was not jealous at all; for, when she heard all that had happened, she clapped her little hands, crying, "Oh, how glad the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='step-mother;hand' adjectives='jealous;little;other;best;glad' verbs='be;love;marry;cry;hear;know;have;happen;clap' valence='5.75695652174' arousal='4.27217391304' dominance='5.52956521739'>Prince</entity> will be; for although he hath married again, I know that he loves thee best."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='279'>That night the Prince came home from hunting looking very tired and sad, for what his second wife had said was quite true. Although he loved her very much, he was always mourning in his heart for his first dear love, <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='heart;love' adjectives='' verbs='mourn;be;love' valence='6.49428571429' arousal='4.81' dominance='5.61285714286'>Princess Gold-Tree</entity>.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='280'>"How sad thou art!" exclaimed his wife, going out to meet him. "Is there nothing that I can do to bring a smile to thy face?"</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='281'>"Nothing," answered the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='nothing;bow' adjectives='heart-sore;gay' verbs='answer;be;pretend;lay' valence='5.78375' arousal='3.98875' dominance='5.49625'>Prince</entity> wearily, laying down his bow, for he was too heart-sore even to pretend to be gay.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='282'>"Except to give thee back Gold-Tree," said his wife mischievously. "And that can I do. Thou wilt find her alive and well in the Mullioned Chamber."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='283'>Without a word the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='word;couch' adjectives='ready;sure' verbs='be;welcome;run;sit' valence='6.169' arousal='4.055' dominance='5.792'>Prince</entity> ran upstairs, and, sure enough, there was his dear <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='word;couch' adjectives='ready;sure' verbs='be;welcome;run;sit' valence='6.169' arousal='4.055' dominance='5.792'>Gold-Tree</entity>, sitting on the couch ready to welcome him.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='284'>He was so overjoyed to see her that he threw his arms round her neck and kissed her over and over again, quite forgetting his poor second wife, who had followed him upstairs, and who now stood watching the meeting that she had brought about.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='285'>She did not seem to be sorry for herself, however. "I always knew that thy heart yearned after Princess Gold-Tree," she said. "And it is but right that it should be so. For she was thy first love, and, since she hath come to life again, I will go back to mine own people."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='286'>"No, indeed thou wilt not," answered the Prince, "for it is thou who hast brought me this joy. Thou wilt stay with us, and we shall all three live happily together. And Gold-Tree and thee will become great friends."</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='287'>And so it came to pass. For <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='sister;life' adjectives='other' verbs='bring;become;love;have;be' valence='6.57583333333' arousal='4.32583333333' dominance='5.92'>Princess Gold-Tree</entity> and the Other <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='sister;life' adjectives='other' verbs='bring;become;love;have;be' valence='6.57583333333' arousal='4.32583333333' dominance='5.92'>Princess</entity> soon became like sisters, and loved each other as if they had been brought up together all their lives.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='2' num='288'>In this manner another year passed away, and one evening, in the old country, <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='water;country;well;manner;face' adjectives='little;old' verbs='go;do;look;have;pass' valence='5.94533333333' arousal='3.90333333333' dominance='5.598'>Queen Silver-Tree</entity> went, as she had done before, to look at her face in the water of the little well in <entity type='LOCATION' common-nouns='water;country;well;manner;face' adjectives='little;old' verbs='go;do;look;have;pass' valence='5.94533333333' arousal='3.90333333333' dominance='5.598'>the glen</entity>.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='289'>And, as had happened twice before, the trout was there. "Troutie, troutie," she whispered, "am not I the most beautiful woman in the world?"</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='0' num='290'>"By my troth, thou art not," answered the trout, as he had answered on the two previous occasions.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='291'>"And who dost thou say is the most beautiful woman now?" asked the <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='voice;vexation;rage' adjectives='' verbs='ask;tremble' valence='4.93' arousal='4.744' dominance='5.302'>Queen</entity>, her voice trembling with rage and vexation.</paragraph>
	<paragraph num_entities='1' num='292'>"I have given her name to thee these two years back," answered the trout. "The <entity type='PERSON' common-nouns='course' adjectives='' verbs='' valence='7.64' arousal='5.42' dominance='5.74'>Princess Gold-Tree</entity>, of course."</paragraph>
